<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-andrew-carnegie</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2017270211/1892-08-11/ed-1/?sp=15</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		THE ALLIANCE-INDEPENDENT.
15
SOME CARNEGIE HIST6RY.
Crushing Power of The Great Iron Com
pany Untold Wealth.
The bitter struggle at Homestead
between organized workmen on the one
hand and organized millionaires on the
other, gives to the phenomenal career of
Andrew Carnegie, the chief of capital's
iidc in the controversy, a special interest
to Americans, who arc called upon to
lecide by their votes whether or not
they indorse a system which has made
such wholcsarb money-gathering possiblo
to any man, The history of Carnegie's
wealth-making is one of the most extra
ordinary in the history of the United
States, and he differs from every other
American millionaire in his ambitions
and achievements no less than in the use
he has made of his wealth, the distinct
ions which he has striven to obtain, and
the curious mixture of socialism and
imperialism which go to make up his
character.
People in general who read about the
6trikc at Homestead have no idea of the
extent of the Carnegie industries of
wiiich that will, with it3 thousands of
workmen, is but one among many.
Even in Pittsburg, under the shadow of
he vast commercial house which Mr.
Carnegie has built iip, there are thou
Eands of people with no adequate idea
of its extent and resources, of the crush
ing power with which it has stamped
out aspiring rivals or the millions of
profit which it has reaped and of the
long line of huge iron industries which
it has swallowed one after another.
People who read the accounts of the
strike are confused by Various names cm
ployed. There is talk cf Carnegie,
Phipps Co., of the Bessemer Steel Co.,
of the Lucy Furnace, of the Keystone
Bridge Co., of the llartmnn Steel Co. of
Carnegie brothers although there is
now only one Carnegie of the Edgar
Thompson mills and of the Homestead
mills, with a host of others. They all
are Carnegie industries, although
Andrew Carnegie has no share in their
management. The man at the head of
affairs is the Mr. Frick who is taking all
the responsibility. Ho is the head" oFtlie
new concern, the Carnegie Steel Co.
(Limited), which came into being a few
weeks ago and which embraces all the
industries absorbed by Carnegie or
started by him up to date.
This huge ocropus has so many arms
and tentacles t hat only people in the iron
trade arc aware of its vamilicatiens.
Yet the rise of Carnegie and the story of
his life arc as much a wonder to them as
if they knew nothing of the man who
has made himself master of the greatest
industry in the new world. Carnegie
not only founded a great house, but he
has invented a new business maxim and
followed it with marvelous success.
When he ceased to be a telegraph
operator and went into business with
his brother Tom and D. A Stewart,
Carnegie laid it down as a fundamental
principle upon which the partnership
should be conducted that when a partner
died his estate should bo settled up
within thirty days and his interest in the
business acquired by the remaining
partners, and also that no son or child of
any of them should have a share in the
concern or a voice in its management.
This policy has been rigidly followed
down to the present; The consequence
has been that the partnerehip from time
to time has been refreshed and invigor
ated by infusions of new blood and the
active managers have been young and
energetic men. )Yrhcnevcr an employe
or a successful man in some outside but
collateral businees, as in the case of
Frick, displayed unusual ability and
energy, he was taken in, given a share
in the profits and pushed rapidly to the
front.
Both David A. Stewart and Tom Car
negie, who formed tbe original copart
nership with Andrew Carnegie, are now
dead, and each died a many times
millionaire at a time when the business
had not anything like its present
proportions but was growing rapidly.
Mr. Stewart left two sons and Tom
Carnegie more than half a dozen, yet
none of these young men were allowed
to come into the concern, and the estates
of their fathers were settled up im
mediately after death and the business
continued by Andrew Carnegie. The
consequence' has been that the active
management of" the business has been
intrusted to bright and active men wlib
have grown up on iron.
All of theso partners have become
millionaires. To be suro thGy are not
millionaires of the Carnegie magnitude,
having to strugglo along with from one
to ten million!. This was the case with
Henry Phipps. He is one of mlnoi
partners, whose name has not even been
mentioned in connection with the Home
stead strike, and yet he lives in England
in a palace and maintains an establish
ment like one of the princes of the blood.
Indeed there is not in England a princ
with a house as line as Kneb worth Park.
Stevenage, Herts, where Henry Phippi
and his family are now residing.
This magnificent house is the count rj
stat of the Lyttons, and from there the
late Lytton was buried. Knebwoith
which has an immense aemcsnc ana ar
estate of thousands of acres, with every
thing which wealth, care and time car
add to make it a delight to the eye, wai
at one time a royal palace, and has beer
in the family of the Lyttons since abou1
1470. It was purchased then by Sii
Robert de Lytton, who was Undei
Treasurer jof the Exchequer to Ilenrj
VII., and Queen Elizabeth with othe;
subsequent sovereigns have been enter
taincd within its ample walls
The fortunate tenant of this establish
ment has, however, been through tin
mill at Pittsburg, and the yeMv of'tol
lie has put in piling up the Carnegie
millions as well as his own entitle him
to the case and comfort which it is
presumed he now enjoys there. Mr.
Phipps, who, unlike Carnegie, lias never
aspired to literary or political distinct
ion, was recently presented at court,
with his daughter and other members of
his family. Rigged out in the ornate
costume which a man is obliged to put
on when he goes to court, the partner of
Andrew Carnegie may be highly
Interesting from a picturesque stand
point, but does not add much to the
dignity of American citizenship.
Carnegie, as the cable has told the
puUic, is living now in lordly luxury at
Cluny Castle, Scotland. 1
Here is what a recent writer had to
say about the goings-on at the castle
"Mr. Carnegie has a pljjer of his own,
who pipes each day for dinner, the
company marching two and two behind
him thrice around the hall in solemn
Srocession until led by the host to tho
Ining-room." The same writer, in
farther description of this famous piper,
says that ho is always "resplendent in
tho Carnegie tartan." Thcro is no
Carnegie tartan, and James Grant's
book, "Tho Tartans of tho Clans of
Scotland," docs not CTcn mention tho
name of the family. Tho "Carnegie
Tartan," therefore, which tho piper at
Cluny Castle wears, must not only havo
been made out of whole cloth, bujt it
must havo been invented by Mr. Car
negie. Perhaps he wears tho kilt him
self. People who know Carnegie havo
told him that his manly form coald be
set off to no better effect than if he were
to don the cap, the stocktngs and the
sporran. f"v i
III3 NEW niGIILAKD SEAT. I
But ho is now at Cluny Castle.
Klnlochrannoch, Perthshire, is the name
of his new country seat fn the, Highlands',
and here his grounds embrace thousands
of acres of mountain and moorland,
brawling burn and silvery loch.
In Ids splendid house in New York,
No. 5 west Fifty-first street, Carnegie,
who has filled tho establishment with
Scotch servants, has invented a coat-of-arms
which reporters who have Inter
viewed him in his library hav.e seen
emblazoned on tho walls. It consists of
loaves of bread quartered with a knife,
sausagos, heads of cabbages, etc., in
yules, azuro and ermine and all painted
with a wretched disregard of art.
Much attention is given to Spain'
young six-year-old king. The proba
bilities are that when that kid is old
enough to be a king the world will bo
too wise to admit of any such foolish
ness even in old bcnjclitcd Spain.
Sixty-cent wheat, five-cent cotton,
lower prices for cattle and everything
else produced are arguments that are
silently but surely doing a work in
opening the eyes of men that have here
tofore been deaf to the appeals of
reason.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1901-11-10/ed-1/?sp=28</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		ANDREW CARNEGIE.
BACK IN HIS OWN LIKRAKY-A PROPHBT
NOT WITHOUT HONOR IN HIS
OWN COUNTRY.
The first banners put up by the Tammany
eumpaign committee bore in large and glaring
letters two paragraphs as to "what Andrew
Carnegie did" nnd "what Andrew Carnegie
said." By these misleading statements it wac
hoped by the managers of the Croker-Devery
gullivan party to mislead the voters of New-
York to believe that Mr. Carnegie indorsed the
Tammany administration, and would aid the
organization in perpetuating its misrule of the
city. Mr. Carnegie was in Europe when the
THE CRoWD IN HARRY MT.VoVS SALOON, CANAL AND BAXTKR STS.
Cheering the first new? that Jerome was probably fieri Mr M< Evoy In the centre.
banners were put up. and when he returned
was besieged with questions as to his leaning
In the political contest. lie emphasized the fact
that he was "no partisan" without going Into
the details of the questions of the day. but in
the minds of those who know him there was
never any doubt as to Mr. Carnegie's sympa
thies In tho fight between the fusion and the
Tammany candidates.
Even without the political advertising ban
ners Mr. Carnegie would have attracted un
usual attention "n his return from Europe.
While he was abroad he made princely Rifts to
educational institution.*, and In recognition of
hia liberality received many honors at th"
hands the Lord -torsh'p of St. Andrew's University,
one of the four institutions to share in the gift
of $10,000,000 which was given for the benefit
"Scottish fellow citizens" only, and not
enjoyed by "English, Irish, colonists <-r
f gners
Schcols, libraries an<3 colleges in all parts of
I'nited States had received more than
{CO.OOU.OiNi from Mr. Carnegie in the- last
twenty years. The word has become accus
tomed to bearinp about large gifts from the
ironmaster, but $10,000,000 to "establish
fr. education 'n fi'ur Scotch universities' w:is
a philanthropic measure which created surprise
and iccitement even though Andrew Carnegie
was the donor
Mr. Carnegie'z hobby is libraries, and it is
natural lisa* the library in his home .should he
.-iis favorite room. Tin* house in which he now
lives urn! which he will probably occupy until
jj js u<-\\ home in Fifth aye. is completed Is in
Fifty-first-st.. near Fifth-aye There is nothing
remarkable about it but its simplicity. The
library, where Mr. Carnegie spends much of
his time, where he wrote "The Gospel of
Wealth" and many "f his lectures, occupies the
entire front of the Becond Btory of the house
and is a luxuriously furnished apartment. A
conspicuous feature of i!:< room is the Carnegie
cat of arms, emblazoned on the library wall
This shows i versed crc.vn surmounted by a
liberty cap A weaver's shuttle and a shoe
maker's knife nre upon the cuteheon, Scotch
arid American flags are the supporters, and
below Is the send. "1 ath to Privilege." There
are hooks everywhere, on tables, shelves and
stands, and tin the massive centre table there
is always a handsomely Itound copy of Mr.
Carnegie's "Fifty Years' March of the Repub
lic" (me ei'le of the room is taken up almost
entirely by the fireplace; but even on this side
NEW-YORK TRIBUNE CXUSTRATED SUPPLEMENT.
there are books and two cases containing clvnr
fshed souvenirs. Among these are cases tn
which the freedom of cities were presented,
trowels with which cornerstones were laid, and
similar treasure?. Ail this will soon be removed
to the palace In Fifth-aye., and Andrew Car
nr-gie will have the pleasure of fitting a new
library for himself, an occupation at which he
should be an expert
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90060625/1903-06-13/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		Nine! The deep-toned bell of the
cathedral clock in Andrew Carnegie's
mansion at Fifth avenue and Ninety
first street, New York, has chimed
the quarters in a musical scale, and
is booming the hour as the master
reaches the doorway of his workshop.
As he stands for a moment on the
threshold of his library, his small,
lithe figure is the incarnation of quiet
force and nervous energy. He has
said publicly that he is out of busi­
ness for good. He is about to begin
a busy day, in the course of which
he will accomplish twice as much
work as many a man in the hurly
burly of lower Broadway who is still
in active command of his forces as a
captain of industry.
System is Andrew Carnegie's
watchword. Although no longer
directing the movements of 200,000
employes in the great steel works
and other enterprises with which his
name was so long associated, he con­
tinues to be the man of affairs, and
each day brings its iabors, none the
less exacting because they are pri­
marily for the good of humanity and
not for personal gain.
It is estimated that Mr. Carnegie's
income is $15,000,000 a year. Of this
he gives away two-thirds at least.
Exactly how much of his fortune is
dispensed in public and private gifts
no one knows but himself. To dis­
tribute money so that the greatest
good to the greatest number shall re­
sult is the business of his life, and
he devotes at least ten hours a day
to this task with all the vigor and
concentrated shrewdness which have
made the former peasant boy of Dun­
fermline one of the wealthiest men
in the world.
Ah, the morning papers! To read
some of them and look through the
rest is the first thing to be done. Mr.
Carnegie is a rapid reader, and as
his interest extends to all parts of
the world, it is well that he is, for he
reads everything1 in the paper, from
the foreign cable dispatches to a
skimming over the advertisements.
The papers disposed of, he rings
for his secretary, James Bertram, a
Scot, like his employer quick-witted,
too, or he never would do for Andrew
Carnegie.
"What's new, Bertram?" he asks,
pleasantly* as he picks up one of the
pile of letters which have been placed
at his elbow, open and ready to be
scanned.
"Nothing particular You will find
several orpin requests in that pile
which look all right, and there is an
answer from that Indiana town about
their library. There are two person-'
al letters for you, too.* Oh, yes, you
have them."
This with Scottish directness and
military brevity, as Mr. Carnegie
breaks the seal of one of the two let­
ters, 'which have been placed on his
table unopened. Very
few
Carnegie
ft
iV1
are
are the
letters addressed to Andrew Carnegie
that are not opened .by Bertram, who,
with the true private secretory
In-
Sttoct, seems to be able to smell a
missive that Is personal enotigh to
belong enly to the person whose
name is in the superscription. Among
these are letters from relatives, of
course, and a very few from other
person* .whose relations with
Andrew
intimate. To
prevent
i'-s feSK i,i Mt rfu £1
Twelve Ho\irs of Activity
With .Andrew Carnegie
A Day with the Great Philanthropist in His Beautiful New
York Hortie—Perfect System in Each Hour of Labor.
any misconception, let it be said
here, positively, that writing the word
"Personal" on an envelope will not
deter the secretary from opening it.
Mr. Carnegie has gone through the
first letter and makes a short memo­
randum on it. The same with several
others. Then he takes up one from
a Western city which tells him that
the authorities there have decided
not to accept his offer of a library
because public feeling is against
using the required sum from the
municipal treasury every year to
support it. He elevates his eyebrows
in a shadow of vexation, and dictates
a reply to Bertram, who jots it down
in shorthand. The reply is courteous.
It expresses regret that the town will
not take a library, on the terms of­
fered, but declares emphatically that
the conditions which govern all other
library endowments cannot be modi­
fied in this case.
By the time the correspondence is
disposed of, and Mr. Bertram's note­
book is full of pothooks for Campbell
to turn into typewritten letters, the
forenoon is well advanced, and a pile
of newspapers from other dfties, in
America, q.nd abroad, are ready for
Mr. Carnegie's attention. He reads
the mall. Many are complimentary,
but there are some which criticise
the use he makes of his wealth, or
take issue with certain opinions he
may have expressed in speeches,
magazine essays or newspaper inter­
views.
All of these receive due considera­
tion and even when a prominent hum­
orist raps him hard—as one did
a few weeks ago—he only smiles in­
dulgently. N6 one realizes better
than Andrew Carnegie that to be in
the limelight of public view means
many an unkind comment, as well as
a fair quantity of praise, so he takes
the bitter with the sweet with equal
composure.
It is now time for luncheon. Mr.
Carnegie steps into one of the auto­
matic elevators and is taken to the
dining room. There is not much done
in Mr. Carnegie's room for an hour
'or two after dinner. He has spent
more than an hour at luncheon, in
domestic privacy, and when he re­
turns to his den it is to sit quietly
reading for hour before the car­
riage fs announced fort the afternoon
drive in the park.
But he cannot spend much time in
the park this afternoon, for he is due
to attend the opening of one of his
libraries on the east side. He has
promised to be present and make a
short address, and he will keep' his
word. The carriage has heen ordered
to be in readiness on his return from
his walk, and by 4 o'clock he is on
the platform in the new building, fac­
ing a large audience He shakes
hands with a few scores of persons,
and is rescued' from some hundreds
of others who would like to grasp his
hand, and drives back to his home.
He is Jin particularly good spirit
now, and id ready for a lot more'cor­
respondence. There have been sev­
eral mails in the course of the day,
and the mountain of letters which the
secretary has winnowed has resulted
in a pile for his personal considera­
tion even larger than that which
faced him in the morning. He goes
through them rapidly, and then he
has the' evening NeV York papers
and a lot of blue penciled papers from
other cities.
Visitors have been coming and
going all day, but, with the exception
of a. committeeman, he has not seen
any of them. He has a public dinner
engagement at the Waldorf-Astoria
for the evening, and has no time to
talk to any one whose business is not
imperative.
Six o'clock sounds from the big
hall clock and its companions, and
Bertram and Campbel disappear. As
they go out a cheery voice is heard
in the hall, and Mr. Carnegie smiles.
He recognizes the tones. In another
inoment, Charles M. Schwab, presi­
dent of the United States Steel Cor­
poration to the world at large, but
"Charlie" to Andrew Carnegie, is
seated in the den, laughing and talk­
ing. They may talk steel business,
but if they do it is only in a casual
way. Andrew Carnegie has passed
through a busy day, and he has still
that dinner to attend at the Waldorf
Astoria.
"Let's have some music," suggests
Mr: Carnegie, leading the way to the
magnificent pipe organ, which is one
of the luxurious features of the Car­
negie palace.
"All right," responds "Charlie," as
he seats himself in front of the in­
strument, "what shall it be?"
Andrew Carnegie has dropped into
a chair in front of the fireplace, and
his gaze is fixed among the red coals.
He smiles without answering. The
fingers of the musician sweep the
keys and "Ye Banks and Braes" thun­
ders through the great house. Then
comes "Annie Laurie," followed by
"The Bluebells of Scotland." The
quiet figure In the chair is* perfectly
still, save for a gentle nodding of the
head in time to the thrilling melody
that brings back old memories, old
times and many faces dead and gone.
Again the air changes and there are
tears in the music as the organ seems
to say articulately, "Robin, Robin
Adair."
Perhaps there are tears in the keen
blue eyes of the great multi-million­
aire and philanthropist, sitting so
quietly before the fire. If there are,
they cannot be seen, for the night
has been closing in and the musi­
cian is playing by the sense of touch
alone, as the listened still looks into
the red coals, dteaming, dreaming,
dreaming.—New York Herald.
Just Jones.
Golden Rule Jones? mayor of To
ledOi Ohio, visited Mayor Low not
many moons ago. He walked rapid­
ly through the corridor of the city
hall to. the door of the mayor's office.
There he met Secretary "Billy" Mo
ran.
"Low in?" said Jones.
"Yes. Mayor Low is ini, Card
please!" said Moran.
"I'm Jones," said the mayor of
Toledo.
"Walk right in, Mayor Jones!" said
Moran.
The secretary had never seen the
Golden Rule, not even a picture of
him, but by one of 'the lightning men­
tal calculations for which he is fam­
ous Mr. Moran worked out the iden­
tity of the man who had said,
"I'm
Jones/' The Golden ^Rule and Mayor
Low had long talk.—-New York Even­
ing Sun.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78000395/1902-01-25/ed-1/?sp=4</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WORM
CARNEGIE
INCIDENTS IN THE LIFE OF AX
DREW CARNEGIE.
Scottish Paper Prints Interesting
Account of His Life—His Father
Wns a Weaver—What Prompted
Him to Make Donations For Li­
braries—Was Telegraph Operator.
Third Man Injured In Civil War.
We clip the following from the Peo­
ple's Journal, Scotland's greatest week­
ly, on Andrew Carnegie, who is known
across the water as "The Laird of
Skibo," and which may be of interest
to our readers:
The Carnegie week in Piitsburg was
recently celebrated with great rejoic­
ings. As in former years stories of the
millionaire and incidents of his early
life were on everybody's lips. It was
stated that Andrew Carnegie came by
his fondness for books and libraries in
a legitimate way. His father was a
Scotch Liberal, a weaver of Dunferm­
line, and was one of three men, all
weavers, who, 75 years ago, gathered
their little handful of books together,
and placed them at the disposal of their
fellow-workmen. Shortly after Andrew
Carnegie graduated from the woollen
mills of Allegheny and became a mes­
senger boy in the Pittsburg "Tele­
graph" office, he had his own first ex­
perience with libraries and librarians
in his attempt to acquire knowledge.
At that time there was a wretched little
free library in Allegheny on Federal
street, just above Colonade Row, the
property made famous in the Jack Rob­
inson will case in Media. Andrew Car­
negie made aplication for books, and
was refused on the plea that he was
not a "working boy." At that time
clerks, telegraph operators, and other
boys and young men not employed in
mills, factories, or workshops were not
regarded as "working boys", and as
he was a telegraph operator young Car­
negie was refused the privilege of the
library. At this time young Carnegie,
as he subsequently confessed, had a
burning desire to become a reporter
and subsequent the editor of a news­
paper. He did not achieve his ambi­
tion, but he has always been exceed­
ingly ready with his pen and tongue.
Stung by his rebuff at the Allegheny
library young Carnegie made an attack
on that institution in the Pittsburg
"Dispatch," over the signature "Work­
ing Boy," with such signal success that
he forced the librarian to ask an inter­
view, at which the differences were ad­
justed and Carnegie was admitted to
its privileges on the score of being a
"working boy."
One of the three "don'ts" credited to
Mr. Carnegie is "don't speculate." The
other two are "don't drink," and "don't
Indorse." And yet Andrew Carnegie's
colossal fortune is based on speculation.
With a number of others, shortly after
the oil excitement broke out in north­
western Pennsylvania, Mr. Carnegie
took a "flyer" in petroleum, and pur­
chased 300 shares of stock in the Storey
Oil farm, on Oil Creek. Oil was as
great a gamble then as it is today,
and so Mr. Carnegie took the risk. Luck
was on his side, as it has ever been.
At first the venture did not promise
to be a success. He became discour­
aged, and sold one-third of his stock
at a nominal figure. He went to Scot­
land on a visit, and while there some
big wells wer struck, and he came back
to find that his shares were worth
hundreds of thousands of dollars. His
ultimate profit was $1,000,000. While a
great deal has been said about Andrew
Carnegie, very little is heard about his
brother, Thomas, or "Tom," as he was
familiarly known in Pittsburg. Thomas
Carnegie was the antithesis of his
brother Andrew. He was tall and slen­
der, and did not bear the marks of his
Scottish origin as plainly upon his face
as his elder brother. He was a nervous,
wiry man, whose inseparable compan­
ion was a Pittsburg "stogie." He was
a partner in the Carnegie interests,
president in fact, and was lifted into
financial and social life by Andrew as
the latter rose. Thomas Carnegie has
been dead a dozen years, and is almost
forgotten now by all save his associates
of that time.
The old Hope cotton mill in Allegheny
where "Andy" Carnegie worked is still
standing, although it is not in opera­
tion. From the cotton mill he rose to
be a messenger boy, and it all came
about through his father's love of play­
ing checkers. The elder Carnegie used
to visit Pittsburg to meet some check
er-playing cronies, among whom was
Jofon Brooks, then a clerk or manager
in the Pittsburg Telegraph office. One
night Mr. Carnegie, in speaking of his
elder son, said that he did not know
what he was going to do with Andrew.
"Send him over and I will make a mes­
senger boy of him," replied Brooks.
Tliat is how Carnegie got into the tele­
graph business. In the same office with
him as messenger boys were four other
lads who have since become famous
in one way or another. They were
Robert Pitcairn, now superintendent of
the Pittsburg division of the Pennsyl­
vania railroad, and many times a mil
ion aire Henry W. Oliver, another great
iron master of Pittsburg, whom it is
said Senator Quay has selected for his
successor in the senate David M'Cargo,
another railroad man, and William C.
Moreland, for many years. a leading
lawyer of Pittsburg. Andrew Carnegie
was one of the little handful of men
who witnessed an epoch in telegraphy
45 years ago. It was the sending of thq
first message from New Orleans to New
York. It was considered a wonderful
thing, almost impossible of achieve­
ment.
In those days operators worked on
short circuits, but the managers de­
cided to try the experiment of wiring
from the far south to the north. James
D. Reid was general superintendent of
the telegraph line, with headquarters
in Pittsburg. On the day set for the
trial, Superintendent Reid, David
Brooks, and Carnegie, M'Cargo, Oliver
Pitcairn, and Moreland, who were then
operators, gathered round the instru­
ment adjusted for the purpose. At a
signal, New York called Philadelphia,
Philadelphia called Harrisburg, and
then in quick succession Pittsburg, Cin­
cinnati, Louisville, Memphis, and New
Orleans opened. In describing that
scene, one of the number said recently:
—"For a moment there was absolute
silence in the office. No one seemed to
breathe, so great was the tension. Then
came a few faint ticks growing louder,
and an instant later an unbroken mes­
sage was sent between the north and
the south." In every instaiice the men
who have cast in their lot with Andrew
Carnegie have been lifted into wealth
and prominence. Those who have
dropped out have not always retained
their good luck. The latter is the case
of some of his old partners. Andrew
Carnegie is what the Rothschilds would
call a "lucky man." Their house will
have nothing to do with unlucky men.
Andrew Carnegie would be a perfect
treasure to them. One of the little
known episodes in Andrew Carnegie's
life is his connection with the civil war.
He was the third man wounded during
the Rebellion. When Thomas A. Scott
undertook to help President Lincoln as
assistant secretary of war in the mat­
ter of railway transportation. Carnegie
was placed in charge of a portion of the
telegraph work. He followed General
Butler's troops southward on an engine.
He rode on the pilot inspecting the
wires. At one point between Eldridge
Junction and Washington he found that
the Confederates had 'grounded" the
wires by pinning them to the earth. He
stopped the engine to release them. As
he did so one of the wires bounded up,
cutting a deep gash in his cheek, and
he entered Washington his face cov­
ered with blood.
Some years ago Mr. Carnegie was
asked to make a subscription toward
a library at Lincoln, Neb. The first 25
dollars had been given by an Omaha
man, Mr. Rosewater, of the "Bee."
Years before this Mr. Rosewater had
been a telegraph operator at the time
that young Carnegie was also an oper­
ator in Pittsburg. They had "talked"
frequently over the wire between the
cities where they were employed, but
had never met. It was Mr. Rosewater
who made the request for a donation
from Mr. Carnegie. It was forthcoming
very promptly, and in sending a mag­
nificent subscription Mr. Carnegie re­
cognized the bond of a telegraphic
brotherhood in a peculiar way. Down
in a corner of the letter below his sig­
nature he wrote "Sevnty-three," which
in the sound manual of the telegraphers
is a code signal used in exchanging
greetings. It was his greeting with his
check to his former brother telegrapher.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1919-08-12/ed-1/?sp=16</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		Andrew Carnegie, Maker of Millionaires
Deceased Ironmaster, While Rolling Up His Billion, Made Millionaires of More Than
Twoscorc Partners, Men Picked Fzom the Throng Because of Their Potential Ability
Many of These Men, Such as Schwab, Frick and Corey, To-Day Rank Among the
Wealthiest Men of the World.
ALL great captains of Industry
and finance In gaining great
ncnes tnemaeives maice oiner
men rich, but with the excoptlon of
Plcrpont Morgan sr., who dollbor-
ately picked out young men and
guided tbem along the paths leading to
wealth, Andrew Carnegie waa the
only autocrat of Industry and finance
who ever designedly made the fash
ioning of millionaires a by-product of
his own wealth-accruing activities.
He was a pioneer In that line, biasing
the way when millionaires were com
paratively scarce In Uila country, nnd
his by-products. In tho ranks of whom
are such men as Cbarlea M. Schwab,
Henry C. Frick and William B. Corey,
to-day rank among the wealthiest
men of the worm.
In his early days Andrew Carnegie,
by vlrtuo of his Scotch blood, waa a be
liever In Individual industry aud fru
gality. In his memolra he says be ac
cumulated his first $1,000 by saving
the money a few dollars at a time, but
other paaaagea Indicate that he had a
winning way and waa able to procure
aid from banks and capitalists In lay
ing the foundation of his fortune. Do
that as It may, he waa a believer
hard work and aavlng habits, but he
waa not long In coming to the Idea
that the short cut to wealth Is through
the efforts of others.
His first job entailing responsibility
was assistant to Thomas A. Scott. Su
perintendent of the Pennsylvania Rail
road Col Scott was a railroad man of
the old school. He believed In doing all
the Important work of his office with
his own hands, and he trained young
Carnegie along those lines.
"But," wrote Mr. Carnegie, "a few
years ago, after he had retired from
business, "I think Mr. Scott ,and I
were the most foolish men In the
world In that respect
"It took me some time to learn, but
I did learn that the supremely great
managers such aa you have In these
days never do any wprk themselves
worth speaking about; their point la
to make others work while they think.
I applied this lesson In after life, so
that business with mo baa never been
a care,
Col. Scott by the way, waa one of
Andrew Carnegie's first by-products.
Impressed by Carnegie's business abll
Ity, Col. Scott gave tho young man
his first opportunity to make money
outside his pay by advising blm to
buy (S00 worth of Adams Express
Company shares and to Invest $500 In
the Woodruff sleeping car, which
..Jwu tbo forerunner of thg Pullman,
I
WmmMim Summer Girls of 1919
Uf WHn HKf -Will
111 f Af.-iJaHisasHMlaWMnsMX. 13 III I
When Andrew Carnegie went into the
steel business ho made Col Scott one
of his partners and one of the early
steel millionaires.
When ho had foreseen that steam
railway would soon be compelled to
replace, their wooden bridge's by steel
structures ami had decided to make
the steel bridges Andrew Carnegie
cast about for likely young men to
aid blm In his enterprise. He found
ed In the early seventies the Key
atone Drldgo Company. His original
partners were William P. Shlnn,
David McCandless, nenry Phipps and
Thomas Carncg'e. These partners
conducted the plant and Andrew
Carnegie raised the money and sold
the goods and attended to the adver
tising. Ho wna tho first great Indus
trial press, agent, and his methods
awed and disgusted the,old timers In
the steel business, but he got the
business and the money. Subsequent
ly he took into the Keystone Drldgo
Company Thomas N. Miller, William
Coleman, Andrew Klomon, J. Edgar
Thompson, John Scott, DaVId A. Stew
art and John W. Vandervoort
The steel Industry waa flourishing
In Western Pennsylvania and North
ern Ohio In a small way. The meth
ods of the old-timers were conserva
tlve. Andrew Carnegie's bridge con
cent grew like a mushroom and he
began learning things about the ateel
manufacturing business every mln
ute. He found that many labor eav
lng and productldn speeding devices
had beon Ignored by tho steel Makers
and that therp were Jn the trade many
young, ambitious men who were not
getting a chance. He gathered up
some of these 'young men and wont
Into the steel business.
Aided by a prohibitive tariff and tho
tremendous railroad expansion In the
late seventies, the Carnegie enterprises
would have grown to great propor
Uons along natural business channels,
but he forced them. He began in
anlrlng his superintendent and sub-
superintendents by gifts of atock In
the concsrn. He made them partnsr,
In 18$) Andrew Cagncgio had thirty.
three of these partners, ,not one of
whom bad paid a cent for stock which
was earning from $0 to 60 per cent
per annum. He drove these men aa
Simon Legree drove Uncle Tom, but
ho waa a benevolent Simon Lcgree.
He ro warded toll munificently and he
weeded out the men who could not
stand the pace with scant ceremony
or consideration. Occasionally a val
ued partner -would break down. He
would be promptly ptgeonbold and a
new, eager, striving, ruthless young
man would take his place.
The army of clerks In the Carnegie
enterprises were keyed up to the ut
most endeavor by promises dangling
always before them of stock bonuses
nnd promotions to salesmanships or
superintendences. In the mills, the
skilled workers were paid ataggorlng
iagea and many with Ideas were
picked for promotion. Of the thirty
three partners of Andrew Carnegie In
1S$9, only three had more than an
elementary school education. The
others had gone into the milts as
boys and worked their way up.
Those were rough, strenuous days.
Andrew Carnegie applied to the fullest
extent of his remarkablo powers of
organization his point "to make
others work while I think." Henry
C. Frlok, one of his partners at that
period, brought to the Carnegie Inter-
ests five-sixths of the Henry W.
Oliver holdings in the Mesaba ore
range without the actual expenditure
of a cent Later. Frick had a falling
out with Carneglo hlch resulted In
the reorganization of the Carneglo
interests. For hla services In bringing
about this reorganization, James D,
Dill, the corporation attorney, was
paid a fee of 1.000,000,
When J. P. Morgan and the, allied
Wall Street Interests saw that the
Indomitable Carnegie, who thought
all the time and drove others to work
for him all the time, was In a fair
way to carry out his threat that he
would grab control of the steel and
ore business of the continent they
bought him out He had forty-
four partners; none of whom had paid
a dollar for his stock, and all were In
the millionaire class or approaching
It Many others bad dropped out of
the organization either to retire from
business or to go Into aome branch
of the ateel Industry on theJr own
account
Among those millionaires who wero
the by-products of Mr. Carnegie's
closing years In business were Wll
Horn E. Corey, Charles M, Schwab,
George Lauder, James Qaylct A. T.
Dinkey, F. T.. F. Lovejoy, John a. A.
Lelshman, P. T. Derg. Henry Docnth-
rager, Thomas Lynch, W. W. Black
burn and H. P. Dope. All of the
partners, who were active to tho close
of Mr. Carnegie's control, profited by
tho sale of the Carneglo steel in
terests to the United States 3teel
Corporation and named the President
of the United States Steel Corpora
tion for five years after bo retired
from active business.
The formation of the United States
Steel Corporation was the means of
making millionaires of hundreds of
men. who had not been with tho Car
negie organization, and theso are In
direct! responsible to Carnegie for
their wealth, for he made possible
the United Statca Steel Corporation.
Tho aggregate wealth of tho million
aires Andrew Carnegie mode directly
or Indirectly amounts to many times
more than Carnegie's fortune at the
peak of his prosperity.
After he retired from business he
looked after the widows of many of
the. men he had raised to wealth, pay
lng them 6 per cent on their money
and protecting them In their holdings
by bond. At one time he had on his
books the names of 148 of these
widow depositors and the amount ho
held for them waa $$,1S7,82.20.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026897/1920-03-24/ed-1/?sp=7</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		STEEL MASTER BEGAN
TO SAVE WHEN YOUNG
Recognized That Success Lay In Sound
Investment-Safest Security in
World Is Now Offered By
Government.
Andrew Carnegie died not long ago,
leaving behind him $30,000,000. He
had given away about $300,000,000 in
an effort to avoid the reproach of
dying rich.
It is probable that the high cost of
living gave the "steel master" little
worry during th? latter half of his
life, but it is certain that in his boy
hood the prices of the necessaries of
life were vital factors. And Andrew
Carnegie in his early years met'the1
cost of living with the same remedy
which America's leaders, headed by
President Wilson, are now putting
?h as the biaic principle of the
t to withstand the menace that
s in the soaring prices of today,
t remedy IB thrift-the practice of
ng, the elimination of waste and
id investment,
the days when Andrew Carnegie,
?ears old, earned $1.20 a week as
abbin boy in an Allegheny City
on mill, and later when he earned
25 a month as a telegraph mes
:er boy, the cost of living meant
h to him. He had little margin
for saving. But he did save. There
were few opportunities for the small
saver to make safe investments. Se
curities were not issued in small de
nominations. There were no Thrift
Stamps or War Savings Stamps,
backed by the government, into which
the meager proceeds of the Scotch
boy's thrift could be converted.
But Andrew Carnegie at the age of
20 determined upon safe investment.
The soundest securities that offered
were 10 shares of stock in an express
company worth $600. Carnegie had to
borrow part of the money he paid.
But he was convinced that savings ly
ing idle were not performing their
proper function.
The American man or woman, boy
or girl of today does not have to bor
row to add to the savings fund in or
der to find safe investment. The gov
ernment makes sound security in the
form of Savings Stamps, Trtasury
Savings Certificates, and war bonds
available to /ery saver who will be
gin to practice thrift by the regular in
vestment of sums as small as 25
cents.
Every American today has a better
opportunity for success than lay be
fore Andrew Carnegie when he faced
the world.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1935-11-24/ed-1/?sp=92</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		The Fruits of a Fortune
What should a rich man do with his money
^Andrew (arnegie's answer was to invest one
of the world's greatest fortunes so that it will
work forever to improve man's lot. Dfow the whole
world is celebrating the centennial of his birth
by Nicholas Murray Butler
President of Columbia University; President of the Carnegie Endowment
for International Peace
Andrew Carnegie’s
favorite photograph
Skibo Castle,
where many of his
dreams were born
Photo by
Davis Sanford
Photo by International
Film Service
Andrew Carnegie was bom at Dun
fermline, in Scotland, on November
25. 1835. The centenary of his birth
is now to be celebrated in most
distinguished manner both in the United
States and in Great Britain. These celebra
tions will be echoed throughout the civilized
world, for there is no land in which Mr.
Carnegie's name is not known and none
which the influence of his idealism and fore
sight have not reached.
To what is this amazing circumstance due?
Surely not by any means to the fact that he
amassed a huge fortune through his develop
ment of modem industry, for many others in
many lands have done that and their names
are neither known nor remembered. The
rt-ason for -Andrew Carnegie's outstanding
position in the history of his time, with fullest
assurance that he will be remembered through
the years, is that the making of his great
fortune was wholly subordinate to his mag
nificent use of it.
If. as his biographers estimate. Andrew
Carnegie's fortune at its maximum amounted
to some S360.000.000 he gave more than 90
per cent, of it for the benefit and service of his
fellow-men. If those who by reason of ability
or opportunity amass great fortunes in in
dustry. in commerce or in transportation use
their accumulations as Andrew Carnegie used
his. little criticism will be heard of the suc
cessful man of affairs, for in such case he will
have returned to the public service that which
he was able to gain for himself, honestly
enough, through public cooperation and
support.
Observation of scores of those who have
been acclaimed as successful men of business.
and acquaintance with many of them, is
ground for the observation that the modem
multimillionaire has before him four stages of
possible evolution.
The first of these is the acquisitive stage,
when his whole concern is with making money
and amassing a fortune. The second is the
possessive stage, when he hugs his wealth to
his person and identifies it with himself and
himself with it. This is as far as most multi
millionaires ever get. It requires both large
intelligence and fine character to go farther.
The third stage is the contemplative. When
this is reached, the multimillionaire asks,
sometimes quizzically, sometimes seriously,
"What am 1 going to do with this money?"
He usually answers this question by pouring
it out in huge sums upon the members of his
immediate family, thereby wrecking their
lives and the lives of their children and grand
children, until his accumulation is fortunately
dissipated. But it is dissipated only after it
has done its demoralizing work.
The fourth and final stage of this evolution
is the distributive. When this is reached, the
possessor of great wealth is in position to
become an outstanding public servant. If his
ideals are high, his judg
ment good, his knowledge
of men well tested by ex
perience, then he may
quickly climb to the high
est level of public service.
This Andrew Carnegie did.
Born a Scot, and early
becoming deeply im
mersed in American life
and thought, Andrew Car
negie from his young man
hood had a truly amazing
insight into the proper
meaning and significance
of wealth. As far back as
1868, when he was but
thirty-three years of age
and already had an in
come of some £50,000 a
year truly a huge sum
for those days he wrote
t hese extraordinary words:
Beyond this never earn make no effort
to increase fortune, but spend the surplus
each year for benevolent purposes. Cast aside
business forever except for others.
“Settle in Oxford and get a thorough educa
tion, making the acquaintance of literary men
—this will take three years active work pay
especial attention to speaking in public.
Settle then in London and purchase a con
trolling interest in some newspaper or live
review and give the general management of it
attention, taking a part in public matters, espe
cially those connected with education and im
provement of the poorer classes.
“Man must have an idol the amassing of
wealth is one of the worst species of idolatry
no idol more debasing than the worship of
money. Whatever I engage in I must push
inordinately; therefore should I be careful to
choose that life which will be the most elevat
ing in its character. To continue much
longer overwhelmed by business cares and
with most of my thoughts wholly upon the
way to make more money in the shortest
time, must degrade me beyond hope of per
manent recovery.”
Surely this is an extraordinary revelation of
mind and character on the part of a young
man who wrs already demonstrating a capa
city to make money in exceptional fashion,
but who refused to be either tempted by it or
paralyzed by it, as is unhappily the almost
uniform experience of modem men in a like
situation.
Something more than twenty years later.
Andrew Carnegie wrote his famous article for
the “North American Review” which led to
giving the widest currency to his phrase that
he should consider it disgraceful to die a rich
man. John Morley wrote to Andrew Carnegie
that these words would stick to him forever
as an unreserved condemnation of those dying
rich. Oddly enough, there appeared almost
simultaneously Henry George’s “Progress and
Poverty” and Edward Bellamy's “Looking
Backward,” and for some time Henry George,
Edward Bellamy and Andrew Carnegie were
all three widely quoted in the attempt to
answer the question. What are we going to do
with our rich men?
Andrew Carnegie had another marked char
acteristic which greatly broadened his intelli
gence and his outlook, strengthened his
character and guided his judgment in all his
public benefactions and relationships. This
was the habit which he early formed of mak
ing the acquaintance and the friendship of
outstanding leaders in the intellectual, the
artistic and the public life of his time, and
attaching them to himself in bonds of close
friendship. What Mr. Gladstone and John
Morley and Elihu Root meant to Andrew
Carnegie is well known to his intimate
friends, and some record of it all may be
found on the printed pages of his life and
personal writings.
During his months at Skibo each summer,
he was surrounded by a group of men which
probably could not be reproduced anywhere
else on earth. There were to be found prime
ministers, archbishops, heads of universities,
great judges and members of the Bar. leading
scholars, men of letters and men of science
all welded by Andrew Carnegie's hospitable
personality into a company of surpassing in
terest and significance. The conversation
during a week or two at Skibo in those days
will never be forgotten by any who were so
fortunate as to take part in it.
It was because of Andrew Carnegie's fixed
purpose to use his fortune' for the public
service and to be guided in so doing by the
judgment of the ablest men of his time, that
when the distribution of his vast accumulation
was made, it took so remarkable and so un
precedented a form. Andrew Carnegie began
to think of this distribution long before it
actually took place. He turned the whole
matter over in his mind again and again. He
discussed it with his intimate friends and dis
tinguished counselors both in Great Britain
and in the United States. He began in various
small ways —small they must be called in
comparison with what was to come —and
brought comfort and happiness time and
again where there had been distress and suf
fering. and also, through his gifts for public
.libraries, put hundreds of communities in pos
session of those instruments for reading and
study of which they had previously been
deprived.
When Andrew Carnegie was ready to begin
(Continued on next page)
Photo by J. B. McClay
The Carnegie Institute of Technology his tribute to Pittsburgh
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028272/1892-07-27/ed-1/?sp=8</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		NON-UNION MEN
Start Up Carnegie's Armor Plata
Mill at Homestead.
Dot. Fattlaon ArrlTM on th ften
trmdltlon or Carnegie Will Ba Ka
queiteil bjr Amalgamated Lead-
era Stubborn Legal Contest
In I'roepect.
Homestead, July 20. The booming;
of cannon' Tuesday morning' announced
to the cltizeub of Homestead that Got.
Tattinon had arrived. A larije crowd
had gathered at the depot Rain was
falling steadily and it was a yery disa
greeable morning for the governor to
make his entry. The governor's priv
ate car was switched off at Munhall
station and the governor went through
the Carnegie mill to the hotel opposite
the entrance. The governor's presence
was not discovered for some time.
Finally word was sent to headquarters
and the cannon in front of Gen. Snow
don's headquarters responded with a
salute of seventeen guns. While this
was in progress the governor was driven
up the hill in an open carriage. The
cavalry acted as an escort. Gen. Snow
den was at headquarter awaiting the
arrival of his chief.
For the first time since thn present
lockout began, the Carnogie Company
yesterday made a pretense of starting
its mills here. It was something of a
surprise to Homestead people to see
smoke issuing from the armor plate
mill in the morning, and they were still
more surprised at noon when the big
whistle was blown for the dinner hour.
The full power of the whistle was not
put in operation, but the people recog
nized the oM-time sound and many of
them looked down toward the entrance
to the works to see if gangs of workers
were not pouring out on their several
ways to dinner. But none came. There
wens workmen inside the works, how
ever, and tliey were pursuing their
duties in a business-like manner, seem
ingly without thought that an armed
guard was necessary to protect Those
men were brought into the works
secretly by the company within the
past. week. They came a few at a time
until Monday, when the company suc
ceeded in getting in s number of work
ers sufficient to guaruntee the starting
up of the armor plate mill.
In the afternoon some of the new
workmen made a protective shield for
heavy marine guns in the presence of a
number of military officers. The start
ing of the mills, following the issuance
of warrants for leaders of the strike,
has shown the advisory committee the
determination of the Curnegie Com
pany officials, but they do not appear
to be downcast at the presence of non
union men in the places of Homestead
workmen. Members of the committee
ins' -it that non-union men can never
run the Homestead mills because Of
their ignorance of the technical branches
of iron and steel, The committee also
has hopes of defeating the company In
the long run on the declaration of a
general boycott by freight handlers,
railroa 1 men, carpenters, masons,build
crs and others engaged in construction
work against the Carnegie Company's
product if non-union men are allowed to
run the mills. Meanwhile the non
union men are ready for another day's
work.
HnMK'TRAii, July 20. No attempt
was made Tuesday to serve warrants
on the five men in Homestead who,with
John McLuckie and Hugh O'DonneU,
are charged with murder committed on
the day the I'inkertons were repulsed.
Constable Weblier, one of the trio sent
out by AlUurmun McMusters, of I'itts
burg, to arrest the five men wanted,
came to Homestead in the afternoon
with subrxrnns for people whose evi
dence is wanted at tho hearing llurgess
McLuckie will receive in Pittsburgh to
day. This duty wasaccomplished with
out trouble.
When the subpoenas Hd been served
Webber went back to Pittsburgh with
out having uttempto l t arrest Ross,
Oitelilow, Flanagan, KurUett or Flu-
herty. These five men were to be seen
nboutthe strei ts.appar.,:'.t'.;.- Indifferent
to t he serious charge made nguinst them.
There wai no attempt made at con
cealment of their presence In town.
The accused men have decided to evade
arrest until after the McLuckie hear
ing. If the biiresi Is admitted to bail
they wi'.l iuliii"iliately surrender and
ask release under l.ond on the same
grounds a tlmse aucd by McLuckie.
They have not made any decision ns to
what they will do If bail is refused the
burgess, but it is probable that they
will give themselves up.
The members of the Amalgamated as
sociation have practically decided to ap
ply for warrants for Mr. Prick, Andrew
Carnegie and others, but are still In
consultation with counsel as to whether
the warrants, if sworn out for murder
and treason, will hold. They are de
termined to offset the action of the com
pany's officials by obtaining thesi war
rants if possible, and the men are confi
dent that they will succeed. They
claim that their caso against the offi
cials of the company Is much stronger
than that of the lutter against any of
the individuals who are now wanted by
the constables. They claim that An
drw Carnegie and Frick are responsible
for sending an armed body of men into
the state without legal authority and
they can le held for treason on this
charge, and that they are also responsi
ble ns accessories before the fact for the
manslaughter which followed.
Victims of Fir.
St. Johns. J.". V., July 50. Forest
fires are iij.iin raging In the country.
At Hay Hulls a large fire is in progress
and another between here and Topsail
is assuming serious proportions. Be
yond that the whole country along the
railway line la in flames. Msnuels,
Holyrood. Keillgrews and Salmon Core
are threatened, and five houses were
burned at Whltbourne and fourteen at
Blaketown.
i Banner-man park contains nearly 1,500
persons living in huts, and widespread
feneration of disease Is feared. Doctors
visit the camp frequently to direct the
aaaitary o Derations.
NfLUOKtB RELEASED,
Ha FnraUhe at,00O Ball aad li Owes
nil Lltwrtf'An BaHturtastle KaeapMos
Tenderatt Iha By-rasa by ClMsaas Upas
m Eatam.ao (MMattead.
PirrsavReto July 81. Burgess Mc
Luolile has been released on 110,000
ball but the decision la this oasetrtll
not apply to Hugh O'DonneU and the
rest of the strikers fo whom warrants
have been Issued, and all of them will
be compelled to take their innings be
fore the court Judge Magee's court
room was crowded Wodnesday by labor
ing men of tills olty and Homestead.
It had been anticipated that counsel for
the Carneglcs would resist the applica
tion to give McLuckie his liberty and
there were many murmurs of surprise
when, as soon as the case was called,
District Attorney Burleigh arose and
said that having carefully gone through
the evidence with the associate counsel
for the state he conceded thatMcLudMe
was entitled to his liberty. Inasmuch,
however, as the offense was one of con
siderable gravity and in view of the
present situation is the locality, he felt
justified in asking that the ball shoultl
be ample.
McLuokle's ball was fixed at 110,000.
Owen Murphy and Oliver C. Kinton,
two residents of Homestead, qualified
after being put through a rigid exam
ination by the district attorney and Mo
Luckio was released. The crowd filed
out of the court room and gave him a'
ohcer as ho hurried away to Homestead.
In an Interview with Attorney Bren
nan, he said that warrants will be is-i
sued very soon for tho arrests of Prick
and Lovejoy. They will be prosecuted.
He did not say what would be done
about Andrew Carnegie.
Homestead, July 21. Burgess Mo
Luckie was given a big reception when
he arrived in town after his sojourn in
the Pittsburgh jail Nearly 2,000 mill
workers gathorod at the depot and the
brass band was in readiness. When the
train rolled in and the burgess appeared
on the platform there was a tremendous
shout McLuckie was escorted to an
open carriage which was in waiting.
Ho took a seat in the carriage and
Messrs. Lowry and Schuchman, of the
committee, entered the same carriage.
The band led the procession which was
formed and nearly a thousand mill
workers fell In behind the carriage
The procession moved through the prin
cipal streets to the home of Mr. Mo
Lucktc. Thus did the man arrested at
the instance of the Carnogie Company
and charged with murder re-cntor the
borough of which he is burgess.
Exactly ninety-eight men surrounded
the dinner table in the pressing mill of
the Carnegie steel works at noon yes
terday. A reporter gained admission to
tho mill just before noon and was pres
ent when the whistle announced the
noon hour. Fifteen carpenters were at
work on a new house being constructed
between the machine pressing room and
the river.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1904-11-13/ed-1/?sp=56</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		THIS IS HOW THE HAGUE ARBITRATION PALACE, THE GIFT OF ANDREW CARNEGIE TO TILE WHOLE
WORLD, WILL LOOK WHEN COMPLETED.
fm na a composite photograph which may be
talien as a type.
The first impression obtained from a study
wealthy is that the richest of them have
founded and built up their own fortunes.
Th were pioneers, turning into riches what
was untilled. According to James Burn
the English author, the Individuals en
lo .1 with the greatest possessions all began
They head the list of names which he
ar.J ranked as follows, giving also their
t t-e of wealth, their homes, and the amount
sir fortune:
Alfred Beit, diamonds. London, $500,000,000.
J. B. Robinson, gold and diamonds, London,
►.000,000.
J. D. Rockefeller, oil, New-York, $250,000,000.
W. \V. Astor, land, London, $200,000,000.
I rtnee Demidoff, land, St. Petersburg, $200,
>.Andrew Carnegie, steel, New-York, $125,000.-
O.'»O.
W. K. Vanderbilt, railroads, New-York, $100,
00 MXJO.
William Rockefeller, oil. New-York. $100,000.
oo<».
J. J. Astor, land, New-York, $75,000,000.
Lord Rothschild, money lending, London,
$75,000,000. I
Duke of Westminster, land, London, $75,000,
00*
J. Pierpont Morgan, banking, New-York, $75,
000.000.
Lord Iveagh, beer, Dublin. .$70,000,000.
"or a Isidora Ccusino, mines and railroads.
Chili, $70,000,000.
M. Heine, silk, Paris. $70,000,000.
Caron Alphonse Rothschild, money lending,
P^ris. $70,000,000.
Baron Nathaniel Rothschild, money lending,
Vienna, $70,000,000.
Archduke Frederick of Austria, land, Vienna
70,000.000.
George J. Gould, railroads, New-York $70-
OMOOO.
James J. Hill, railroads, New-York, $70,
0 >.000.
Ilia. Hetty Green, banking, New-York, $55.
•K>O,OOO.
James 11. Smith, banking, New-York, $50,
0 >.000.
Duke of Devonshire, land, London, $50
003,000.
Duke of Bedford, land, London. $50,000,000.
Henry O. Ilavemeyer, sugar, New-York, $50
01 >,000.
John Smith, mines, Mexico, $45,000,000.
Claus Spreckels, sugar, San Francisco, $40,
000,000.
Archbishop Conn, land, Vienna, $40,000,000.
Russell Sage, money lending. New-York, $25,
0000,000.
Baroness Burdett-Coutts, banking. London,
$2;">,000,000.
Sir Thomas Lipton. groceries, London. $25
fVIO.OQO.
Belt. Robinson and Rockefeller, it may thus be
seen, have amassed greater riches in their chosen
i Ids than those born to great estates an.i
reared with the sole view to Increasing them.
They have outstripped the heads of such houses
as the Rothschilds, the Astors, the Vanderbilta,
ar.d the titled men of wealth of England, with
their ancestral square miles of lands.
An element common to the character of each of
these three men is a constant, powerful, untir
ing desire for gain. It us a purpose which they
boast of. They may not know human nature
l.alf as well as some dramatists, but, unlike the
playwright, they do not waste their talent on
what they regard as Impractable things. Before
his son's Sunday school class, at the Fifth
Avenue Baptist Church, of this city, Mr. Rocke
feller once said: "I believe it is a religious duty
to set all the money you can." To Cecil Rhodes,
his associate in the diamond business at Kir-
berley, Mr. Belt said: "My sole pleasure is the
making of money. I once found Joy in spend- 1
Lng it, but that wa3 before I called myself rich." I
Mr. Carnegie baa acknowledged that at one time
Coating en eleventh uajca.
XEW-YOUK TRIBUNE ILL! STILVTiM) SUPPLEMENT.
THIS IS HOW THE MAIS' STAIRCASE OF TIIF. MUUTftATIAN itlin
WHEN CGMP^TCD TIIE UAGUE WILL L
HAGUE PEACE PA LACK.
Plan* for Andrew Camcaie's (rift
to the World Decided On.
The Hague. Nov. 7. Final decision has at last
been reached concerning the Carnegie P*ac«
Palace. The announcement was made th- other
day that the Dutch government had porcbaaad
a plot of land situated at the eastern end of The
Hague, behind the Botanical Gardens, to be
given to the Carnegie committee. Following
that it was officially announced that the future
palace of arbitration would be built on the plan
of the Brussels Palace of Justice, of which It
will be an exact copy on a smaller scale.
The estimated of*?t of the peace pa'are La
$1,040,000, or about one-fifth the amount ex
pended on the Brussels Palace of Justice. Mr.
Carnegie's original offer, on April 22. 10ft.?. wa3
$1,500,000. Doubtless he will supply the rest
The general appearance of the palace r.o-.v aboat
to be erected will be that of a capitoL The
style of the building will be classical, or Greco-
Roman, a3 it is called here.
The edifice will consist of a main r
flanked at each end by a forepart, ar. 1 with a
spacious central portico as the prtadpaJ en
trance. A double row of columns will rise to the
right and left of this portico, and behin 1 them
a large monumental staircase leading to the
principal audience room, where the Court of
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024055/1903-06-13/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		ANDREW CARNEGIE
LIKENS
BOOKER T. WASHINGTON
UNTO
MOSES OF. OLDEN TIMES
Lately Andrew Carnegie presented
his Check to Booker T. Washington
for six hundred thousand dollars, and
In doing so ho declared that "the
founder of Tuskegee is the mod
em Moses of the Afro-American
race; that like Moses of olden
times he will guide or lead
the race into the Promised land which
will flow with milk and honey." It's
true that Andrew Carnegie has suc
ceeded in becoming a billionaire not
by his own genius but because the
United States government has for
years enacted legislation for his spe
cial benefit which has made It possible
for him to accumulate his millions.
But In spite or. his Ill-gotten million
Andrew Carnegie displays his ignor
ance of ancient history whenever he
likens Booker T. Washington unto
Moses of old, for there Is not much
similarity between these two charac
ters excepC that Moses met with a
crushing defeat and failed in his mis
sion and the same fate is in store for
Booker T. Washington.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn2008060406/1913-02-28/ed-1/seq-8</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		Rise of Andrew Carnegie - Laird of Skibo
Dunfermline, Scotland, January.—ln a wee garret
of an humble workingman’s home in this old city,
Andrew Carnegie, the great steel millionaire of Amer
ica, was born. __ v
The trip from Dunfermline to Skibo, Scotland, is
not a desperate undertaking when made in the usual
way, but if the journey be made byway of Pittsburg,
Pennsylvania, the venture is a tedious one, beset with
difficulties. But one living man has ever thus made
the trip, and his name is Andrew Carnegie. It took
him half a century of steady toil and exertion to ac
complish the feat.
If one goes from Inverness to John O’Groat’s house
in the northland, he passes Dornock Firth and Bonar
Bridge. The latter is the station of Skibo Castle, some
eight miles distant. There lives
the “Laird of Skibo,” Prince of
Pittsburgh, the “Star Spangled
Scotchman,” who got his G. B.
at Dunfermline and his K. C. B.
at Homestead, in the current
lingo of the Boer war.
As a matter of fact, the home
life of Mr. Carnegie in Skibo
Castle differs in but one particu
lar from that of any other poten
tate of the Grampian Hills; Mr.
Carnegie does not smoke. It is
a legend that but one man ever
lit a stogy within the walls of
Skibo. That man was the Duke
of Sutherland, and he had bad
luck all his life. Deep potations
of Scotch whisky take the place
of vulgar tobacco at Skibo. But
even these are limited to meal
times. It is a fundamental dog
ma of Mr. Carnegie that alco
holic indulgences should be lim
ited to the meal hour. In his
volume published some years ago reciting the adven
tures of his first coaching trip through the kingdom,
Mr. Carnegie railed right lustily at the Prohibitionists
for advocating total abstinence, pointing out that
moderate indulgence at meals was the only true tem
perance.
Aside from Mr. Carnegie and his retainers, the
principal inhabitants of the neighborhood of Skibo are
ghosts, most of whom have a harmless disposition. At
Bonar Bridge was Macbeth’s Castle, and which was
about as far north as Shakespeare ever got in his im
aginings. Os course, there is a spook hovering in that
vicinity. Moreover, the old Castle of Dornoch itself
has a well-authenticated ghost. All the laity of the
neighborhood will tell you about the Old Abbot who
was doomed to forever haunt this pile on account of
his sins. The poor old man’s time is not up yet.
By Clarence Alexander, in American Patriot.
ANDREW CARNEGIE
From Photo made in Dunfermline, Scotland, twelve
years ago.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/46032385/1908-05-01/ed-1/seq-17</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		SURELY THIS IS DIVISION
Certainly there is division in the
republican party when a republican
newspaper is bold enough to attack
Andrew Carnegie. In a recent issue
the Chicago Inter Ocean (rep.) print
ed an editorial entitled "Can this
Really be Andrew Carnegie?" The
Inter Ocean editorial follows:
One shock after another! A news
paper telegram comes from Los An
geles, the capital of the incomparable,
sun belt of glorious California, where
the thinking of righteous thoughts
requires little or no effort. Before
touching upon the writer of the mag
azine article, it tells us that the Hon.
Paul Morton, formerly vice president
in charge of traffic of the Santa Fe
railway, later secretary of the United
States navy, and now president of
the Equitable Life Assurance society,
a recognized expert on all matters
pertaining to the .rebate, is there,
and, of course, talking.
''You knew," he was asked, "that
rebates were given by the Santa Fe
railroad system when you were its
first vice president?" and, it seems,
he replied:
" ""The rebate proposition was built
up as a matter of competition. Mr.
Carnegie, who poses as a philanthro
pist, is one of the greatest rebate
enthusiasts the country has ever
known. Every one who knows about
the steel industry knows that."
This is by all odds the worst blow
we have received for some ti-ae. It
seems incredible that the Hon. Paul
Morton is speaking the truth. And
yet, if anybody knows, he knows,
when it comes to rebates and rebat
ers. But to realize it is the difficult,
almost impossible, thing!
Can this be the Andrew Carnegie
who is telling us in the magazines,
over his own honored signature, that
the railway management of this
country for many years past has been
Inexcusably immoral?
Can this be tho Andrew Carnegie
who has been telling us in the mag
azines that Mr. Roosevelt is right in
tearing up the whole country to end
the vicious practices of the rail
ways? Can this be the Andrew Carnegie
who, by a slight extension of the av
erage imagination, may be seen to
blush with shame . as duty to his
adopted couniy compels him to pen
magazine articles dealing with the
pernicious methods of the railway
magnates?
Can this be the Andrew Carnegie
who, after chilling us with fear,
warms us with faith by explaining
that the residuum of national virtue
of which he himself is the foremost
representative is still a potent factor
among those influences which make
for good, and that the country may
yet be saved by the exalted thought?
Is this the Andrew Carnegie who
endeavors to instill into our minds
the highest and most enduring pre
cepts of commercial integrity from
month to month, next to pure read
ing matter, in the ten and even the
fifteen cent periodicals?
Is this the Andrew Carnegie who
declares that the thing for all of us
to do in these trying hours is to be
15
just and fear not, to be virtuous if
we should be happy?
We are afraid that it is the same,
and none other, and that the picture
that presents itself to our troubled
consciousness is as black as it seems;
for if anybody knows about those
things that tho Hon. Paul Morton is
talking about, and apparently can
not refrain from talking about, that
man is the Hon. Paul Morton. Chi
cago Inter Ocean.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038485/1917-03-04/ed-1/seq-48</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1934-05-06/ed-1/seq-95</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		Among those sailing. Andrew Carnegie,
steel baron turned philanthropist, and Mary
Garden, in her opera hey-day. pose for the
ship photographers. & Havper & Bros
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86092356/1904-12-20/ed-1/seq-7</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-john-rockefeller</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86091092/1891-06-27/ed-1/?sp=2</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		MEN OF GREAT WEALTH.
John I). ROekrfellor Taken the Lead
With About $100,000,000.
AN INCOME OF S26.000 PER DAY.
The story has been in circula
tion in Wall street during the pnst
week to the effect that John I).
Rockefeller, the president of the
Standard Oil Truet, is seriously ill,
and that, acting under the advice
of his physicians, ho had deter
mined to stay at hi* residence in
th« suburbs of Cleveland during
the entire summer. Further de
tails were that Mr. Rockefeller was
suffering from nervous prostration,
consequent on close attention to
business. It was believed, how
ever, that if he remained in seclu
sion for six or eight weeks and left
business matters entirely to the
care of others he would be all right
again in the autumn. The story
of Mr. Rockefeller's partial collapse
commanded a certain amount of
belief among Wall street men, for
the reason that the millionaire has
not looked particularly well for
some time past, and those who
have experience in such matters
declare that the strain consequent
upon giving personal attention to
such vast interest as are controlled
by Mr. Rockefeller is bound, sooner
or later to tell on a man's health,
however strong he may be by rea
son of a naturally vigorous consti
tution.
The report regarding Mr. Rocke
feller's illness put forward in the
conservative form here indicated,
has met with a prompt and em
phatic denial at the hands of Mr.
Rockefeller's family in Cleveland
and of his business associates in
New York City. Possibly the
stories as to his bad health have
been exaggerated, but the fact that
the reports have been circulated
has emphasized the rather interest
ing consideration that although
Mr. Rockefeller occasionally oper
ted in the Wall street market, and
although his wealth is probably
three times as great as that of Jay
Gould and equal to the aggregate
wealth of perhaps any ten Wall
street millionaires that may be
mentioned, these reports have had
no effect whatever on the course of
the markets.
Similar reports concerning Jay
Gould, or even Rüssel Sage or The
odore Havemcyjr, would have had
an immédiat» effect on prices and
disturbed the market to a very con
siderable extent. The explanation
is, of course, that although Mr.
Rockefeller has at times purchased
large blocks of stock in Wall street,
and was at one time reported to
have purchased enough Northern
Pacific stock to secure control, he
has never figured as a large specu
lator or as an operator carrying
considerable lines of stock. His
retirement from business, therefore,
eithvr temporarily, or through ill
ness or by death, would not be
attended by the throwing of large
blocks of stock on the market and
any consequent decline in prices.
Outside of this Mr. Rockefeller is
not interested in the railroads of
the country except as a holder of
railroad bonds.
That Mr. Rockefeller is the rich
est man in America admits of no
question whatever. His wea'th is
estimated to be anywhere from i
$125,000,000 to $150,000,000. No I
closer estimate than this can be
made, except by Mr. Rockefeller
himself. Even that gentleman
once declared on the witness-stand
that he was not able to estimate his
çwrn possessions within ten or fif
teen millions of dollars, and this
8 .ate oient was not prompted by
any affectation whatever. Affecta
tion is not one of Mr. Rockefeller's
peculiarites.
About two years ago a Standard
Oil man who is a close personal
friend of Mr. Rockefeller, and who
is thoroughly and accurately posted
as to the inside of Standard Oil
affairs, estimated the Rockefeller
fortune at $129,000,000, and gave
the following figures:
Standard OH stock S40 ,n00,0nn
I'rcnilmns on same 28,min,ooo
Ileal estate lo,onn,ooi>
l.eail trust 2,000,000
Railroad stocks and bonds 20,000,000
Natural wis stock 4,000,000
Bank stock n,ooo,ono
Manufactured gas stock 3,000,000
Steamboat stock (Inman Une, &o.).. 1,000,000
Mines In Utah, Wisconsin, &c 4,000,000
Cash on hand 2,000,000
Miscellaneous 10,000,000
Total Si», 000,000
It will be seen from this state
ment that Mr. Rockefeller's invest
ments are of the most solid, sub
stantial and remunerative descrip
tion. This estimate of his wealth,
however, is confirmed by no less
an authority than Mr. Rockefeller's
associate millionaire, Henry M.
Flagler. Mr. Flagler not long ago
said that he knew Mr. Rockefeller's
income was in the neighborhood
of $9,000,000 a year. Reckoning
that his investments yield an aver
age of 6 per cent, and there is not
much doubt that the gilt-edged
securities he holds pan out at that
figure, this gives him a capital of
$150,000.000. The vastness of this
income may, perhaps, be better
realized when it is calculated that
$9,000,000 a year means something
like $25,000 a day. At the same
time as making the statement re
ferred to Mr. Flagler said that his
own income was $3,000,000 a year
and estimated the wealth of Col.
Oliver Payne another Stanard Oil
magnate, at $22,000,000.
The only man, probably, who
has ever lived in America whose
possessions were larger than John
D. Rockefeller's possessions at pres
ent was William H. Vanderbilt.
There is no reason to doubt that at
the time of William H. Vanderbilt's
death he was worth over $200,000,
000. Indeed a close friend of Van
derbilt once said that Vanderbilt
took him into a safe-deposit vault
and showed him securities that
aggregated even more than this.
W. H. Vanderbilt's wealth, how
ever, was divided up at his death
and no one of the Vanderbilts now
—not even Cornelius Vanderbilt—
has anything like this amount of
money. After Rockefeller, the
wealthiest man in America (o-dav
is unquestionably William Wal-J
dorf Astor, who is worth probably
$100,000,000. Jay Gould is worth,
according to the most careful esti-
mâtes by well-informed Wall street
nien, about $50,000,000 or $G0,000,- j
000. In comparing the Rockefeller I
fortune with the Rothschilds for
tune it must be remembered that
although the entire wealth of the
various branches of the Rothschild
family adds up to perhaps a billion
of dollars, no more than $75,000,
000 is in the hands of any one
member of the family.
In establishing any comparison
between the Rockefeller fortunes
and other notable fortunes held by
human beings on the face of this
earth, this fact deserves to be
pointed out: The Rockefeller for
tune is the accumulation of com
paratively a few years, and it is the
accumulation,of one man and that
by no means an old man. John
1). Rockefeller was born in 1839
and is therefore now only a little
over fifty years of age. He did not
go into the oil business out of
which his vast fortune has been
made until after the war, that is
to say about 1868 or 1869, when
he was about thirty years old.
The $125,000,000 or $150,000,000
mentioned represent, therefore, the
result of a business career extend
ing over a little more than a score
of years. To make one more arith
metical calculation, it may be
pointed out that Rockefeller there
fore made at the rate of between
$6,000,000 and $7,000,000 a vear 1
daughter Bessie, married in 1889
Rev Chas. L. Strong, a young Bap
tlSt cler m:ui antI son of the l )ros
ldent of the Utica Tbeological Som
in ary AUa who is ver v Pi
Wlth a vivacioU8 face 1!t b y a P air
f br0Wn °y eS is ambitious to be
a roat musician and practices
three h Urs a day< Edith is 8aid
ever since he started in a small
oil refinery with a capital of
$5,000.
Unlike the Rockefeller fortune
great fortunes of America and, of
course, the great fortunes of Europe,
represent the successive and suc
cessful labor of several generations.
The foundations of the Astor for
tune were laid "nearly one hundred
years ago, and when John Jacob
Astor built the Astor House some
thing less than sixty years ago he
was already a very wealthy* man.
The Vanderbilt fortune is thirty
five or forty years old and the
Rothschild fortune dates back to
the last century.
Although John D. Rockefeller
thus seems to be the richest man
in America he lives in a compar
atively modest fashion. He has
never built a palace on Fifth ave
nue, and his equippage is not of
that gorgeous character calculated
to attract attention on the street.
His New York house is at No. 4
West Fifty-fourth street, opposite
St. Luke's Hospital. The house is
surrounded by spacious grounds
and is handsomely furnished, but
there is no ostentatious or even
notable display of the evidences of
wealth. There are no servants in
livery; in fact, there are no men
servants whatever. The door is
opened by a maid in cap and
apron, and maid-servants wait on
the table. It has been repeatedly
remarked, by the way, that Mr.
Rockefeller looks like a preacher.
He is not a large or impressive
looking man, but has stooping
shoulders and solemn face. He is
is fact a deacon in the Baptist
church, and is probably the largest
contributor to the work and institu
tions. He and his family are not
occupying either their house in
New York or the house in Cleve
land. They are apt to go to Green
wich, Conn., or down to the sea
shore for a few weeks. Ailantic
City is frequently chosen.
John I). Rockefeller's immediate
family consists at present of his
wife and two unmarried daughters.
Edith, the elder, is twenty and
Alta is seventeen. Thoy are said
to have a quarterly allowance of
$500 each, and out of this tliey j
dress themselves and pay all their
incidental expenses. The eldest
to be determined to learn Japanese
and to go to that country as a mis
sionary. Presumably J the Rocke
fellers have a great many relatives
about whom nobody ever hears.
The wealth of John D. Rockefeller
will probably be divided up at his
death between the immediate mem
bers of his family and the Baptist
church.
There are two or three interest
ing facts about the marvellous
growth of the Standard Oil Com
pany that have never been put
together. The value of the first
refinery built by Rockefeller was
about $5,000, and this represented
the capital put in by Rockefeller
and Samuel Andrews. Andrews
had been a porter in a commission
house and Rockefeller had formed
his acquaintance while he was yet
a bookkeeper. When the opera
tions of the firm became so great
that the capital, increased by the
rapidly accumulating profits, was
still altogether inadequate, Henry
M. Flagler was taken into the firm
and a new firm created under the
name of Rockefeller, Andrews
Flagler. Flagler's father-in-law,
S. V. Harkness, put in $60,000.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1896-08-02/ed-1/?sp=13</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		FROM POVERTY TO
,^^TWO HUNDRED MILLIONS
CHAPTER I.
This is the story of America's wealth
iest man and greatest philanthropist. It
is the history of a man who, with al
most $200,000,000 at his command, gives
art-ay over $500,000 yearly in charity,
says tht New York Herald.
in short, it is the story of John D.
Rockefeller, the Standard Oil Midas,
Croesus, wizard, magician or magnate,
whichever you may choose to call him.
Thirty years ago he was a poor man.
With one uncertain foot on the bottom
rung of the ladder of fortune, he began
to mount with amazing speed toward
the top. He has amassed wealth at
the rate of six million dollars a year
for a period of thirty years. He now
iinds it difficult to keep track of his
property
Ami still the great sold ball rolls on,
accumulating- and increasing with the
years, becoming more colossal and
more formidable as the days pass, until
some day it may require an array of
men to look after it. John D. Rocke
feller does not earn money now as he
did in the old days when his brain was
taxed with the problem of how to make,
instead of how to keep.
Whether he sleeps or wakes, whether
in sickness or health, whether dreaming
away his tjme on his yacht or idling
the days away at one of his many
country homes, his income of $20,000
a day will continue. Should he sleep
for only a minute during an afternoon,
he wakes to the knowledge that he is
$14j-icher than a minute before. Should
he sleep for an hour, $833 roll into his
co#ers in a trickling stream. Every
morning when he opens his eyes he
finds himself $10,000 better off than on
the evening'previous; and this without
an effort other than a few hours' daily
scheming to render his wealth more se
cuce, and to further fasten the finan
cial rivets and cleats that hedge his
RoTfden granary. Yet he was born poor
and penniless, as far as inheritance is
concerned.
T'have said that thirty years ago
John D. Rockefeller was a poor man.
More than that, he was not only poor.
blif fven his best friends would not ac
cord him any credit for industry or
sagacity. He was a plain, plodding
bookkeeper— that is all. What John D.
Rockefeller does not know about his
own wealth would at pres3nt make rich
m«p of thT>se very frietvls. He prob
ably cannot guess within ten million
dollars of how much money he is worth,
without extensive figuring.
Jjahn D. Rockefeller is of Scotch par
entage. His parents came to this co.in
try shortly before the birth of the fu
ture great magnate. The family set
tled in the western part of this state
on -a smaH farm near Moravia. Here
the^ Rockefellers rapidly increased,
until the "family consisted of father,
mother, two sons and two daughters.
From Moravia the Rockefeller family
moved to a farm near Ow^o. At this
time, John D., the eldest son, was a
tall, slender lad, nine years old. The
farm house ocupied by the Rockefellers
at^this time- is still standing. It was
then and is still owned by Mr. G. M.
Lanioiitr,"a well-to-do farmer. It was
In his service that young Ro--:kef filer
°a«ned his first 25 cents, hoe
ing" potatoes. According to a statement
made afterward by Mr. Lanonte. the
boy did the work slowly, >ut well.
TJje two young Rockefeller boys
tvere always together, working on their
mvn little farm, or hunting, Railing and
'iid's nesting about the noun cry. They
iv,-ro not bad boys, as hoys «0,, but
iv ore in for all sorts of harmless mis
chief. And it was on account of this
propensity for harmless mischief that
John onee 'got into trouble w'uh his
mother.
TRIES TO EVADE A SWITCHING.
7?oth John, and William had a great
love and respect for their mother, but
their thoughtlessness was sometimes
the cause of disaster. One day, when
Mrs.' ■Rockefeller was sick, her son
Jolm committed some overt act in con
nectton with the cupboard or the sugar
bowl. He was promptly called in and
arraigned before the awful tribunal
of justice at Mrs. Rockefeller's bed-
Bidet
He acknowledged the corn. Then
he was sent out to procure a switch
f*>r his own punishment. This is an
awful trial for a boy. In his desire
to temper justice with mercy, John
brought in the frailest kind of a willow
affair, _. tha,t would not have hurt a
kitten. Thus early he displayed that
acumen for which he is now so well
known.
l'.ut the scheme did not work. Mrs.
Rockefeller sent William out to pro
cure another switch. William had no
BUCD compunctions. The switch he
In ought in was a peach. He cut it
from the tree in the back yard. It was
large, tough and serviceable. Job did
not take his punishment in unflinching
consciousness of wrong doing like the
grood little boy in the story book.
Oh, no! He howled like a Coman- j
che, just as another boy would have
done. He was a mercurial boy, how
ever, and soon forgot all about it. As
the boys grew up into tall, healthy
striplings, they began to earn more j
money from the surrounding farmers.
"With this transitory prosperity they
developed an astonishing fondness for
the circus, whenever it made a stay
in Owego. From being a desperate pi
rate, with an old threshing machine
for a rakish craft, young Rockefeller
was determined to become a circus j
tumbler or a trapeze performer. He I
concocted a spring board and utilized
all the straw in the neighborhood as a
cushion to preserve his bones.
During the Owego period of the
Rockefeller family's existence the
father was always away from home.
In truth there was some talk of do
mestic trouble, but nobody outside the
immediate family seemed to know
much about it. Mr. Rockefeller sent
money regularly from Cleveland for
his family, and they were fairly well
to do. He visited them occasionally,
but did not stay for any length of i
time.
Among the neighbors young John
Rockefeller had the reputation of be
ing a rather lazy boy, but even at this
early age he showed signs of the strong
■will, calm judgment and perseverance
that have since made him famous.
Who shall say that even while he was
hoeing potatoes or ploughing corn his
mind was not so active that his mus
cles performed their allotted tasks
lazily and mechanically?
Endowed with mental activity and
capacities that were perhaps still un
dreamed of by himself, young Rocke
feller began to long for a wider field
of action. It was only a dream as yet.
His ideas were acute, his character
unformed, his habits unstable and un
settled. "John is too much of a
dreamer," said the neighbors; "he will
never make a good farmer. While sow-
ing his wheat he will be counting upon
the profits of the coming harvest. He
will have it all in the market before
a blade is in sight."
The men who spoke in this wise are
still planting their corn and sowing
their wheat about Owego. Some have
prospered; others have failed and fall
en into poverty. But the boy who
dreamed of unharvested wheat and un
hatched eggs could buy all their farms
rolled into one for a double price, and
then allow the land to lie idle until
the end of time without inconvenienc
ing himself in the least.
REMOVES TO CLEVELAND.
The father of John D. Rockefeller is
said to be still living in Cleveland, al
though he has never occupied the same
house with any of his children. He
lived and labored in Cleveland while
his family were yet in Owego. One day,
many years ago, he suddenly made up
his mind that Cleveland was the beat
place for his family. At this time, John
D. and William Rockefeller were at
tending school at the Owego academy.
The neighbors in Owe^'D rejnrettPd the
departure of the Rockefellers for Cleve
land. Mrs. Rockefeller was a strong
character, well liked by all, and a strict
disciplinarian of the old s^hook Phe
brought the two boys up religousliy
and well, and when, after a six years'
residence in Owego, they started for
Cleveland, both John D. and William
were well behaved youngsters of four
teen or fifteen.
Instead of being ruined by the bustle,
turmoil and temptations of a large city,
the young Rockefellers thrived under
the new conditions. As for .."ihn, the
elder, it was the very thinrj for which
his soul had been yearning. It was a
realization of the dream that had
stricken his muscles with lassitude in
the old farming days.
Again the two youngsters were sent
to public school, where for a while thoy
had a rather hard time of it in amal
gamating their country ideas with
those of the city boys. They had quite
as many youthful disagreemnts as are
usual with boys of their ages, and came
out of them quite as well.
Three years later we find Master
John D. Rockefeller grown into a
strapping young man of seventeen. His
ambitions had outgrown the narrow
}trhvu 2 Ifax*fc2!UAs m
limits of a public school, and he made
up his mind to do and dare 'for him
self. He told his mother about it and
then went his way, looking for a job.
It was not an easy thing to find a po
sition that fitted him.
So it v.-as that young Rockefeller
wandered away to St. Louis. Was it
blind chance that led him to accept the
position of bookkeeper for a small
produce commission firm in Water
street? Nothing better could have
been devised for a thorough training
in busines methods. Neither did it
take Rockefeller any length of time to
master everything ther? was to be
known about the commission business.
He worked early and late on his books
and in the study of the methods of
his employers. He saved his money,
too, and herein lies the difference be
tween John D. Rockefeller and many
of his contemporaries who are still
keeping books In Cleveland.
Young Rockefeller worked with the
Water street commission firm until he
had accumulated something like $500.
He was then nineteen years old. Time
was flying, and its flight made him
restless. He asked himself why he
should not go into business for him
self. His only inheritance \n this world
had been brains and a good constitu
tion. With these he had acquired the
small capital with which he proposed
to do wondrous things In the future.
CHAPTER 11.
It was in 1857 when John D. Rockefel
ler, then a young man of nineteen,
met M. B. Clark, who is now a member
of the elevator firm of Gardner, Clark
York.
The two young men rented a store
and went into the commission business
on their own account. They succeeded
in a moderate way. Rockefeller con
tinued to save his share of the prof-
Its as he had saved his salary, and in
the eight years during which the part
nership continued he had put aside
something like $5,000.
Then the young man was again
stricken with a feeling of restlessness.
He was not making money fast
enough. The commission business had
apparently reached Its limit He
looked about him for an investment
in something more profitable. Dis
satisfaction is sometimes mere ambi
tion after all.
Some time before this Rockefeller
had become acquainted with Samuel
THE Sa£&^°?&Ui/ '&LOBE: SUNDAY, AUGUST 2, 1890.
Andrews, a porter in a commission
store further down the street. In th«
course of a conversation one evening
Andrews expressed his belief that there
was a great future in the petroleum
business. Rockefeller had always
thought so, but had never before ex
pressed an opinion. The conversation
with Andrews gave the decided touch
to Rockefeller's ideas. He consulted
with Clark, and together with Andrews
they built a little petroleum refinery
up the river a short distance from St.
Louis.
Rockefeller and Clark's investment
in this enterprise was $4,000. The firm
still hold onto their commission busi
ness, however. But the petroleum re
finery gave promise of a big business,
and Rockefeller determined to give his
entire attention to it. He tried to per
suade Clark to his way of thinking,
but the latter did not care to venture
into untrodden fields.
The firm was therefore dissolved,
Clark buying out Rockfeller's inter
est. Andrews, who had been superin
tending the refinery on a salary, had
saved a few hundred dollars, and
Rockefeller, knowing him to be a prac
tical man, took him in as partner.
Thus the Standard Oil company
came into being as a commercial en
terprise, one of its originators a book
keeper hardly more than a boy, the
other a porter in a commission house.
The bookkeeper is now president of
the company, while the porter lives in
a three hundred thousand dollar resi
dence.
At the time Clark withdrew from
the little refinery the entire property
could not have been worth much more
than $5,000. It was not much of a nest
egg, yet from this humble beginning
has grown the great Standard Oil
company, with its hundreds of offshoots
and its $70,000,000 of capital. So the lit
tle refinery kept pegging away, with
an ever increasing business and an
ever ambitious management.
In the meantime young William*,
Rockefeller, who had been working at
a salaried position in Cleveland, cam*'
to St. Louis and took a position in the
little oil refinery of Rockefeller An-"
drews. The investment continued to,
pay a handsome profit, and a year or
two after beginning business the firm
had a snug sum in the bank.
A year or two after Rockefeller and
Andrews had joined fortunes they in
conjunction with William Rockefeller,
established a second refinery, and the
money making business was greatly
Increased. The two establishments
were finally consolidated, and the
younger brother, William, was made a,
full fledged member of the firm. A
warehouse for the sale of refined petro
leum was opened in New York, and
William Rockefeller was placed in
charge of it. John D. was the business
head of the consolidated concern, while
Andrews looked after the machinery
and men.
There were no disagreements or
friction. The members of the firm were
very little more than boys, but they
were enthusiastic and ambitious to a
degree. In their lexicon, as they then
regarded it, there was no such word as
fail. They were confronted with
failure, however, shortly after the con
solidation. They had built and pur
chased and planned without regard to
their financial abilities, until finally
they found themselves in very deep
water. They had spent a great deal
of their little hoard in extending their
business, and were threatened with
ruin before they could get returns from
their investments.
Creditors harassed them, their funds
were exhausted and their business was
apparently ruined. "It's no use," said
Andrews. "I guess we are in for it. I
i do not see how we can tide the thing
over."
A PERIOD OF DESPONDENCY.
William Rockefeller was gloomily
desponded. One morning John D. ap
peared at the office of the refinery,
carrying a valise. "Where are you go-
Ing?" asked Andrews. "I am going to
get help," was the reply.
Where he could not tell. He had no
definite plan. But help must be had,
and, just as he had long before set out
to win a fortune, young John D. Rocke
feller took his grip and went forth to
obtain assistance in retaining the little
he had already accumulated. By luck,
instinct, good judgment, or what you
will, he met Mr. S. V. Harkness, a rich
whisky distiller, whose son-in-law,
Henry M. Flagler, was then doing bad
ly in the salt and lumber business near
Saginaw. Harkness Investigated Rocke
feller and the refinery business and
made up his mind that he would take
an interest In it for his son-in-law.
About a month after he had started
out on his still hunt for money Rocke
feller returned with Harkness' Michi
gan son-in-law and $60,000 with which
to continue the business. A new firm
was created, under the name of Rocke
feller, Andrews Flagler.
This was the pivotal point in the for-
Pcs of John D. Rockefeller, as well
of Henry M. Flagler. The money
of-Harkness and the methods of Flak
ier were just what the petroleum re
finery neefled. PrftvhsttfJ to the advent
of. the company had; been con
ducted In a semi-sentimental way."
John D. Ro©kefel|fer's heart had not yet
hardened intojjgranite In l|is business
dealings, although he was tbe princi
pal schemer lflssh<» Ifirm.
It was diffefernfc/ with Flagler. Al
though he hacr* bean far from auccesßr,
ful as a maker of salt and a sawyer'of
logs, he developed remarkable talents
when it came to petroleum. In deal
with opposing refiners he went as far
as the law wwuld permit. He argued
that there was nfeeling in trajfto Consequently when
he got his busUiesa enemy In a hole he
squeezed him
Under these new, tactics the firm of
Rockefeller, Andrews Flagler throve
apace. Their business was extended
amazingly, an&Mn a sort of geometrical
progression. In 1870 the flrm had be
come so imposing and their business
so immense that it jvas thought best to
incorporate under the style of "The
Standard Oil Company," with a cap
ital of $1,000,000. More consolidations
followed. They resembled the consoli
dation of the bird and the worm, but
they were within the limits of business
ethics.
During the days when he was a com
mission merchant John D. Rockefeller
had married a Cleveland school
teacher, Miss Lucy Spellman. The
union proved a very happy one, and at
the time of the incorporation of the
Standard Oil Company he had two lit
tle daughters, Bessie and Alta, who
have since become lovely young women.
Altogether the Standard Oil magnate
has had four children. The oldest
daughter, Bessie, is- the wife of Profes
sor Gfrarles Strong- J>wha occupies the
chair of Professor of Psychology in. the
Chicago imlverstty? "The yoirhgest of"
the four is John D., Jr., who is now 24
years of age. A year or two ago
Edith become the wife of one of the
McCormick boys, of Chicago.
Mrs-. Rockefeller is a slight little
woman, with grayish hair that was
once jet'black. Her life, has been de
voted almost exclusively to her hus
band, her children and her household.
She has never figured in f the society
columns of the newspapers or in great
social events. She tfas'been^ giving
money away in charity continually
since her marriage. The idea of one j
great concern that should control all
the petroleum in this country originate
"ed wTfH^^rilUn-^mg Roc3f£relfifer> Th<#«
Oil G&v&^y was already anj
immensely r ws3 [Bjf.lcorpQration
-ih-ia. -idea- \wisu Shortlj^after^
the company' ha ."bfgfun to 'swallow the
pmaiter -rtmeerri -V&fc 'Andrews*? thf or*§
iginal partner I tra business, became
..He. stiy,£gniaj sji'ifr the
the capacity oi sij^frintendent, while
Kcekefelte*VoE kii isiiind the rest of the
firm liad 'e'volu to speak, into
carpeted 'offices **3gk easy chairs. So
Andrews, aftei tj»king the matter;
over, offeTexr tl his interest. He
claimed ..teJ3,ea_ kh§ion. practical man,
while John«p. JpfcaMefeller considered
himself, v-ery-p fc^kfcriy, an uncommon
man. It is prob gfeTthat this was the
beginnrnr*of«wr iMifcle.
r "A: GOOD B aiK&SS SEAL.
-AX-Jiny rate,^ 9pS*s was 4-^ complaint
on Andrew's part, sfrkl, quick as a wink,
R«eteefe4l#*-aßke4 WiW how much money
he wanted for his" sliare. Andrews was
already a rich man. He grew somew4;at,
excited t and, grabbing a piece of paper,
wrote upon it, "One ffiflHon dollars,*
and Jaaaded it to Rockefeller. The lat
ter accepted the offer instantly
the transfer was made.
A few days later Rockefeller sold
the Andrews stock to W. H. Vander
bilt. for $1,250,000, thus clearing a mod
erate fortune on the transaction.
After the retirement of Andrews from
the Standard Oil company the "con
solidations" and extensions continued
without cessation, until practically all
the petroleum output, of this country
was under its control. Then it beg-in
to reach abroad for the control of the
Russian output. Although as yet it has j
pot secured lull control, it has sue- j
ceeded in underselling the Russians*
even in their own country. It seems to
be only a qu«stldn of time, however,
before the Standard will have the oil
markets of the entire world in its
hands.
It was when the Standard Oil com
pany began to be a concern of national
magTrttuiie that John D. Rockefeller
began to give away those magnificent
sums for charity that have made his
name a synonym for benevolence. They
have increased with his growing for
tune until at present his gifts to various
charaties range from $500,000 to $1,000,
--000 annually.
The Standard Oil company in one
sense has been only a bureau for the
distribution of the earnings of the com
panies unc er its control. It has paid, and
continues to pay£*t(et profits to its cer
tificate holders. F6r th»e past eight years
it has paid dividends at the rate of
twelve per qgn£. p^gspar. In, the earlier
years" the profits were not so large, but
they were substantial. IB it any wonder
that under the circumstances John D.
Rockefeller is thA-^i^hest man in the
United States? He once said before a
legislative investigating committee that
he did not knowllhSw rich he was by
several millions. jKp. other man ever
made money so iasff Although fhuch of
his income is derived from the oil busi
ness, his -outside 'tntferests "brrhg him
several millions a' year.
OTHER AMBITIOUS PROJECTS.
In the neighborhood of Puget Sound
there is a. lake 3 but little known to.:
Eastern people. It is called Lake
Washington. It is spring fed, and is
about twenty-five miles long, from
eight to ten miles wide and has a depth
of water sufficient to float the largest
steamships.
Mr. Rockefeller's scheme was to build
a belt line of railways around the lak?,
making connections with the" great
trunk lines running to the East. Next, I
in connection with Gen. Russell A.
Alger, he proposed to build a. canaV
tweive miles long, running from the
lake to the sea. It was to be"a ship
canal, capable of floating steamers en
gaged in the China trade, and was to
become a port of entry which wan to be
come the future metropolis of the coast
north of San Francisco.
Mr. Rockefeller is an iron kinpr as
well as an oil Croesus. He practically
owns all the Lake Superior iron mines,
as well as the principal iron mines of
Cuba. This places him in tho same
position toward the iron producing bus
iness as he has long held in regrird to
oil. To gain control of all these bead
mines has cost him something like
$10,000,000, but the great oil magnate
is a man of gigantic enterprises and
does not balk at a scheme Involving a
mere million or twoT
During the finan/jLil. depression a few j
years ago, when &ifc Jror mine owners
were cramped for money, Mr. Rocke
feller seized the opportunity to buy
everything in sight. He accumulated
all the stocks aridf of Southern
mines that he coirid* get hold of. When
the shares of the Minnesota Iron com
pany were placed on the market he
bought them in. large quantities,
enough in fact to control it. This com
pany owns the great mines at Tower
and Ely, Minn.; the Duluih and Iron
Range railroad, the big docks at Two
Harbors, and large areas of dock and
railroad property >ltf Duluth. It prac
tically held a monopoly of the iron
trade of the North- B
Mr. Rockefeller also has control of the
Mesaba mines in Northern Minnesota,
and Is virtually enabled to dictate the
price of iron. The makers of Bessemer
steel have found that they must have
ore from either Lake Superior or Cuba,
and that they have to pay just what"
price Mr. Rockefeller chooses to place
upon it.
As constituted a few years ago, there
were seven Standard oil companies in
corporated in the great oil trust. They
were in the states of "New York, Perm- I
sylvania, New Jersey, Ohio, Indiana,
lowa and Kentucky. The trust certifi
~eates nave never been dealt in on the
New York stock exchange, because ap
plication has never been made to put
them on its list. The only public
-transactions in them have been at the
auction sales of securities on the real
estate exchange. The last known sale
Was at $190 a share.
The certificates have been as high as
$225, which was before an increase in
Uiem was made to take in new proper
ties controlled by the trust.
When everything is taken into con
sideration, and all interests are figured
out and added up, the wealth of John
D. Rockefeller will be found to be about
aa follows:
Standard Oil stock $50 000 000
hi*? 35,000;000
Real estate 15,000,000
Lead trust 3.000,000
Iron mines m 15 000 000
Railroad «tocka and bonds. 26,'<)00'000
n«ll rB ga Btock 4,000,000
Bank Stock g nnn qqa
q^»m a^ Itur,td1 tur ,t d gas BtSteamship lines p nnn nnn
cLT-iTt" 11 state*.. .y:::::: l;Z:Z
00 hand 9 nnn nnn
iISZ
Tot 1 $179,000,000
CHAPTER 111.
John D. Rockefeller lives in a com
paratively modest fashion. When in
the city his home Is at No. 4 West
Fifty-fourth street, opposite St. Luke's
hospital. The house is surrounded by
beautiful grounds, and is substantially
furnished, but even the modest crit
ical observer can find nothing ostenta
tious or offensive to good taste through
out the place.
lJS 1 6 aylns that Mr Rockefeller
4 6 a preacher is in a measure
S™' it- 8 nOt a large or an impres
sive looking man, but has stooping
shoulders and a rather melanchol?
face. The family has a splendid resi
dence in Cleveland, and another in
Greenwich, Conn., but the favorite re
tiring spot of the magnate is his splen-
Sr CG^ ntry reslde *cc near Tarrytown
Mr. Rockefeller is said to be a fine
performer on the violin, and is always
one of the family musicians when music
is in order. There is also a fine pri
vate skating rink attached to the house
.and on winter evenings it is a favorite
resort for the entire family
Although Mr. Rockefeller gives a
piodigious amount every year to dif-
R-rent charitable objects, he generally
floes so through insitutions and organi
iV^nJ} is sald that ne P^ a sa l a ry
of $10,000 a year to the person who
looks after his charities and makes in
vestigations as to the worthiness of
the concerns he proposes to beneftt
Ncne.of the family is afflicted with ex
travagant habits, and, while they give
freely, it is seldom that their charitable
dellars find their way into the pockets
of unworthy persons. They never at
tend either the theatre or opera but
they have a box at Carnegie Music
hall, where they regularly attend the
l>amrosch concerts or those given by
Seidl or other eminent performers.
He was the principal donor for the
building of the new dormitory at Vas
sar College. It is named Strong Hall
in honor of Mr. Rockefeller's daughter'
Mrs. Strong-. His donations to the
American Baptist Education Society
have proved the salvation of that or
zanization.
In all educational history, however
the donations of Mr. Rockefeller to the
University of Chicago are without a I
parallel. Altogether they amount to the I
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040052/1902-04-25/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		THE GREATEST TEACHER OF THE NATION.
He is John D. Rockefeller.
Editorial from Hearst's Chicago American.
Mr. John D. Rockefeller reminds the world
of his existence at this moment by giving
5250,000 to Barnard College for Women and
by compelling or inducing others to give 250,
000 more.
It must be said for Mr. Rockefeller that what
he takes away through an ingenious display of
force and skill combined, he occasionally gives
back to the people very intelligently.
Mr. Rockefeller has given many millions to
the cause of education.
Whatever you may think of his way of get
ting the millions, you cannot deny him grati
tude for the motive and intelligence which
direct his gifts.
Mr. Rockefeller's money "does much for edu
cation. Mr. Rockefeller himself is a great
national educator.
If he gave a huudred millions a week to the
cause of education for a whole year, he could
not do as much in the long run for the people
of the United States as he is actually doing in
his daily business life.
He is teaching the power and importance of
industrial organization.
The American people before Rockefeller
arrived had very primitive ideas about han
dling a great industry.
Th ere were thousands of middle men mak
ing tlxir little profits and paying their em
ployes as little as possible.
Oil was dear. Rockefeller comes along,
wipes out the thousands of middle men, makes
them all work, as they should work, organizes
oil production, builds huge pipe lines.
He appropriates to himself a thousand mil
lion dollar? of the wealth that God has given
to the nation. But he makes oil cheap, and he
teaches a lesson in'itidustiial organization.
The railroads are simply the feeders, the car
riers, the messengers of industry. They
should be coutrolled. The people, however,
have no idea how to control the railroads.
But John D. Rockefeller knows how to con
trol the railroads.
The people owning the nation and owning
the railroads ought to establish their own rates
on the railroads. They don't know how to do'
this.
But John D. Rockefeller knows how to .es
tablish his own rates on the railroads
Rockefeller does not go, hat in hand, to the
railroad managers, as does the average poor
farmer or manufacturer, asking, "Will you
kindl) carry my goods, and how much will
you charge?"
Rockefeller sends for the railroad manager.
Hk arrives with his hat in his hand. Rocke
feller says to the railroad manager:'
"I will allow you to carry so mucn freight
for me on such and such conditions, and I will
pay you so much. That's all. Go away."
The manager goes away and does as he is
told, obeying all orders, including the order
not to carry anybody else's oil in opposition to
Rockefeller.
The people of the United States elect, and
they ought to control, their representatives in
congress and in the various state legislatures.
They don't know how to control these law
makers. But Rockefeller knows how to control the
people's representatives.
He defeats them when they come up for re
election if they oppose his will. He never
forgets to reward them if they serve him
faithfully. He never ceases to hound them .if
they attack his interests. In that, he teaches
a sp'endid lesson to the people. They might
just as well coatiol their representatives as
Rockefeller does defeating the unfaithful and
rewardiug the faithful but they don't know
enough. Rockefeller is teaching them.
We are grateful to-day to the reckless pirates
whose courage gave the first great start to nav
igation The merchant dealing honestly travels in the
wake of pirate craft that were first to risk
the open sea. The intelligent merchant whose
ships sail safely to-day is grateful to those old
pioneer pirates.
The people of the future will be grateful to
John D. Rockefeller, the bold, original, capable
and useful pioneer pirate of industry.
He organized a great industry for himself.
He controlled railroads for himself.
He controlled legislatures for himself..
But, consciously or unconsciously, he is
teaching the people of the world how to do all
these things for themselves.
Thes rict duty of the people and of newspa
pers is to watch Mr. Rockefeller and control
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064384/1903-05-02/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		HISTORY OF A FORTUNE,
JOHN D. ROCKEFELLER TO BE A
EiLLIONAiRc.
Million cn Million Delng Piled Up In
Profits From Oil, Railroad and Bank
■—When the Standard Oil King Al
most Went Broke—His Destiny.
Dnvld Graham Phillips writes as fol
lows in the Philadelphia Saturday
Evening Post:
Among the great fortunes of (he
Xvorld today there are two that tower
colossal—-the Rothseshild and the
Rockefeller. No one—not even the
heads of the two houses—knows just
how large these fortunes are. A few
years ago John D. Rockefeller said up
on the witness stand that he was un
able to tell how much he was worth
within several millions. Indeed, there
is no way of estimating accurately
these modern fortunes, invested in
many ways and subject to daily, hourly
fluctuations. Probably a billion and
a half of dollars is as near to accur
acy as it is possible to come in state
Ing the wealth of the house of Roths
child. As for the house of Rockefeller,
a business associate of the elder and
many times the richer of the two broth
ers said within a year: ''John D. Rocke
feller is worth not far from three
quarters of a billion, and he will pres
ently lie the first billionaire the world
has ever had. "If the estimate were
based upon income—certainly as fair
a way as to attempt to value capital
John D. Rockefeller would today be
classed as a billionaire half on the
way toward his second billion. And
there are in addition the several hund
red millions of his brother's fortune,
and the many mUlions of the three or
four allied members of the family.
The Rockefeller fortune was founded
upon credit capital. In 1375 John D.
Rockefeller was a considerable oil
merchant. But his schemes for mon
opolizing the oil business of half the
world were trembling between success
and failure. In that year there were
three weeks when he walked the floor
night after night, sleepless, fighting
the ruin that seemed to be closing in
around him. It is said that his wife
exclaimed: "I wish John would go
bankrupt, for then he would get some
sleep." It is said that the nervous in
digestion which now compels him to
the quietest of lives and to a diet of
crackers and milk at 98 2-5 degrees
Fahrenheit dates from that terrible
three weeks. He owed the banks -of
Cleveland 11,700,000. He could not pay;
they were pressing him, but did not
dare to close In upon him. They knew
that if he failed it would swamp them
and would precipitate a panic in
Cleveland—Cleveland was not so large
and rich in those days, and $1,700,000
was a big sum of money, even in Wall
street.
The Rockefeller fortune may there
fore be dated from 1875, the year when
the founding crisis was passed, though
the big returns did not begin to come
until about 1885, the enormous returns
until less than ten years ago.
From 1860 to 1875 Rockefeller was
reaching out and out to take posses
sion of his promised land. brother,
and their intimate friends^nighed at
him, tried to dissuade him, warned
him. They, too, would buy oil wells,
but they would make what they could
and sell out before the well caught fire
or ran dry. He bought to keep, bought
burning wells and extinguished the
fires, bought dry wells in the hope that
they would some. day yield to the
pump. And when his brother and their
intimates saw that there was method
in his madness, he invited them in,
practically gave them as a present
the shares that were to make them
multi-millionaires. And, slow and 'te
nacious and saturated with his "mys
tic" of manifest destiny, he marched
on to the Montenotte of 1875. The
reaching out on small capital, the ris
ing clamor and fury against his merci
less methods of monopoly, brought on
that crisis.
Until the secret history of the Stand
ard Oil company is written, and it
probably never will be—no one ex
cept John D. Rockefeller will know
how that crisis was passed and how
prosperity and power were obtained
through these contracts with the rail
ways which made competition with
Rockefeller hopeless and forced al
most all the oil men, producers, re
finers and sellers, to choose between
submission and ruin.
Another point in tho development
of the great American fortune Is con
trol of railways—the arteries of the
whole people. It is next in importance
to a monopoly of some natural prod
uct. Rockefeller scored both points.
It w T as about 1884 that some of the
high-priced counsel discovered a way
of freeing him from the bondage of
anti-monopoly law, a method of re
organizing him into legality and safe
ty. Soon tho period of insecurity
passed—though the general public did
not know it and the press and tho
politicians were still howling. Rocke
feller was able to shake off his pur
suers and dismiss his horde of law
yer«. He had at lari a large, secure
income.
And now began the rapid increase.
He was a simple, thrifty man, and so
was his brother. They spent com
paratively nothing of their income, I
I
They reinvested it in obtaining com
plete ownership of what they had only
controlled—that is. of the petroleum
industry. They developed the Stand
ard Oil company from the single con
cern to a conglomerate of about 60
corporations, each engaged in a sepa
rate department of the industry. They
utilized the crude oil in a thousand
ways, turning to account the discover
ies of science which the scientists
gave freely to the world. Soon, so
many and so valuable were the by
prcducts of oil production that the
eil itself cost the Rockefellers practi
cally nothing at all—for the by-prod
ucts more and more paid for its pump
ing, refining, transportation and sale.
For 15 years, Mr. Rockefeller and his
group have been selling about a thou
sand million gallons of oil a year at
prices ranging from 5 to 20 cents a
gallon, and averaging about 7 cents;
and, as the by-products have increased
in number and in value, they have
put into their pockets as clear profit
more and more of the entire selling
price of the oil. Today that selling
price is estimated to be all clear pro
fit, and it is said that there is in addi
tion a profit of from $10,00,000 to $20,
OOO.noO upon the by-products. This
explains why tho profits of the Rocke
fellers from their trust are greater by
many millions annually than the val
ue of tho petroleum production.
About 10 years ago Rockofoiler's in
come was given as $30,000,000 by an
excellent, authority. He had reached
the limit of profitable reinvestment
of profits in the oil industry. Here
then wore those enormous sums i*
cash pouring in—more than $2,000,000
a month for John Davison Rockefeller
alone. The problem of reinvestment
became more than serious. It became
a nightmare. The oil income was
swelling, and, the number of sound in
vestments is limited, was then even
more limited than it now Is. It was
through no especial eagerness for more
gains that the Rockefellers began to
branch out from oil into other things.
The first conspicuous excursion and
incursion of tho Rockefellers was into
I ho railway field. By 1895 they con
trolled one-fifih of the railway mile
ago of the country. What do they
own or, through dominant ownership,
control today? They are powerful in
all the great railways of New York,
north, east and west, except one
where their share 13 only a few mil
lions. They are in most of the great
railways radiating from Chicago. They
dominate in several of the systems
(hat extend to the Pacific. It is their
votes that make Mr. Morgan so potent
—though, it may be added, they need
his brains more than ho needä their
votes—at present, and the combination
of the two constitutes in large meas
ure tho "community of interest."
But railways could not alone absorb
rapidly enough those mighty floods of
gold; presently John D. Rockefeller's
$2,500,000 monthly had increased to
four, to five, to six millions a month,
to $75,000,000 a year. Illuminating oil
wag becoming all profit; the reinvest
ments of Income were adding their
mite of many annual millions.
The Rockefellers went into gas and
electricity when those Industries had
developed to the safe-investment
stage. And now a large part of the
American people must beg^n to enrich
the Rockefellers as soon as the sun
goes down, no matter what form of
illuminant they use.
The latest industry into which tho
Rockefellers have gone is banking.
There they already dominate, and
there they think they have found the
solution of their investment problem—
for a few years, at least. And It is
within the possibilities that the Rocke
feller banking adventure may cause
a convulsion—a greater convulsion,
perhaps, than that which shook the
country when John D. Rockefeller first
introduced the industrial monoply to
the American people jind began to
force Its acquaintance and society
upon them.
The Rockefeller bank—the National
City bank—is by herself far and away
the biggest bank in the United States.
It is exceeded in the world only by
tho Bank of England and the Bank of
France. The deposits average more
than $100,000,000 a day; and it domi
nates the call loan market on Wall
street and the stock market. But it is
not alone; it is the head of the Rocke
feller chain of bank's, which includes
14 banks and trust companies In New
York City, and hanks of groat strength
and influence in every large money
centre in the country.
The chief business cf these banks is
to receive the Rockefeller income and
lean it to speculators, manufacturers,
merchants and farmers throughout
ihe country. And the Rockefellers not
only are relieved from much of their
former anxiety over investments, but
also receive a double profit. There is
the profit of the interest which the
banks pay them for their huge cash
balances 50 and 75 and even of a 100
millions steadily maintained from day
!o day theso largest private handlers
of cash the world has ever seen; then
there are all profits of dividends which
the banks declare—and large dividends
they are.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033781/1905-03-03/ed-1/?sp=2</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		STANDARD OIL TRUST
COME TO JUDGMENT
GIGANTIC STRUGGLE WHICH HAS BEEN
BEGUN AGAINST THE GREATEST
OF ALL COMBINES.
THE FIHS GUN
Government Orders an Investigation Which Will Lay
Btxre the Methods of the Oil" Octopus John
D, Rockefeller ond the Pixrt He PIolVs
in the Game-In Fifty Yevrs
He Has Become the World's
Greatest Potentate,
John D. Rockefeller has been laugh
ing up his sleeve and serenely waiting.
It has amused him to read in the pa
pers that the Kansas legislature had
appropriated $4lu.(no for the estab
lishment of a state refinery to buck
against his JjyO.oou.noo company. He
has been annoyed, perhaps, at the ef
fort to meddle with his pipe lines, but
he has felt confident that the end
would come in victory for him and the
establishment of his company in the
state on firmer basis than ever before.
He has mapped out a campaign of
waiting. This great financier, this
$r.r,,.o0,0o0 money bags, can afford to
wait, for his dollars work while he
sleeps, and he can keep busy banking
the $."0.000.000 yearly income from his
Investments while the jxor Kansans
tee their $110,000 refinery a sink hole
Into which to pour the wealth of the
state and the independent producers
there brought to a state of sub
mission where they will be willing to
make peace at Rockefeller's own
terms, and if reports are to be credited
Rockefeller's terms are never generous
except to tho interests of Rockefeller
fclmself. Ho 13 never atisfied, it is
FIRED IN KANSAS
said, unless he can buy at ruinously
luw prices and sell at figures which
tell the story of a lair prolit of
several hundred per cent.
We speak of the Standard Oil com
pany and we think of the man who Is
the brains and sinew, yes, and money,
too, of the gigantic corporation John
D. Rockefeller, who began 50 years
ago with nothing and to-day counts
his wealth in the hundreds of millions.
He Is by all odds the richest man in
the world. How did he get within
his grasp all this wealth? What of
the man and what of his methods?
In discussing Rockefeller and his
millions in a recent issue of the New
York World. Karl Mayo dec lares that
nothing in the career of this man has
been accidental except the place of his
birth, which occurred at Richland. N. Y.,
in IS.'il). and about which presumably he
had nothing to vay. The means by
which he rose to wealth was the com
bination of an idea with an opportunity.
Oil happened to be the opportunity, but
if the marvelous richness of the oil fields
never had been discovered' the .idea
would have been applied to some other
business and Rockefeller still would
have been one of the country's richest
men.
We think of trusts as a development
of th last ten or twenty yenrs. but
Rockefeller long before this, yea. 20
years prior, grasped the idea and blazed
the way for the other trusts that have
followed in the train of the Standard.
The control of industry, elimination of
competition, community of interest, reg
ulation of output, consolidation under
a single control, all were a part of his
plan. He led the Standard Oil to Its
present eminence over a rocky road
which has since become smoot h by much
traveling. What was exceptional and
unheard of then has become ordinary
and matter of fact.
Mr. Rockefeller does believe in th
industrial system which he represents
and which he has (lone so much to fur
ther. His commercial creed is founded
upon the theory of'the survival of the
fittest.
"We are better able to run your busi
ness than you are. We will pay you a
fair price for it and will conduct It our
selves, but we will provide for you
by paying you a salary to manage it (or
to do whatever work you are best fit
ted for), and you will thus have a cer
tainty to depend upon Instead of the
uncertainty and the possibility of losing
your entire business which exists under
the competitive system. Therefore, you
will be better off than before. We will
be better off because wo can m ike more
money on a smaller margin of profit
if we handle all tho business. The
public will be better off because, through
the economies of management on a large
scale, it can secure its necessities at a
lower or at least at a more regular price
than before.
"The fact that we make big fortunes
for ourselves by this process is not un
just, for we have demonstrated that we
are more capable than the rqst of you
by getting control of the business.
Therefore wo are entitled to a gi eater
reward, but we feel it our duty to help
you by applying a part of our wealth
to objects that will bo for tho public
Ngood."
This Is the argument that John D.
Rockefeller used in conversation with
his friends at the very time when ho
was securing control of the oil refin
ing business and which he has repeated
since. It is expressed more baldly hero
and with more self-assurance, but thH
is what it amounts to. In an industrial
community ordered by Rockefeller the
shrewdest Intellects would control and
as a corrollary It would follow that their
control would bo for the general good.
As has been expressed In happy phrase
It Is a system of benevolent industrial
feudalism.
Standard Oil Interests $250,000,000.
While anything like an exact com
putation of John If. Rockefeller's wealth
is Impossible, there Is obtainable so tin
data that give interesting glimpses of
its staggering total. Some seven or
eight years ago one of the Standard Oil
leaders. In speaking of the fortunes of
some of the men most prominently
Identified with that company, was
quoted as expressing the opinion that
John I). Rockefeller's share of this
great aggregation of wealth was then
$150,000,000 and that his income from It
was from $12,000,000 to $15,000,000.
This statement had reference of
course only to that part of Mr. Rockefel
ler's wealth derived from his oil Inter
ests or represented by his holdings In
the Standard Oil company and the nu
merous subsidiary companies engage
In the distribution of oil or in the utili zation
of its many by-products. It was
made, too, before the great Increase in
prices which in the past half dozen years
has added probably one-third to tho mar-
flip
JOHN D. ROCKEFELLER.
!.et value of these holdings. At a con
servative estimate, therefore, this
branch of Mr. Rockefeller's fortune,' In
cluding the Increase yielded by his In
come during the Intervening period,
nust represent not less than $250.
000,000. It is pretty well authenticated, how
ever, that for the past decade Mr. Rocke
feller's yearly Income has been steadi
ly rising from $30,000,000 at the begin
ning of the period to a point at least
two-thirds greater than that at the
present time, and that, during the pre
ceding ten years, it grew from $10,000,000
to $30,000,000.
Lives the Simple, Frugal Life.
Mr. Rockefeller and his family are
modest In habit and expenditure. They
are perhaps the most notable devotees
of the simple life among our multi
millionaires. If we assume that $2. 0mm..
ni'O were expended every year in living
mh1 in charity, it will be seen that th
nrtural growth of this income withorr
courting its compounding power
throu h Invr-t rvr rts must haxer'1.1""
nearly $::mumhU!0o to theotal. Rut this
vast sum has not been allowed to ac
cumulate in vaults and strong boxes
Practically every dollar of it has been
invested where it hns enrned other dol
lars. Many of them, directed by tho
i:een trading instlvet of their owner
b'vf multiplied themselves threefold
within the past dozen years. One of the
-nnbives of aggregated wealth is thrt
:t enables its prssrsrr In times of
nv.r or depression to purchase vohnl lo
''?,rrt jfs cheaply nd by the s'rirle
-"fPss of holding then until letter
,!mes to renlie a multiplied return on
he jnvestmeut.
Thre-FoJd Profit in Iron.
Mr. Rockefeller Ins done this in p-anv
'Mo,anceg. A notable case v. as that of
'lis iron ore properties. During the do
rrssion of he bought, rheanlv for
"sh. the ore lards of Lake Superior rd
hn Minnesota mi its. He Improved the
iiing en'iiomnt built grent docks ant1
'nvested In h"'Te rrn carriers on the
T"at lVes. When the era of hi--'i
Hops "inie alone or the pros per :t."
wa'-e 1D00 and the T'rfled States Steel
''rporation was c-r-rled Mr. Rnr.-p-''llrr
sold out. Tfcp 2r,.or,0.000 which
Tt Ro'Vofel'er b one form orar-
'rr of steel hcViirs may be said to
v resent p Inter-:! e:'tirf'V profits rn h
estTr.en.t of dM-ni ears ago. It
"derstnod tha 1" "-'-'it'on to his lnte--'ss
in the r-!?"'i S?tfs Ftei crron.
'on hr,,"e,'er poS 'rrv larire hop!
J1" In the f.nei-vnma Steel (c,n- v
Vn he H n r"""pe-d factrr l" th
"""irs of the fW-rido Fuel and inn
Verv rMich the st me story as hh
rof.table in-eytnieif jn iron-ore lam s
'o:ild be told of h's eonrppflon with the
'"'id and zinc mines which were trai s
"erred to the trust at a profit that ran
into millions.
In the discussion about the affairs of
the Amalgamated rnpper company th
:ame of Rockefeller has been mentioned
frequently, but it has been explicitly de
rbd by the legal representatives of
standard Oil that John I). Rockefeller
ha any interest in this company, in
which his brother, William, and his
close associate. If. H. Rogers, have bee'i
the leading spirits. This statement a
accepted at its face value in Wall street,
where it is known that John I). Rocke
feller has heavy investments in a much
more profitable company, the Amcrica'n
Smelting and Refining.
Other industrial companies in which
he is largely concerned aro the Ameri
can Linseed Oil company, two of the big
express companies, the sugar trust and
the various organizations known collec
tively ks the to bp ''."j trust.
Not a Railway Han, But
John I). Rockefeller is not known as
a railway man. While there are Van
derbilt, Hill, Morgan and Harrlman
systems, there is no combination of
roads known as tho Rockefeller system.
Nevertheless Mr. Rockefeller Is the larg
est Individual holder of railroad securi
ties in the country. He is heavily inter
ested In tho Gould roads Missouri Pa
cific, Missouri, Kansas Texas, Texas
Tadfic and Wabash and It is through
Lis backing and assistance that George
I
i
Gould has been able to fight his way I
successfully against the powerful com-,
bination of railway interests In bringing j
his lines eastward toward the Atlantic t
seaboard. Rut in addition to this he Is
a heavy holder of the stocks and bonds,
more particularly the bonds, of almost
every one of the big eastern lines, as
well as of Northern Securities and of
half a dozen of the big roads running
out of Chicago. Probably not less than
$30,000,000 of his wealth Is Invested In
railways. And It should be borne In j
mind that practically all these holdings
were bought when their market rating
was much less than It Is to-day. i
The solidity and power that come from
the backing of unlimited millions are
valuable assets for a bank or trust com
pany. A number of the most Important
of these Institutions in New York and
other cities have prospered through the
magic of connection with the Rocke
feller name. Certain of these, like the
National City and Hanover banks, of
New York, the First national of Chi
cago and the two largest banks in Cleve
land, are known as Rockefeller institu- t
Hons.
The Country's Richest Banker. j
These are by no means the measure
of Mr. Rockefeller's banking interests.
A well-informed Wall street financier
showed me a list recently of f0 banks
and trust companies, all of which aro
reputed to be more or less under the
Rockefeller influence. If John I). Rock-,
efeller had nothing but his bank hold
ings he would be known as the coun
try's richest banker and would have a
fortune equaled ny lew in the United
States.
Oil, steel, railroads, banks and trust
companies have not been equal to the
task of providing occupation sufficient
for all the fast-multiplying Rockefeller
millions. Within the past ten years
especially a great many of them have
gone Into a particularly lucrative form
of investment city lighting and trac
tion companies. Whether $10,000,000 or
$25,000,000 more nearly represents John
D. Rockefeller's investments of this sort
in and about New York it is impossible
to say, but the amount is likely to bo
near the latter figure, while he has other
50.000000 YEARLY. 12 000.000 YEARLY 4.00(10M.rEARLY 3650.000 YR 2ltf00Q N? ft2000.OOO.TK
BAREFOOTED BOY CLERK THE
large sums similarly invested in New
England and the central west.
Two important items of John D.
Rockefeller's fortune are frequently
overlooked in making computations of
his wealth. These are his holdings of
real estate and mortgages and of gov
ernment and municipal bonds. Roth are
so vast that if we undertook to follow
out the threadc that lead to them they
would take us to every part of the Unit
ed States and across the Atlantic.
While Mr. Rockefeller's real estate
holdings would amount to probably
$10,000,000, such investment does not
prove a very attractive venture for the
astute financier. He prefers to let the
other fellow own tho real estate and he
hold the mortgage. The city of Cleve
land is an example of this. He owns
valuable property there Forest Hills
and his Tarrytown (N. Y.) estate is
truly baronial in its magnificent propor
tions, but these are nothing In com
parison to his mortgage holdings. In
Cleveland he holds a $100,000 mortgage
on the principal hotel, a mortgage for
a like amount on a large wholesale busi- i
ness. and banking and street railway
holdings which would bring the total to
fl5.0oo.oon in the Ohio city alone.
Rut Cleveland is rot the only city In
the United States that is doing a good
part of its business on John I). Rocke-
feller's money and paying him well for j
the privilege. New York. Chicago, Pitts
burg and Ruffah.r. re rases in point. j
Will Be World's First Billionaire.
Of Mr. Rockefeller's holdings In gov
ernment and municipal bonds It were
Idle to speculate. His beneficent atten
tions have been bestowed on other fields,
too. that are not Included in any of the
above classifications, such as that of
the big Insurance companies, steamship
and telegraph and building corporations
and other things, as the department
store advertisements say, too numerous
to mention.
Taking into account all these wide-
spread Interests, it Is not difficult to
figure out that John 1). Rockefeller la
ilready possessed of upward of $050,
300,000, or that, with the power which,
his vast wealth gives him of buying
cheaply when prices are at rock bot
tom and when financial stress compels
the holders of particular properties to
let them go, he will become a full
fledged billionaire within another ten
rears, if he lives so long. Indeed, the
accumulation of his yearly income of
$'i0.000,000. or thereabouts, will carry
him to that point without any allowance
for the appreciation of the properties in
which his money is Invested such as is
certain to occur.
If one were to construct a table show
ing chronologically the growth of Mr.
Rockefeller's fortune It would read about
as follows:
is:,:,
isor $3,000
1S70 C0.000
1 75 5.000.000
l V" 1 oo.ooo.ooo
1 SD0 200.000. Of i0
1 900 4 00.000,000
1 90." 550,000,000
The World's Greatest Potentate.
From the purely financial point of
view, however, Mr. Rockefeller is easily
the world'sgreatest potentate. The
czar of Russia enjoys an annual income
of about $12,000,000; Emperor William,
as king of Prussia, receives a little less
than $1,000,000; the emperor of Austria
Hungary, $3,875,000; King Edward. $2.
225.000, and the king of Spain. $2,000,000.
In the expressive phrase of Wall street.
King John, as emperor of oil, king of
steel, banking and railroads, and
prince of several lesser dominions,
could buy and sell them all. If he had
to earn his present wealth at the rate
of two dollars a day. which many of his
employes receive, it would take him
something more than 80,000 years to
accomplish the task, or considerably
longer than we have any record of in
human history. It is not merely the
number of John I). Rockefeller's mil
lions, astounding as Is their total, tha
Is most impressive. It is the power
which they convey. By reason of his
WORLD'S GREATEST POTENTATE.
ability to reward and punish, to maka
and unmake values, to bestow riches or
ruin, he is almost absolute master not
only of those enterprises in which he
holds a major monetary interest, but In
all those to which he cares tcS turn his
attention in any way. The enterprises
in which he holds investments aggre
gate a capitalization of over $5,000,
000.000. Though he owns outright but a
tenth of this, he can sway the destinic3
of every company involved if he so de
sires. Certainly the world never has seen
such a fortune as this, accumulated In
50 years by the efforts of one man who
has possessed no advantage, except such
as he was able to impose through the
cunning of his brain over any one of
50.000,000 of his fellows, but who never
theless has levied tribute notonly on his
countrymen but. on residents of the re
moteness of China, India and Africa who
never have heard and never will hear
his name, who has worsted opponents
of business resorrces as vast and busi
ness consciences ns elastic as his own,
and who holds to-day the greatest Indus
tries and most powerful financial Insti
tutions In the country In tee hollow of
his hand, the unre.sk-4!: subjects of his
will.
Telling Time by the Scales.
"I happened to be in a butcher shop up
in Harlem the other afternoon," said
Mr. Edward Morgan, the assistant post
master of New York, "when In came a
woman of ample proportions and unmis
takable Hibernian extraction. The
scales were the old-fashioned kind, with
a round brass dial, on which a pointer
swung around to indicate the pounds.
"After she had waited some time her
eye happened to light on that dial, and
she Jumped like a deer as she almost
shouted:
'For the love o' Hlven, give me that
mate, quick. It's 5ix o'clock.' N. Y.
Herald.
0
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042242/1905-07-01/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		JOHN D. ROCKEFELLER'S
$10,000,000 GIFT
ANNOUNCEMENT MADE OF A GIFT
OF TEN MILLIONS BY JOHN
D. ROCKEFELLER.
INTIMATED DONOR WILL MAKE
LARGE ADDITIONS TO IT IN
FUTURE YEARS.
New Yortc, July 1.—Ten million
Collars as an endowment for higher
education in the United States has
been given the general education
board by John D. Rockefeller. The
announcement was made by Dr. Wal­
lace Bufetrick of the board at a meet­
ing during the day. The following
letter to the secretaries and executive
officers of the board from F. T. Gates,
Mr. Rockefeller's representative, was
given out:
"I am authorized by Mr. John D.
Rockefeller to say that he will con­
tribute to the general education board
the sum of $10,000,000 to be paid Oct.
1 next in cash, or, at his option, in­
come producing securities, at their
market value, the principal to be held
in perpetuity as a foundation for edu­
cation, the income, above expenses
and administration, to be distributed
to or used for the benefit of such in­
stitutions of learning, at such times, in
such amounts, for such purposes and
under such conditions, or employed in
such other ways, as the board may
deem best adapted to promote a com­
prehensive system of higher education
In the United States."
With the letter the following state­
ment was given out:
"John D. Rockefeller, Jr., with
other gentlemen of this city, was in­
strumental in forming the general
education board in February, 1902. A
very bread and admirable charter was
secured from congress and signed by
President Roosevelt on Jan. 12,1903.
Explanation of th« Gift.
"A gift of $1,000,000 from Mr. John
D. Rockefeller was immediately
passed over to the board, especially
designated for educational work in the
South. Other funds have been added
by other philanthropists since that
time and the bdard has confined its
work hitherto mainly to educational
work in the Southern states.
"The present gift differs from Mr.
Rockefeller's first gift to the board In
the following particulars:
"The principal sum ef the gift of
11,000,000 made on the organization
of the board could be distributed. The
present gift of $10,000,000 is held as
endowment, the Income annually be­
ing available for distribution.
"The first gift was designed to be
used exclusively in the Southern
states. The present gift is for use not
only in the Southern states but
throughout the United States without
distinction of section.
"The first gift could be used for
common schools and secondary edu­
cation. The second gift is confined to
higher education and is designed spe­
cially for colleges as distinguished
from the great universities, although
there Is no prohibition in the letter of
gift against making contributions to
universities.
"It Is known #at Mr. Rockefeller
has had this gift in contemplation for
a long time and Mr. Gates has beet*
studying the subject in his behalf for
many months. If the fund proves to
be is useful as is now anticipated Mr.
Rockefeller will undoubtedly make
large additions to It In future years."
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86072041/1909-04-06/ed-1/?sp=4</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		GIGANTIC FIGHT
COMING 10 ENS
FINAL ARGUMENTS IN EFFORTS
OF GOVERNMENT TO DISSOLVE
THE STANDARD OIL TRUST AT
ST. LOUIS.
St. Louis, April 6. —Before the four
Judges of the United States Circuit
Court for the Eighth Judicial Circuit
the final chapter in the government's
three-year war to disrupt the Stand
ard Oil Company was begun today.
For ten days or two weeks attorneys
for the government and for the Stand
ard Oil company and its 109 co-defen
dants will make final argument on the
evidence already collected at hearings
held in many of the important cities
of the United States and before which
some of the most prominent financiers
of America weTe called.
John D. Rockefeller was not pres
ent at the hearing today. Instead he
and Archbold and other leaders in the
oil industry will be referred to only as
page so and so of the volumes of
printed evidence that have been laid
before the judges.
Under'the procedure of the Circuit
Court only that evidence can be pre
sented which has already been gath
ered and printed. Instead of living
men telling the story of the growth
of the octopus, a dray load of calf
bound volumes will furnish the facts.
After the attorneys have explain
ed the importance and significance
of the replies of Mr. Rogers as to
rate so and so granted to such an
oil company, their honors, the judges
will decorously withdraw from the
court room and by a process about
as exhilirating as reading the en
cyclopedia decide whether or not the
Standard has for two score years
violated the laws of the country.
The umpires who will decide the
case are Judges Walter H. Sanborn,
Willis Van Devanter, William C.
Hook and Elmer B. Adams.
The government forces today were
marshalled by Frank B. Kellogg, of
ficial trust buster. He is one of the
few men who has been connected
with the case all through Its cir
cuitous course. Charles B. Morrison
of Chicago was his chief assistant.
Mortiz Rosenthal and John S. Mil
ler, who shattered the Landis twenty
nine million bubble fine, appeared for
the Standard. There were a half doz
en others seated behind the breast
work of law books stacked on the
counsel table.
For two months the attorneys have
been pouring over the evidence and
mapping out their arguments.
There are nineteen volumes of evi
dence. Each judge and each attor
ney received a complete set. There
are 25,000 pages of questions and
answers. In addition there are 1,500
exhibits. The arguments will be
typewritten and sent to the judges.
It is estimated that by rapid work
they could read through this mass of
material in about two months. No
decision in the case is expected for
at least six months.
From this decision either side has
the right of appeal direct to the su
preme court of the United States.
There the case has precedence and a
final review might be had within a
year and a half.
The evidence was gathered by Spe
cial Examiner Franklin Ferriss, of
St. Lewis. He was apjpointed exam
iner in June. 1907, and began hear
ing evidence September 3, 1907, and
continued from time to time until
January 22, 1909. Since then the
evidence has been transcribed and in
th bands of th printer.
Hearings were held in New York,
Chicago, Albany. Cleveland and St.
Louis. In all there were 444 sepa
rate hearings.
The hearings that attracted the
most attention were held in New
York a few months ago. At these
John D. Rockefeller. John D. Arch
bold. Henry H. Rogers and other
Wall street leaders were present.
Curiosity was so great when Rocke
feller himself was on the stand that
Examiner Ferriss had to have three
policemen in the court room to help
keep order.
Aside from the rather lucid stories
told by the men who have been con
nected with the Standard since its
inception, the evidence was almost
wholly technical and had to do with
rebatps. tariffs, absorptions, cost of
raw material and kindred subjects.
Yet in all the 444 hearings there
was not a question asked that was
not intended to show either the truth
or falsity of the allegations of the
government's complaint.
This document was filed at the in
stance of Attorney General William
C. Moody November 15, 1906, and is
not the least interesting one pertain
ing to ihe case. The complaint itself
covers 194 printed pages, and eighty
two pages of exhibits, mainly con-
Tacts between various oil producers,
are appended.
Through a maize of "saids" and
"aforesaids" can be traced a story
of the Standard Oil Company as in
teresting as any yet written. With
intnße detail the growth of the com
paay tins been given and the con
nection of prominent men shown.
With legal blnntnees the company
is declared to be a gigantic conspir
acy to monopolise the oil business
TUB WENATCHEE DAILY WORLD, WENATCHEE, WASHINGTON, TUESDAY, APRIL 6, 1909.
of the world, and its tactics are des
cribed as unfair and contrary to the]
laws.
The complaint divides the devel
opment of the alleged monopoly Into
three periods: First, that from 1870
Ito 1882 when the individual defend
jants, John D. Rockefeller, William
j Rockefeller, Henry M. Flagler and
i others are described as forming the
Standard and forcing competitors out
of business; second, the period from
1882 to 1899, when the Standard
openly a "trust" operated under a
trusteeship headed by John D. Rock
efeller; third, the period from 1899
to the time of the filing of the com
plaint when the company organized
under the laws of New Jersey, Its
individual leadership lost behind its
corporate personage, is alleged to
have defined the United States and
continually to have violated the
Sherman anti-trust act.
Competition was stifled, the gov
ernment says, by price cutting. This
it declares the Standard was able to
do because of preferential rates and
rebates. The rebates, it is alleged,
were obtained through a conspiracy.
Bogus companies were formed to
crush competition it is declared.
Railroads were forced to use Stand
ard lubricating oil, competitors be
ling forced out of the field. The
United States was divided Into sec
tions each subsidiary company being
given its section so that prices might
be controlled, and there would be no
real competition. And each allega
tion Is backed with figures and maps
and copies of agreements.
The testimony taken has all borne
|some relation to some of the specific
charges in this complaint. It has
been intende to form proof of the
specific charges of unfair and illegal
methods. The testimony is as tan
gled as the story of the trust itself.
Each witness was asked questions
concerning various phases of the
dealings, and in the evidence each
man told facts which bore on specific
allegations scattered from first to
last of the long complaint.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92061524/1914-10-03/ed-1/?sp=4</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		GULDEN WEDDING
IS CELEBRATED BY
THE ROCKEFELLERS
Wife of Oil King, at Seventy-Five,
Realizes Life's Ambition.
SO GLIMPSES OF HER LIFE
Points In the Career of a Woman
Never Before Given to the Public
Family Was Always Her
First Consideration.
New York. In a secluded corner oí
the state of New 'York, a quiet little
old woman of seventy-five years en-
Joyed the realization of her her life's
ambition on Tuesday, September 8.
On that morning she attained her
golden wedding anniversary the goal
of her existence. Surrounded by all
(Of the richest man in the world, she
i cares only for the pleasures of the
thrifty housewife and the bestowing
of little charities that might be the
pride of, a prosperous' business man.
Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, one of the
principals in a golden wedding anni
versary that Is golden in every sense,
is tne personification of simplicity in
dress thought and manner.
There are plenty of 50-year wedding
anniversaries in these days. But sel-
do the very richerst dwell together in
peace and companionship through half
ra century of nuptial experience, re-
wear and tear incident to the amass-
John D. Rockefeller.'
lng of fortune and all the burdens
that money brings until they reach
an age sufficiently ripe to plan for
i golden weddings. 5
So the Rockefeller anniversary,
v which fell on September 8, was unique
in many ways.
It was in Cleveland, O., on a bright
autumn, day In 1864 that Laura Ce
Jestia Spelman and John D. Rockefel
ler took their nuptial vows. The bride
groom was twenty-five and the bride
was almost the same age, her birth
day succeding her wedding day,
i Their romance had Its foundation
in an acquaintanceship when both
were in grammar school at Cleveland,
and ripened after Miss Spelman had
finished her education at a boarding
school in Worcester, Mass., and re
turned in 1859 to Cleveland to teach,
í Mr. Rockefeller had been, a clerk in
a Cleveland commission house, but
about this time he entered into the
partnership of Clark Rockefeller in
the commission business, and laid the
foundation for his fortune in furnlsh-
lng food supplies to the Union army
at the outset cf the Civil war. His
sweetheart agreed to wait for him
until he had firmly established him
self, and their wedding was deferred
until John,' with the fruits of his com
mission business invested, launched
Into the oil Industry with" Andrews,
Clark Co., In 1862.
Thó story of how Rockefeller rose
to fortune subsequently by the forma
tion of the successive concerns of Wil
liam Rockefeller Co., and the vari
ous Standard Oil companies, culminat
ing in the Standard' trust. Is familiars
to almoBt every schoolboy. But what
of his wife, this little woman of to
dayf 1
Never a strong girl and of less than
average physical- size, she was al
ways of the sweetest disposition ?and
most kindly thought. She was, the
daughter of Harvey Buel Spelman,
who emigrated from his native Massa
chusetts to Akron, 0., where he .be
came a successful dry goods mer
chant. He was an educator and a
member of the Ohio legislature, an
ardent Congregationalist and aboli
tionist. He removed to Cleveland
when Laura was a child. In Cleve
land she attended grammar school,
and after a course in the East taught
in Cleveland for 'five years, giving up
pedagogy for matrimony. Her moth
er was an active W. C. T. TJ. wbrker,
and the daughter followed in her foot
steps. She was indefatigable In her
work for temperance, for the poor,
for those ill She "went about doing
good."
Despite her long residence in New
York city and her immense wealth, she
never figured in the society of the
metropolis. She sought, rather, the
hospitals to visit, comfort and give
financial help to those ill. And when
her children were large 'enough they
made their regular visits to the sick,
carrying flowers. She has .taken a
deep Interest in the ..welfare of col
ored girls in the South,' in 'which
work her father was interested before
her. In fact, Spelman pater estab
lished the Spelman seminary at At
lanta, Ga., for negro girls, and since
his death this institution has been
supported by Mrs. Rockefeller.
Mrs.. Rockefeller's chief occupation
in life has been the rearing' of her
four children. Another child died in
Infancy. Society never claimed her
from her children and she never has
had any interest that was considered
as approaching her family in impor
tance.
Mrs. Rockefeller trained her chil
dren in the ways of thrift just as she
might have done if she had expected
that they would be compelled to make
their own way in life. She set them
an example In, this respect in her
manner of dress and in the direction
of her household, even when this
involved the great home and grounds
at Pocantico Hills, Tarrytown, N.
Y. Her,' sociaf circles always in
cluded only the old friends of the
family friends made during the early
days when nobody suspected that John,
Rockefeller, commission merchant,ever
would be the richest man in the world.
Even this limited number of friends
often was neglected in order that the
mother. might devote all of her time
to her children.
During recent years when Mrs.
Rockefeller appeared in public she al
ways was clad In the same simple
style. She wore a black silk gown
with white lace trimmings at the
throat and cuffs, with a neat black
coat to match. v
Nobody ever discovered that Mrs.
Rockefeller was greatly, interested in
the wealth that her husband spent
his life in amassing. She suffered
much because of it. She suffered when
her husband faced numerous attacks
in newspapers and magazines .that
had to do with his methods of making
money and she suffered when he was
the defendant in several government
prosecutions that were brought on for
the same reason.
'But that practically was the only in
terest she had in the money credited
to her husband's account at the bank
or his numerous banks, to .be. ex
act. Any business man with' an in
come of $5,000 a year cpuld have pro
vided his wife with the 'ame 'luxu
ries that Mrs. Rockefeller enjoyed.
Most of the charities of the Rocke
feller family were left to the husband
or his aids to handle. Mrs. Rocke
feller, however, enjoyed bestowing
funds In certain directions herself.
A needy distant relative was inca
pacitated. A home was built and given
to him free of all cost by Mrs. Rocke
feller. 1
The church interests of this richest
wife have always been important in
her eyes. She was originally a Congre
gationalist. but upon her marriage
transferred her allegiance to the Bap
tist denomination of her husband, and
is now a member of the Euclid Ave
nue Baptist church in Cleveland. As
long as her health permitted, she
was never absent from her pew on
Sunday.
But it is In her home that she shows
to her best advantage. To her guests
she is a hostess royal. Always she
talks of those subjects which are
closest to the hearts of those she en
tertains the rare secret of a success
ful hostess. She makes all feel at
ease at once. There is nothing of the
snob in her. Lovable and companion
able at all times, she is a woman to
whom wealth has brought no change
of. character save to emphasize its
highest qualities.
In recent years she has been in very
Infirm health. But for the tender and
persistent care which she has received
at the hands of her husband she would
probably not have lived until now.
She never sought to buy titles for
her children, though she might easily,
have done so. And she never aspires
to the title of "oil queen" or any other
queen, though Bhe has some, excuse,
for the blood of royalty actually
flows In the veins of her "oil king"
husband.
Such .is the fact, for though not
many know of it, John D. Rockefeller
is a direct descendant of the reign
ing house of England, a lineal heir of
Edward Ironsides, once king, and of
all the succeeding rulers down to Ed
ward JII. Through the third Edward's
son, the earl of Leicester, he traces
his ancestry to the daughter of the
third earl of Lincoln, who married
John Humphrey, early magistrate .of
Massachusetts Bay colony, and whose
granddaughter, Susanna Palmes, wed
Samuel Avery, progenitor of Lucy
Avery, who married Godfrey Rocke
feller, the giandsire of John D.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1914-12-24/ed-1/?sp=25</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		JOHN D. HAS PURCHASED BIG
HUNK OF GLORY
New York, Dec. 24. In the last
year John D. Rockefeller has pur
chased ten and a half million dollars'
worth of glory as an educational
philanthropist by distributing that
amount of money to state colleges
and universities, according to a re
port issued by the general education
board. V
Tennessee received $625,000; Tex
as, $400,000; Ohio, $760,000; Illinois,
$300,000; Minnesota, $350,000; Iowa,
$596,516, and other states larger or
smaller donations.
Even Colorado, scene of carnage
not long since when gunmen
imported by the Rockefeller inter--ests
shot down miners and murdered
their wiyes and children, owes credit
to the philanthropist to the extent
of $200,000 donated to universities.
5 But it is from Colorado that the
piteous appeal has come for clothing
for almost naked children and food
fpr starving miners and their fam
ilies. o o
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1915-09-01/ed-1/?sp=7</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		MINERS AFTER ROCKEFELLER
WANT PROSECUTION
Denver, Sept. 1. Miners are after
John D. Rockefeller, Jr., tooth and
nail, it became known reliably today.
While a militia board of inquiry is
probing charges in connection with
reorganization of the state militia,
and while, it is indicated, the federal
government is taking a hand, it
leaked out here today that as a re
sult of this case and as an outgrowth
of the John R. Lawson conviction, a
concerted effort is under way to get
criminal prosecution of Rockefeller
and others in connection with death
of more than 40 strikers in the re
cent coal strikes.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1937-05-24/ed-1/seq-5</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		i,. •\'f ,"??y
bMHMEBn
fe'W-*«-
”♦ ‘ WW> F i"
1 Tuzm igrirffi
• * ■»- Wy y 1 *S ■ ■ *' kl
"
If II
JB .■'■»* ■
* IRrF > A
‘
I ** Tw*\
•B .» .-•-*%- • O ' ''" ' '* '
’JB H Jk >* ”' ■ K
• wtf ' * , r Wslx x Os
“ y; ;
& ■ -«> *. * ' k \L ' WB
- >'; -
■» ■ w. vww -
PLAYING A CHIP SHOT WITH A MASHIE NIBLICK ON HIS PRIVATE
COURSE AT ORMOND BEACH, FLA.
"k ft. c BBf
WITH two of his 11 great-grandchildren at the Lakewood, N. J.,
estate—John, 9 months (left), and Elizabeth de Ouevas, 2Vi years.
Their grandmother was Bessie Rockefeller, John D.’s (lighter.
I ? ■■■■ __
I \- JKBr
I
nJK
gfl ar \ ’
K V W_ wFjp " y J
. '" "' ■ **r ■. •* B 'l*t» $$
i THE LATE Will Rogers got a laugh by congratulating the multi
millionaire on having beaten him (Rogers) at golf. The humorist
remarked it was a good thing Rockefeller won, because the last time
he lost to Rogers the price of gasoline rose 2 cental
, ,•• •-■, :V
> e». ■*-- »- W * •/ > U 2. &SBMB
The Man Who Gave Away
Half A Billion Dollars
>
JOHN D. KOOKXFELLEK,
who died yesterday at his
estate in Ormond Beach, Fla.,
was one of the world’s great
proponents of golf as well as
one of the game’s wealthiest
players. He was an outstand
ing example of the oft-re
peated statement that golf is
a sport for young and old.
THE WASHINGTON TIMES, MONDAY, MAY 24, 1&37
e
hk
A F , ‘/\\ B Ik
A| F 1 naLi - A A B Hk
A B K '\ Jk b &
j| ™' l >,WI 1 • • • ■
jW ■PKm Ifet -7 W^"w> *% * \ H fliji
1 *k- — - 1
' y--WoB F i‘
A Hhk * ■ M
:
THE MAN whose name was synonymous with enormous
wealth, whose phenomenal business success was symbolic of
the greatest period of expansion in the history of the United
States and whose later philanthropies spread around the
world—John D. Rockefeller.
a»:w>ye;-•:«:»'W:-?»^:>y.:w<»W:«-:rt:-:
''•WWW,"'--''*
HL
■ Bk "’
B Bb
» A ’Sht mI *"
*-1 j •
. .W ’ ■ -V *'•:<''
.*W»X J " ■ *
4&. * -
r*'?. b<?, - IeWMI .' ■
> /-> -i? > ? - - ' Wkfc. *
i<A / ;■
1 K 1
BBra
mHRMHHMBk
•
X’ I jfflßlF *
• }' 7- J *.M
Jffi /I
%VF
OSI/ ' F v 1
w* BBS / i
ISwT; ? / M
Ao to ■
Hff • • ffl MF 3 / H
X z O
JOHN D. ROCKEFELLER, Jr., now .63, to whom his
father passed the burden of directing the gigantic family
fortune several years ago. He is generally considered a
firrt-class business leader and philanthropist.
■ •■ -■- ''.v’s. - Wj: 5 ■■ % ■Tni‘-irr--‘ ■ --. ?y y i
/
i'-// '7rlß
*
jH
< ’?% ; 'SbSI / & ’’"W
■kt BRfeio. * B
awi KrJH BKX&B o
Bk^-..ws BtHF • * JI
Ihß
"wl HEk’■ *B BB E—%/B
I®f?-> •*^^^sß^^HJI H “--sJB
•■rWjWLii ■ BBSfe
d“zS',’ ' *
AN AUDIENCE awaits him—and shiny dimes—as he leaves church services at Lakewood, N. J.,
the location of one of his five estates. International News Photo.
gr?T-: ■< ■ -•
ryy
? ■'•' —, - Tik jj||
ifc .JF
> -B w
fl
fl ... SL f
B ;
w w ’-■'•■ -11.
■ r r. f
fc' -A I
'' ■ L. -
Ba ■'
ROCKEFELLER at 36, sporting the
“muttonchop” whiskers of the period. His
company at this period owned most of the
oil lands in New .York and Pennsylvania.
District 7000
b jE
w <k xIK Est/
JEfe jO; ft
>«?,’ ■” i ' z <Jfti B »’-'
'<- r
®FRi;..- 4 • :
< • ■'-' . F Bl
. Bl
B*i»’
AT 96 he was still an animated being whose vitality con
tinued to amaze physicians—and himself. This is another
view of him on the golf course, in the act of relating a
story which he found very amusing. After such an occasion
he would hand out dimes to his listeners.
3 bMf ign' <. ,>•> Ig g
O'”'
B < W'W
■ : b
/. <z-9 iwfliM
WIFE of John D. Rockefeller, who was
Laura C. Spelman, of Cleveland. They were
married in 1864. Mrs. Rockefeller, who died
in 1915, bore four children.
5
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1927-11-27/ed-1/seq-105</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87096037/1907-07-04/ed-1/seq-1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
LANDIS DECLARES
HE WILL GET HIM
Says the Oil Magnate Must Appear
Before Him—Will Continue Case
All Summer If Necessary—Seven
Officials of Company Served.
NO DOUBT IT WILL BE EMBARRASSING,
iTANO/te'
OIL CO'
To Be Recognized in Open Court as Owher of That Little Octopup.
New York, July 1.—Dispatches from
Pittsfield, Mass., report that Mrs. E.
Parmalee Prentice, who is at Onota
farm- for the summer, is entertain
ing her father, John D. Rockefeller,
and the estate is under strong guard,
presumably.to prevent Mr. Rockefeller,
being disturbed by process servers.
These dispatches state that the lake
front of the property is patroled by
a launch and that a reporter who
drove out to the place, which he
found guarded at all sides, was in
formed that he could not approach
the house. Mr. Rockefeller arrived at
Onota farm late Thursday night.
Denial from Son-in-Law.
Pittsfield, Mass., July 1.—E. Parma
lee Prentice, son-in-law of John D.
Rockefeller, authorized the statement
Saturday that Mr. Rockefeller is not
in Pittsfield at the present time, n»r
has he been in Pittsfield recently. Mr.
Prentice has a summer home at On
ota Lake, on the outskirts of the city,
and it was reported that Mr. Rocke
feller had been visiting him since
Thursday night.
LANDIS BOUND TO GET HIM.
Chicago Judge Will Serve Subpoenas
If It Takes All Summer.
Chicago, July 1.—Make every ef
fort possible to have every, one of the
subpoenas served." In substance this
was the. order delivered to District At
torney Sims Saturday morning by
Judge Landis, who is determined to
hear what John D. Rockefeller and
the lesser officials of the Standard Oil
company have to say about the finan
cial holdings, resources and relations
of the New Jersey and Indiana cor
porations of the so-called trust. It
was reported that Mr. Sims was pre
paring to go east to take part himself
in directing the court processes to
obtain subpoena service on John D.
Rockefeller and the others who have
LAND! LAND
'Ttf/CACrO PAUYJVtys
not yet neen round Dy united states
Marshal Henkel of New York.
Sims Does Not Divulge Plans.
Mr. Sims would not say what his
plans were but declared he would do
everything he could to carry out the
court's directions. He was waiting in
his office this morning for further
word from Marshal Henkel concern
ing the serving of the subpoenas.
What Marshal Henkel has to say
about the -whereabouts of Mr. Rocke
feller will play an important part in
the further action to be taken here.
Will Keep After Rockefeller.
If it is found that Mr. Rockefeller is
not served with a subpoena in time
for his appearance here July 6 federal
authorities say they will keep after
him until they do get him. Judge
Landis has indicated to District At
torney Sims that he will continue the
case from time to time until he has
either found out from the Standard
officers what he wants to know before
intfosing a fine in the case against
the Indiana company or has heard
them state in open court their refusal
to answer his questions.
Case May Last All Summer.
Such being the case, it is said, the
latest phase of the difficulties between
the government and the defendant
company in the present case may
hang fire all through the summer.
Hope of subpoena service on H. H.
Rogers and Treasurer W. H. Tilford
has been abandoned because they are
in Europe. The others yet to be
served are John D. Rockefeller, Wil
liam Rockefeller, John D. Archbold
and C. M. Pratt.
Seven Officials Are Served.
Seven officials of the Standard Oil
company have been served with the
subpoenas issued by Judge Landis to
force them to appear in his branch of
the United.States District court July
6. Five of them were served by the
deputy United States marshals in
New York and two of them by the
local officers. John D. Rockefeller is
said to be in hiding. Search for him
was continued Saturday.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90052331/1907-09-26/ed-1/seq-1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Five men with estates the stock of
which is voted as those controlling
spirits which practically own the Oil
Trust, and these five in eight years,
from 1899 to 1906, divided among
themselves more than $100,000,000 in
dividends. They have the absolute
control of the great corporation in
their hands. Their names are John
D. Rockefeller, William Rockefeller,
Henry H. Rogers, Henry M. Flag
ler and Charles M. Pratt.
With John D. Rockefeller as lead
er, because his share in the Oil Trust
amounts to more than all of the oth
ers combined, these five men, with the
addition of one more, James Still
man, William Rockefeller’s brother
in-law, have used this colossal engine
of wealth to get control of industrial,
commercial and financial combina
tions which have a combined capital
of over five billions of dollars.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1949-09-25/ed-1/seq-101</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-martians</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033306/1877-08-30/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		UP IX 3IARS.
Bnuona Tor Believing that the Planet is
Inhabited.
The conditions which favor the blief
in the existence of life in the planet
Mars present the clearest possible evi
dence ot being one in origin and structure
with our own earth. We cannot tell
wnat the nature of the soil of Mars may
be, but its generally ruddy tince so
well marked that, though the telescope
shows an almost equal part of the surface
to be greenish in hue, the red prevails,
giving to the planet, as seen by the naked
eye, its obvious red color eee'ms to show
that it resembles the red sandstone of
our own earth. This, we know, is one of
tne oiaer geological tormations, and if we
could safely compare terrestrial with
Martian geology, or, let us say, geology
with aerology, we might almost be
tempted to find in the present prevalence
of a tint belonging to one of the earlier
of our terrestrial formation an argument
in favor of the theory that Mars passed
through fewer stages of development
during its life bearing condition than
on r earth, and that thus the later forma
tions of our earth's surface are wanting
in the surface of Mars. This reasoning
would not be very safe, however, it im
plies a resemblance in details which is
not likely, the observed rule of nature
seeming so far as we can judge, to be
similarity in generals, variety in details.
We may well believe that the ruddiness
of the soil of Mars is due to the same
general cause as the ruddiness of our
red sandstone the general prevalence of
certain organisms but neither the actual
character of this particular formation,
nor its position in the territorial series of
strata can be safely predicted of the
ruddy formation constituting the chief
part of the visible land surface of Mars.
Few will now suppose with a French
writer that the ruddiness of Mars is due
to the color of the vegetation there. A
certain support is given to the idea by.
the circumstance that the degree ot rud
diness is variable, and is somewhat
greater during the Martain summer than
in spring and autumn. In this sense we
may say of the summer of Mars with the
poet Wendell Holmes
The snows that glittered on the disc of Mars
Have melted, and the planet's fiery ob
Bolls in the crimson summer of its year.
But the ruddiness of the planet's sum
mer which will be well marked this
year, for on September 18, only eleven
days after its time of nearest approach
and greatest splendor, it will be mid
summer's day lor the southern half of
Mara can be otherwise and better ex
plained than by supposing that the
Martian forests glow with fiery foliage
during the summer days. We can see,
as the summer proceeds, the white mists
which had hidden the planet's lands and
seas breaking up, and the features of the
surface being gradually revealed with
more and more distinctness. It is to the
disappearance of these mists and clouds,
not to the red leaves of Martian trees,
that the change in the plant's color must
most probably be referred. We have less
reason for doubt as to the nature of the
greenish markings. The spectroscope, as
we have already explained in "Life in
Mars," shows that the air of Mars is at
times laden heavily with the vapor of
water. We can no longer, therefore,
follow Wbewell in doubting the real na
ture of the green parts of the planet, or
refuse with him to accept explanation of
the white polar marking long since ad
vanced by Sir W. Herschel. Undoubt
edly wide seas and oceans, with many
straits and bays and inland seas, exist on
Mars. Snow and ice gather in the win
ter time about his polar regions, dimin
ishing gradually in extent as summer
proceeds, but never entirely disappearing.
Thus we are not left doubtful as to the
general resemblance of Mars, so tar as the
structure of his surface is concerned, to
the earth on which we live. He has a
surface of earth, probably in large part
formed by deposition at the bottom of
former seas and subsequently raised
above the sea level by subterranean forces,
or rather caused to appear above the
surface by the effects of the gradual
shrinkage of the planet's crust. Cornhill
Magazine.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87075000/1871-05-05/ed-1/?sp=4</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		How Life in Mars Goes On.
In the case of the planet liars, and in
the case of the planet Mars -alone, oar
astronomers have really established the
existence of a similarity of physical con
dition, which gives us the strongest posi
tive grounds for inferring that even such
creatures as we now are could somehow
make shift to live there, though, of course,
not without a certain amount of preli
minary discomfort while we were trying to
acclimatize ourselves. Mr. Proctor's
graphic account f these similarities, and
his delightful chart of the planet's conti
nents and waters, suggests to ub to discuss
one or two of the known differences of
condition, in their relation to the probable
results upon the history and civilization of
the Martialists.
First, let us briefly say that the Mar
tialista have a world less in area than one
of our hemispheres to explore that, in
spite of this, it has not much less land than
the earth, a much less proportion of its
surface being occupied with water than of
our globe its seas are of the general type
of tne Baltic and Mediterranean, for the
most part narrow, straggling, inland seas
jthe greatest seas are in the neighborhood
of the cold south pole of Mars, which has
a climate far severer than the north pole
there is a world of perpetual snow at tach
Martial pole, which can be seen to diminish
as the summer returns to each hemisphere,
and to increase again as winter comes
back; and, in spite of the prepon
derance of land, a vast deal of rain falls on
Mars, especially in winter, clouds often
hiding the configuration of the continents
from our astronomers, and the suddenly
dispersing, and leaving the continents clear
again a clearing up which usually happens
about the hour of noon-in Mars, just as
our weather so often changes as the sun
passes the meridian that the length of the
Martial year is nearly twice as long as
ours; and that the force of gravity on
Mars is much less than half what it is with
us, so that, as Mr. Proctor expresses it, fa
Daniel Lambert on Mars would be able to
leap easily to a height of five or six feet,
and he could run faster than the best of
our terrestrial athletes."
The general result, then, of the tele
scopical observations on Mars, and the de
duced calculations, may be said to be
(1.) With certainty, that the' weight of
objects of the same mass in Mars is much
less than half what it is here, and that
consequently there would be a far greater
range of activity for creatures of the same
size, that falls would be less dangerous,
that the strain on walls or columns, or any
other supports, would be much less and
that, therefore, roofs, arches and struc
tures of that kind might be easily set up
on a much larger scale by creatures of
equal skill with ourselves; but, on the
other hand, that friction, which is more or
less proportional to pressure, and,
fore, in the case of piles of
stones, etc, to weight, would be far less
than on the surface of the earth, so that
any violent lateral disturbances, such as
hurricanes, would exert a still greater ef
fect than on our earth in destroying such
structures, since there would be less solid
ity and, therefore, less fractional resistance
to overcome in overturning them. Again,
the vastly diminished weight of given
masses would give a very great advantage
to all kinds of engines of draught Car
riages, carts and railways would attain a
vastly greater speed than on our earth, and
the sledging on the snow-fields of Mars
might be as swift as the wind. All these
inferences are matters of certainty, so far
as they go.
But (2) there seems a very great proba
bility that the atmosphere of Mars is re
latively considerable denser than ours,
since at a distance from the sun so much
greater that the planet probably receives,
directly, less than half the light and heat
we receive. There seems no sign of any
arctic severity, and clear evidence that the
atmosphere holds vast quantises of watery
vapr, even in winter, which points to a
temperature much higher than our world
would have if removed to the same dis
tance from the sun, especially when one
considers how much less water to supply
vapor, and how much greater a propor
tion ot iana man tne earth Mars contains.
Again, the rapidity with which storms
clear off from a big continent, and leave
the outlines clearly marked after being all
enveloped in mist before, seems to show
the existence of very rapid currents of air;
and this no doubt the greater inclination
of the axis of Mars, giving a greater range
to the northward and southward journeys
of the sun, would promote. Putting these
facts together, then, we 6hould infer that
tne atmosphere of Mars is, in proportion,
heavier than that cf the earth, and there
fore a wanner envelope for the planet
that its winds are more violent, and that
the great difficulty of the architects of the
planet is more likely to be the strengthen
ing of their structures against lateral forces
hurricanes, for instance than against
me buiuu 01 gravity. ineir outer walls
would hav,e to be comparatively much
more solid their difficulty in rising broad
arches and spacious roofs would be much
less; and locomotion on Mars must be
more easy and speedy, eeterit paribus, than
wcumouou on eann.
If this be so, we may see a fitness in the
much larger proportion of land in the
planet, and the comparative narrowness
ana smauness ot the s as. Probably life
in Mars is faster than it is here. It is very
improbable that the civilization of the dif
ferent continents there, is divided by peri
ods extending over two thousand years.
There is probably no one of the great con
tinental tracts 01 aiars Known there as
the New World." If great migrations
of conquering races have taken place on
Mars, as on the earth, they have probably
uruHi eacn otner iaster, Having a less
surface to move over, less obstacles, per
haps, in the way, and greater advantages
in locomotion. We should not be sur
prised, too, if the Martialists had got
greatly ahead of us in resDect of n a vi rat
ing the air. We know that the density of
Ilia 1 1 J J
puwcb, as wuuie, lit jess man inree
fourths of tnat of our earth; so that it
seems uaeiy inai me tissues of the body
of a Martialist, which must be fed from
the substance of the planet, are. on the
whole, intrinsically lighter than those of
man s ooay. But, u the Martialists' bodies
are intrinsically lighter, and their atmos
phere a good deal heavier than ours, aerial
transit may be a very easy matter to them,
and it is quite conceivable that their
normal mode of locomotion may be through
the air.
Again, if we are right in supposing the
currents of air in Mars to be of more than
usual violence, while the solidifying force
of friction which resists them is much
smaller than here, it may be a reasonable
inference that natural selection" has al
ready weeded out the loftier growing trees,
which would stand less chance in encount
ers with hurricanes than our own and it
is not improbable that the tendency of the
greater facilities for motion, and the great
er velocity of life in Mars altogether,
would be that all its animal inhabitants
range wider for their food, and obtain less
on a given area than on our earth.
We should be disposed to conjecture
that it is a world in which speed is greater
and of more importance than even on the
earth and, if so, it seems likely enough
that the difficulty we have supposed as to
the solidity of walls exposed to the atmos
pheric currents of Mars is got over as the
difficulty of building durable structures is
generally got over in our own tropics,
where earthquakes are so common by not
building durable structures at all, but only
very light and fragile ones a process
which would, of course, be much easier
where all the materials were lighter and
all motion swifter than with us. In a
word, it seems likely that the distinctive
feature of life on Mars is velocity; that
the creatures there live faster, move often
er, undergo more change just as the
planet itself passes through a far vaster
orbit (though its orbital velocity is not
quite so great as ours) in one of the
Martial years. But that such a character
istic would tend to quicken the progress
of the mind and of discovery is doubtfuL
With us civilization has never advanced
rapidly till it had become tame and, so to
say, plodding, and the excitements of local
change, at least, had become few. But
the great seasonal changes of Mars es
pecially in the southern hemisphere, where
the winter and summer are aggravated by
the enormously increased distance of the
sun at that period when his rays are least
direct, and his nearness at that period
when his rays are most direct contribute
to confirm the impression we have drawn
from other considerations that physically.
at least, the lite tnere nas lar more oi
rapid change in it than we can easily con
ceive but whether that has developed or
arrested the mental and moral progress of
the Martialists is a question of which the
elements are altogether too conjectural for
serious discussion. London Spectator.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86091092/1892-08-20/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		PLANET mars and its hen
jocb Discussion as to tbe Lights and
Marks on the Planet.
^semblances Between Mars and Earth
_We Cannot Tell Tet About the
Men Theré.
Are the people on the planet
Mars trying to signal the earth?
That is the question which the
work of the great Lick telescope
during the past few days has
aroused, as Mars has approached
nearer and nearer to the big Cali
fornia instrument, wTiich will soon
have opportunities for observation
sueh as were never known before
in the history of astronomy.
This may be the explanation of
the Btrange phenomena observed
this week at the Lick observatory.
The results thus far obtained have
already been so extraordinary as
to have made profound impression
upon the practical minds of the
astronomers there assembled.
Three great lights, forming a tri
angle, have been seen in the south
western limb of the planet. They
had never been seen before, in any
observations.
There was no mistake about
these lights. They were seen for
four nights in succession, so that it
was impossible that they could
have been produced by conditions
of the earthly or Martian atmos
pheres or have been optical delu
eions ot any kind. Wnen first
seen at the Lick observatory, these
lights in a triangle so astonished
the astonomers that they believed
them to be the effect of light uncon
nected with the planet. They
therefore, with true astronomical
caution, waited until the following
night before devoting much thought
to the lights. On the second night,
however, which was even more
clear and brilliant than the first,
the lights were Been to be there
when the great polished lens was
turned upon the orb which had
itepped to its place in the sky.
For two succeeding evenings
after that these lights were ob
served, burning steadily, brilliantly
and effulgently, as if from three
mountain tops. It was evident
that the lights were placed upon
mountains in Mars or artificial
projections or elevations of some
kind.
The appearance of three brilliant
lights in a triangle upon one of tbe
plaiiets in a manner the astrono
mers are unable to explain raises a
presumption at which their minds
recoil. A scientist would, when
thoroughly convinced of the exist
ence of these light under such con
ditions as are known to prevail in
Mars, easily glide to the almost
irresistible conclusion that they
were the work of the men on
MarB.
Observed at any other time
there would be apparently no other
mean of explaining these lights in a
way satisfactory to common sense
Observed at the present time, whon
eminent men in science have
reached the conclusion that the
people on Mars would seize tho
opportunity to try again to attract
the attention of people on the earth
the three lights on Mars are as
significant as the moving lights in
the diBtanco were to Columbus on
his caravel.
Hut tho the three strange lights
which have looked down tho 3b
incli tube of the Lick telescope for
four successive nights and astound
ed the astronomers at the other end
art- not the only unusual appear
ances upon the surface of the
planet which the great piece of
Hint glass has revealed. That
glass, which cost over $50,000 and
at
took years to select, grind and
polish until perfection was attained,
has re waled things which other
observatories have not noticed dur
ing the present opposition.
The people of Mars being able to
bridge this globe which we call
Earth so close to them that they
can see forests, fields and cities, if
indeed, they cannot actually see
people walking on the streets,
would be eager to establish com
munication with us. They may
have tried to do this for centuties
at each recurring opposition of
Mars, or opposition of the Earth,
as they would call it, and repeated
failures would only stir them to
greater efforts.
The light» suddenly went out,
though, at different times of the
four nights when they were seen.
It almost seemed as if they were
supplied by an electric current and
as if the current had been shut off,
so suddenly did they disappear.
Amazement struck the observers
when first the lights went out.
They reflected that, of course, the
lights were some atmospheric effect
on the rim of Mar* and the very
fact of their strange disappearance
tended to prove this. The next
night, however, the three Btrange
lights flashed out in the same
place as soon as darkness had set
in and after showing steadily for a
few hours they vanished.
SchiaparelU was the first person
to give definite basis upon which
to rest the belief that Mars was
inhabited by a highly civilized
race. He discovered that the sur
face of the planet was intersected
by a large number of canals.
Primarily, Flammarion based
his theory upon that of Schiaparelli
and the two run in together in
many places, being to a large ex
tent identical. He showed plainly
that there was water upon the
planet, and there was little doubt,
he said, that the inhabitants of
Mars very closely resembled those
ot the earth.
Thus, in considering the subject
of opening up communication with
the Martians Flammarion has de
voted much thought to a possible
method of signals which might be
devised upon the earth. He has
said: "A triangle, traced in lumi
nous lines on MarB* surface, each
side from twelve to fifteen kilome
tres long, would be visible from
here by the aid of our telescopes.
It follows then that a triangle,
square or circle of the dimen
sions stated, constructed upon
a vast plain of the earth by
means of luminous points, reflected
in the daytime by solar light and
ligted at night by electicity, would
be visible to the astronomers of
Mars if there are such astronomers
and if they have optical instruments
as good as our own.
Tracing this illustration still fur
ther, Flammarion has said:
"The logical sequence is simple.
If we were to see a triangle con
structed on Mars we would be con
siderably puzzled, but if we were
to see it change first into a square
and then into a circle we would
think with some reason that such
figures reveal without question the
presence of a geometrician upon
the neighbor world. The question
however, now arises, what object
our brethren could have in forming
these figures. Why Bhould not the
inhabitants of Mars be as curious
as we are, more intelligent perhaps,
more elevated in their aspirations,
less hampered than we are in the
mire of material needs? Why
should they not suppose that the
earth is inhabited as well a» their
own world, and why should not the
object of these geometrical appeals
be to ask ub whethes whether we
exist? It is not difficult to reply.
They show us a triangle; we pro
duce it here. They trace a circle;
imitate it, and lo! communication
is established.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015679/1896-10-18/ed-1/?sp=16</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		THE MARTIAN FORESTS
VERIFIED BY OBSERVATIONS AT
THE LOWELL OBSERVATORY.
Remarkable Evidence of the Passase
of tbe Seaoni, Foliase Changing
from Green to Yellovr.
Flagstaff (Ariz.) Letter in New York
Herald.
Since our communication to the Herald
regarding the doubling of the Ganges, two
other canals on Mars have begun to show
double the Phison and the Euphrates. The
importance of this observation lies in the
fact that such duplication was precisely
what theory led us to expect would occur.
It is six weeks since the Ganges showed
double at a time and in a manner parallel
ing its appearances at the last apposition.
The Phison and Euphrates are now in HXe
manner counterpartlng their behavior of
two years ago.
Nor is this all. The surface of the planet,
both in the light and the dark regions is
undergoing the same metamorphosis It did
then. In other words, the seasonal changes
observed in the last Martian year are re
peating themselves in this one. That these
seasonal changes are the effect of vegeta
tion upon the planet we showed then to be
almost certainly the fact. The observations
of this year help to confirm our deduction.
The seasonal history of the two succes
sive Martian years thus paralleling itself
Is in detail most interesting to witness. Wre
will begin with the behavior of the Syrtis
Major and then pass on to that of the
double canals. The Syrtis Major is the
most important of the dark areas on the
planet. It ia a curious funnel-shaped mark
ing, large toward the south, and contract
ing steadily northward till It comes to an
end in two canals that curve respectively
east and west away from it, forming the
Astapus and the Nilosyrtis.
It Is historically of great interest, because
it was the first marking Identified with cer
tainty on the planet by Huygens, in 1659,
and by its identification first enabled the
planet's rotation period to be found. It
was then and long afterward believed to
be a great sea or ocean, Its blue-green col
or seeming to render this a most probable
supposition. More minute examination has
now, as we have said, rendered It practi
cally certain that it Is, in fact, not an
ocean at all, but the largest fertile region
on the planet's surface, its blue-green hue
being due to vegetation, leaves and trasses,
or whatever relatives of such may consti
tute the Martian flora.
The following account of its successive
appearances will show the reader the rea
sons upon which this deduction of its char
acter is based. Early in the Martian year
the planet's southern hemisphere, the Syr
tis Major, and the great contiguous dark
area, under the same name, to the south,
and now more commonly known as the
Tyrrhenium, presents the appearance of one
nearly uniform blue green surface. The
only discernible diversities in it are the
deeper tint of its northern end, the com
paratively narrow neck of the funnel and
of two long bands which join it to the polar
sea, traversing about sixty degrees of lati
tude in order to do so. These bands are of
a deeper color than the rest of the region,
but not so dark aa the bottom of the Syrtis
itself.
THE SEASONS ON MARS.
Such is the appearance during the spring
months, and such it continues to be into
what corresponds In the Martian calendar
to our May and June. After the summer
solstice of the Martian southern hemi
sphere, when the season passes from its
June into its July, the extreme southern
parts of the dark area fade and turn stead
ily from a deep blue green to a fainter one
and then into an orange ochre.
Shortly after this there appears in the
Syrtis Major itself strange mottllngs, Curi
ous causewaylike appearances and rhom
boidal areas of a perceptibly lighter tint
than their surroundings. These then change
further from a faint blue green to an
orange ochre, just as happened before in
the parts of the surface further south.
These causeways, as we may designate
them tor distinction, are very singular
looking marks indeed. They stretch from
the so-called continental bright areas of
the planet over to the so-called islands to
the south, and look precisely as if they
were actual causeways connecting the two.
There are a great many of them all around
the planet. In the rejfion we are now re
viewing there are two, both of them strik
ing and peculiar Soils Pons and Lunae
Pons, the former joining Hammonis Cornu,
the great cape on the west side of the Sjrr
tis, to the northern end of Hellas, 4he lat
ter connecting In like manner the Circe
Promontorium, the cape on the east side of
the Syrtis, with Hellas. They both reach
Hellas at almost, if not exactly, the same
point.
These two curious links between light re
gions were first seen in 1894, about the tenth
of the Martian July.
To understand the significance of their
apppearance this year we must note the
time of the Martian year, owing to the dlf
fr.rr.nt snepds with which the earth and
Mars revolve about the sun. The earth
otrtakes Mars once in about two years
and two months. Such meetings are called
oppositions, because the planet is then seen
In the opposite part of the sky from the
sim. Now, as the periods of the two plan
ets are not exact multiples of each other.
Mars has made, like the earth, about two
of its months more than a revolution since
the two planets met. In consequence we
see him at a time about two months later
in his year, with his reasons corresponding
lv advanced.
Thus, when observations began this year,
it was not. in Martian time about the 1st
of May, but about the 1st of July. Now
as eoon as the planet was looked at there
was the Lunae Pons distinctly visible. It
appears singularly enough in the very first
drawing made, on July 23. Our July, this
Is, for it may be well to caution the reader
to xeep the two calendars distinct. Close
as ihe two dates of detection are for the
two Martian years, it is quite possible that
the phenomena required even nearer the
same Martian date than this. For, in the
first place, owing to the rotation of the
planet the same side of his surface is not
presented to the earth favorably for ob
servation but for a part of each forty
days, and it may therefore very well hap
pen that an event taking place at the
beginning of this observational gap may
not be noticed as having happened till the
end of it.
MR. LOWELL'S OBSERVATION.
In the next place different observers dif
fer in what they must readily perceive, and
it so chanced that the observer, Mr. Lowell,
who first saw the Lunae Pons on both oc
casions had not observed at just that Mar
tian time. It is Interesting to note that
these causeways are apparently optically
connected with Mr. Douglass's canals In
the dark regions, the one probably lying
alongside the other. In addition to the
causeways are the rhomboidal and other
bright areas that seasonably arise in the
Syrtis. Like the causeways, they have
made their anpearance after the summer
solstice of the southern hemisphere at both
oppositions.
Very curious features they are. One
called Oenotria, looking like a long sand
bar left high and dry on the receding of
the tide, is on the western coast of the
Syrtis and separated from Aeria by a deep
blue green canal. It is, however, not an
inundation or tide, but parching, that in all
probability produces the metamorphosis we
detect. The growth that in the heyday of
its springtime looks so green, quickened
by the water liberated from the south polar
cap, has by the first of its July passed into
the sere and yellow leaf.
The speed with which It undergoes Its
changes Is doubtless due to the greater
aridity of Mars, the water not being suffi
cient in amount to keep it longer alive.
That all this was vegetal, not marine, is
pretty conclusively shown, for the theory
that the so-called seas should show differ
ent tints implies that they were shallow
enough to be seen through a highly im
probable supposition on the face of it. That
they changed from blue green to orange
ochre over hundreds of square miles im
plies, on the supposition that they areseas,
an immense transference of water, which
would occasion a corresponding darkening
of other regions. No such corresponding
darkening took place.
Thirdly, that Mr. Douglass found them
traversed by dark lines is quite Incompat
ible with an aquatic character. Lastly, that
Professor Pickering, with the pclariscope,
found the only certain body of water on
the planet, the polar sea, to show evi
dence of being such, while the so-called
seas showed none, is further conclusive as
to their character.
From the dark areas we pass to the light
ones. Beside the Syrtis Major, to the west,
lies. Aerla. It 13 here that are to be found
the Phison and the Euphrates. During the
Martian spring this great light area is to
our present telescopic power one vast
blank, a huge desert no more, no less.
THE POLAR SEA.
When the advancing warmth has un
locked the polar snow and let the water
find its way, aerially and otherwise, to the
equator, strange lines begin to make their
appearance athwart this desert. Two of the
most conspicuous of them start from the
middle of the southern side of ihe desert
and run dlvergingly the one a little to the
east, the other a little to the west of north
down to the Nilosyrtis.
The eastward one is the Phison; the west
ward the Euphrates.
In this singleness of look and Intent each
continues until about the 1st of August,
Martian time, when two lines begin to
show where one showed before two lines
exactly paralleling the originals in posi
tion and direction. Indefinite at first, the
twin lines gain distinctiveness as time goes
on apparently solely by darkening, until
at last the doubling Is unmistakable, and
the two resemble nothing on earth so fiuch
as the twin rails of a railroad track.
All tlls happened two years ago at the
proper reason of the Martian year, and it
is all happening at the corresponding one
now. At the present moment the lines are
evidently double, but not very dark. The
duplication is following the example of the
Ganges in order of time, just as it did then.
The details of the process are curious
and suggestive. At the points where these
lines, which are almost spiderlike in tenu
ity, leave the dark regions there appear'
what look like nicks In the contour of the
edge of the desert. Wherever there are
canals there are nicks, and where there
are double canals there are double nicks.
Now, these nicks are more conspicuous
when well seen than the canals themselves,
although when not well seen the canals
are more easily detected, as long blurs,
because of their length.
Furthermore, they make their appear
ance apparently rather before the canal
Itself. Double nicks were seen where the
double canals start in 1S94. The same
double nicks at the confines of the deserts
are visible now.
What they are is one of the most inter
esting problems before us. They are prob
ably a sort of relay station for the water
on Its way from the canals in the dark,
region Into, those in the light.
Of the oases it is not our purpose to how
speak, although they, too, have made their
appearance Just as they appeared two years
ago. The significant point of the whole is
that the seasonal phenomena of the Mar
tian year are repeating themselves at this
present one, even to details. Tl at Mars is
not only a living world, but a very orderly
one to boot, is pretty conclusively shown
by the phenomena.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045366/1906-11-04/ed-1/?sp=61</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		3 ASPHALT CRACK*
to intim
8. CRATER HA(NS.
Mill*
THE
fessor Edward S. Morse, curatorof the
department of Japanese pottery at the
Boston Museum of Fine Arts, says the
Boeton Herald.
Professor Morse, while not an astron
omer by profession, has made a special
study of Mars for many years. Hi
new bo6k, '"'Mars and It Mystery,"
which appeared early in October, con
tains some astonishing revelations
about our next-door neighbor in the
solar system.
Professor Morse thinks the inhabi
tants of Mara may raise tobacco exten
sively. The Martians may be even
greater smokers than the men. of the
earth. How Professor Morse got this
idea is best explained in his own
words.:
"At certain times there has been ob
served in the equatorial region of Mars
a number of white spots, which have
greatly puzzled the student of Mars,
and for which no explanation has yet
been- offered. That they are not clouds
is seen in the fact that they do not
move or drift. Furthermore, these
white spots are fixed features of the
region, as they appear in the same
places.. ._,.:._
'.'It might "Ke* suggested "that they
represent snow-capped elevations or
mountain peaks, but this is difficult to
believe, as an examination of the ter
minator of Mars reveals no evidences
of -high elevations. These white spots
appear only in midsummer, which
would argue against their being snow
caps, as in midsummer they would cer
tainly melt and disappear. The time
of their appearance coincides with the
time of greatest equatorial heat.
"Since the appearance of these
white spots in Mars corresponds with
the period of greatest evaporation, it
is conceivable that an intelligence in
Mars might utilize the same method
which has recently been adopted in
Connecticut and Porto Rico in the
raising of tobacco, namejy, to protect
the fields with white cotton cloth."
It is the canals of Mars, however,
that furnish Professor Morse with the
strongest evidence of life on the red
planet. On this point he quotes Pro
fessor Pcrcival Lowell of Boston, who
has made more extensive obrervations
of the Martian canals than any other
astronomer. He says:
"What we see hints of the existence
of beings who are in advance of, not
behind, us in the -journey of life."
Problems of a Dying World.
A peculiar interest is excited in these
superior beings because they have
grappled with the problems of a dying
world. They have learned how to ex-,
ist on a desert planet where water is
the scarcest and most precious thing in
existence. Their whole world is much
like the Sahara desert, or the flat des
ert plain of our own Arizona.
Yet on a dried-up world of this -sort
they evidently have built up and con
tinue to maintain a civilization far in
advance of anything on the earth. This
is indicated by the complex canal sys
tem that prevails all over their globe.
One of their canals alone is over 3,000
miles in length, long enough to reach
from Boston to San Francisco. In
deed, canals on Mars seem to be
aswiths
numerous as railroads on the earth.
Professor Morse has made a drawing
showing how similar some parts of our
network of railroads are to the Martian
canal lines. The canals of Holland also
present a similarity. These illustra
tions are set forth to show that such
markings must be the works of intelli
gent beings rather than the haphazard
cracks or markings of nature. Profes
sor Morse sums up the argument in fa
vor of the Martian canals being arti
ficial in these words:
"The unnatural straightness of these
interlacing lines on Mars, many of
them following the arcs of great cir
cles their unilorm width thruout, their
always starting from definite areas, their
convergence to common centers, find
no parallel in natural phenomena.''
Where these canals meet one another
are circular areas, indicating great
oases, and probably large cities.
Professor Morse gained much of the
material for this book by a visit to
the southwest. He spent five weeks at
Professor Lowell's observatory at Flag
staff, Ariz. In the dry, steady, clear
air, 7,000 feet above sea level, ho
studied the surface of Mars thru a
telescope. He saw the pale yellow disk
of the planet gradually develop a net
work of dark markings. I was like
a photographic plate, first blank and
then mysteriously taking on shades and
lines.till a world picture was presented.
Looking about him in that desert re
gion, Professor Morse found an explan
ation of the Martian mystery.
Explanation of the Martian Mystery.
"Let one stand on some peak of the
Verde mountains," he said, "northeast
from Phoenix, Ariz., overlooking the
Gila river as it follows its course across
the desert, and after the river is lost
to view he will notice that the foliage
/long its banks marks its course.
4 FARTII RACKS
10 rm
a MOON
100 MILQ
latest word of science about
Mars and its probable inhabi
tants has been uttered by Pro-
PROFESSOFCEDAR3 Who Feelss
Dramatic aftd Stfeial.
A^SCIENTISPS SPECULATIONS ON^
WHAT THE MEN OF MARS ARE LIKE
9. 1RR10ATIO.V CANALS, AlUXOtU
1V4 MOM
COMPARISON OF NATURAL AND ARTIFICIA LINES TO SHOW THAT MARTIAN CANALS MUST BE MADE -BY
INTELLIGENT BEINGS.
Prof*ES. Morse Thinks They Are Great Agriculturists
Solving the Problem of a Dying WorldMay Be Like
Men or Gigantic Ants.
'Su're'"W MaraD Is Inhabited.,MORSE
"If one $ake$ this view in" winter
time, the ui=iform gray of the plains,
Unbroken by^fe-shade of color, blends
with the lightsbitt^.of the distant Plo
mas and Ca&tle.Dome mountains on the
southwest horizon. In the early spring,
when the water is first let into the
irrigating channels, with their innumer
able divergent ditches, a, shade of green
may be seen emerging from the monot
onous yellow-gray of the hot and ster
ile plain, first conspicuous near the
source of the water supply, and then
following along to Phoenix, Temple and
other regions, till in full efflorescence
these cities stand out like great green
carpets spread upon the earth.
From this mountaintop not a trace
of an irrigating ditch, large or small,
would be discerned, except here and
there a glint, of reflected sunlight, but
the effects of the life-giving waters can
be traced in broad bands to the re-?
motest limits of the water channels,
when they would end as abruptly as
they had begun."
Professor Morse makes this explana
tion to illustrate how wide areas of
vegetation may be seen at a great dis
tance, so great, indeed, that canals
themselves would be invisible. The
canals of Mars are believed to be gi
gantic irrigating ditches, very similar
to those now in operation in the'west
and those being constructed by.tbe-govr
eminent.
As life on Mars appears to be sus
tained solely by irrigation, it would
seem that its inhabitants. are great ag
riculturists. We are only beginnings to
learn how to produce vegetation and
sustain life on deserts. But the. Mar
tian have covered their whole globe
irrigation works. Professor
Morse thinks they must understand the
principles-of hydraulics far better than
our best civil engineers.,
Their sole source of water supply
seems to be the snow caps that- form
at the poles during the winter. When
these snowcaps begin to melt, the wa
ter is conducted by the canals clear
down to the equator, and probablv
every drop of it conserved and used
over and over again for irrigating the
land.
Inhabitants of the Planet. .,V'
What manner of beings these are
that have created such a prodigious,
universal waterworks system is a mys
tery. Professor Morse appears to
think they may be like men or gigan
tic ants. For men and ants, he ob
serves, exist at the greatest extremes
of elevation, where the air is heaviest
and rarest, as well as in places where
the climate is hottest and coldest.
On Mars the air is exceedingly/rare,
about half the density of the atmos
phere on the highest mountain tops of
the earth. A man from the earth sud
denly transported there, Professor
Morse thinks, would give a few gasps
and die. But the rarefaction of the
air has taken place by very slow de
grees, and for this reason Professor
Morse conjectures that man might sur
vive the change. He says on this point:
"One has only to make himself fa
miliar with the wide range of. cond^
tions under which life in various forms
exists on the earth to realize that the
introduction of Martian" conditions here
would not be such an overwhelming
calamity. If these conditions could be
introduced by minute increments cover
ing thousands of centuries, it' is not
unreasonable to believe that myriads
of forms would survive the change
and among those that survive would be
precisely th$ kinds that thrive under
the most diverse conditions here, name-
4. CANALS, OKONIMOXN. HOUAKQ
ly, man and the higher hymenoptera,
the ants."
We have the choice, then, of consid
ering the Martian either a man or gi
gantic being,, adapted to breathing the
rarefied air, or a mammoth ant. Pro
fessor Morse seems to lean to the idea
that a creature very like man is theof
Martian intelligent being.
What Martians Might Say of Us.
One of the most interesting parts
of Professor Morse's book is the chap
ter on "What the Martians Might Say
of Us," which begins:
"For every single perplexity of inter
pretation we encounter in our study of
the surface markings of Mars the Mar
tian would encounter a dozen perplexi
ties in interpreting the various features
on the surface of the earth.
"What must be the Martian inter
pretation of the surface features of
L0
1
3
l0
THB MINNEAPOLIS JOURNAL.
When the nature of the business of the Tailors' Misfit Ex-
change was explained to the public last week we prophesied the
bargains w should offer in high-grade, made-toorder Suits and
Overcoats would keep us good and busy.
As you are aware, we had our opening Saturday, and, with-
out exaggeration, the store was literally packedJail day with cus-
tomers and would-be customers. 7
We very much regret that our limited space compelled us to
turn away a lot of men who wanted to get next to the good
things, but have made arrangements to overcome this difficulty
on Monday.
We shall have a much larger force of salesmen tomorrow, and
the bargains we shall offer will be greater than ever.
Among the good
thingsa offeredvests,:made
this world In examining the earth as
we have examined Mars, the Martian
would find large yellow and reddish
areas, extensive greenish areas, and,
besides, large regions of varying shades
of blue, occupying throe-fourths of the
earth's surf/ace. The vellow areas he
would interpret as desert land, the
greenish areas he might consider vege
tation, but "what would he make out
of the larger regions of blue? ThiB
would certainly puzzle him, because, un
familiar with oceahB, he could not be
lieve that suckvast tracts could really
be water: He, 'would easily interpret
the polar caps .and the water at their
edges, but the oceans would be impossi
ble to solve."
"Even i.he"rocognizod oases in the
deserts of America and Africa, the re
sults of artesian wells or springs, he
could not believe them to be vegeta
tion, for he WQ^'ld detect no irrigating
canals running into them. He would
come to the conclusion that no creature
could possibly exist on the earth. Tho
tremendous force of gravitation and
atmospheric pressure would forbid the
existence of organic forms. Life, if it
existed, must have legs of iron to sus
tain its weight, and a crust like a turtle
to be impervious to the force of rain
drops, and this.wouldbe contrary to all
Martian analogy..
"Believing that Mars is rightly bal
anced as to temperature, the. earth, be
ing so mach-nearer the sun, would be
too hot for lire to exist. The Martian
considers our year too short. In his
reflections he says: 'During the pe
riod in which one of us attains the
middle age of 50 years, thoSe on earth
have become decrepit old men of 94.
if indeed.they,,are. not already dead.'
"If there is an intelligence on Mars,"
writes Professor Morse, "it must have
evolved alongf the same general lines as
intelligence has developed on the earth.
Being an older planet, it must have out
grown many of the vagaries and illu
sions which still hamper man in Ms
progress here."
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1907-01-06/ed-1/?sp=6</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		WILL THE NEW YEAR SOLVE THE RIDDLE OF MARS?
ANOTHER and tmal message from
Mars trill soon be in general
hand. If not epoch making as
a milestone of astronomy, it is
the moFt absorbing and extraor
dinary word on an ever fascinating
subject that has bee-n spoken since
Sehiaparelll first discussed the inhabit
ubillty of Mar* aloud. For Professor
Pcrclval Lowell, our greatest M.'.rtlan
student, now declare* positively and
without reservation that our nearest
planetary neighbor is not only alive
with vegetation made possible by
means of vast artificial canals, but is
peopled by an order of beings In many
respects quite superior to ourselves!
In other words, Professor Lowell has
solved, at U-ast to his own satisfaction,
the greatest riddle of the ages the ex
isfnep of life in another world!
Since 1877, when Sehiaparelll aston
ished laymen and astronomers by an
nouncing the discovery of the Martian
«.anals, etar gazers have kept their eyes
focused upon th« face of the red maned
planet. Acres of white, paper have been
covered with notes of whst they saw.
And. finally, Profrssor Lowell and his
aids at the Flagstaff observatory suc
ceeded in actually photographing the
Martian canals. His new volunio, 1s-
Mi.-,i by the Macmillan Company, Ik the
first formal announcement of his recent
«i!(srrvatlonß «.nd conclusions that has
horn published. Not only in hln verdict
liipliiy revolutionary from a scientific
viewpoint, but It is no lc«e daring tlian
convincing when v|pw*d Impartially.
Stupendous ax the conclusion is from
t'to facts presented *b calmly and dis
pOßsionately by Professor Lowell, we
arc nou 1 actually Introduced to b'-ings
oaj Mtr« resembling ourselves In many
«'?»entla.l features.
owlnr. for instance, to the vast d*s
water on most of the surface It Is
reasonable to suppose that the Martian
means of transportation are other than
our own. For the people must com
municate with one another, since. Pro
feasor Lowell is convinced, water from
the poles Is distributed among the pop
ulous oases hundreds and thousands of
miles apart. And the only possible
agency, in view of the physical flatness
of the planet and of the fact that the
force of gravity at any distance from
the eonter of Mars is only one-tenth
the gravity toward the center of the
«>«rth at the same distance, is artificial.
If. In other words, our force of gravity
its represented by 100. It only 27 on
Mars, co-nslflerlny that Mars is only .63
the size of the onrth. There our pound
would weigh only about six ounces, and
it Martian of human «ixe murt be more
than twtre as strong as the. average
man here.
Without indulging In mental aero
nautics on*> reaches the logical conclu
sion that aerial navigation 1* the easl
rrt and most reasonable means of
transportation for our etarry neigh
bors. Indeed, it if not improbable that
they are equipped, granting their ex
istence, with such knowledge of nat
ure! forces, or euoh physical attributes,
as may enable them to propel tliem
erjves from place to place as would our
own mechanical birds. Following are
tho salient feature* in this amazing
message from Mare:
Professor Lowell
HAT Mars is Inhabited by beings
I of one sort or another w? may con
sider as certain. The theory of an
existent Intelligent life there may be
likened to the atomic theory in chem
istry: tho behavior of chemle com
pounds points to the existence of atoms
too 'email for u» to see. and in the same
way the aspect and behavior of the
Martian markings Imply the action of
agents too far away, as yet, to be dis
cerned.
Though In neither case ran we tell
anything of the bodily manifestation,
we can, In both, affirm a good deal about
their workings. Girdling Mars, for ex
ample, and stretching from pole to
pole, the Martian canal system not
only embraces their whole world,* but
is an organized entity. Each canal
Joins another, which in turn connects
with a third, and co on over the entire
surface of the planet This continuity
of construction proves a community
of Interest; and when we consider that,
though not «o large ac the earth, the
world, of Mars Is 4200 miles in diam
eter. and contains something like 212,
000,000 square miles, the unity of the
process acquires considerable signifi
cance. The eupposod vast enterprises
of the earth are. dwarfed by .compari
son, being merely as a civic subway
compared with one of continental pro
portions.
The first thing that is forced on us In
carefully studying conditions on the
planet Is the necessarllyMntelllgent and
peaceful character of the community
which could thus act as a unit through
out its globe. War is a survival
among us from savage times, and af
fects chiefly the boyish and unthinking
element of the cation. The wls«st
realize that there are better ways" for
practicing heroiFiri and other and more
certain means of insuring the survival
of the fittest. War is something a
people outgrow. But, whether they
consciously practice peace or not, na
ture In Ite evolution practices it for
them,
Whether Increasing common, sense cr
Increasing necessity was the spur; that
drove the Martians tp this 'eminently
sagacious state, it Is certain; that they
have reached It and. actually certain
that they, would otherwise perlsliTrin
the absence of the great Martian canal
system-T-provingr-not only the" world
wide sagacity of the builders.; but a
very suggestive sidelight to c the .fact:
that only a universal necessity such as
water coulC well be ./ts underlying
cause,.
That* the habltat'of both plants and \u25a0
animals is conditioned not by the'mini
mum nor' by the mean, temperature of
locality, but by the maximum heat at
tained in the region, is now appreciated
by, science, .the reason being: that the
continuance of the epecles seems. to de r
pend solely upon the' possibility of're
production and'thls in turn upon a
suitable -temperature wrjen the plant
or cnlnmlbesflnft Its career.
TCow. with Mars tin* 'Kt«4,«> nf thing's
accords completely with whet' is thus
demanded for the existence of life. The*
climate! ls one of extremes, where con
siderable heat treads on the heols of
great cold.l as the surface \u25a0 shows con^
cluslvely. In summer and during/ the
day It must; be decidedly hot.'i certainly^
well above; freeslhs, .a thlruier ;alr>
blanket actually Increasing 'the
amount of heat that reaches the sur-.
t aee. \u25a0 Indeed. \u25a0.\u25a0 thata t eon«IUto be such as put a premium upon life
of a .high order. i Th« Martian', year, be
ing twlceas Tons" as our; own.'* the sum
mer there iy Ist-' 4 prbportionatelytei ex{
tended.*. \u25a0- Even';instheisouthern*,hemi
sphere, th« one 5 where s summer \is the
shorteit^ 1 1 blasts t forSlss I days;V while
at^r the "sarne latitude? our) own la but
ninety, days. .This-Uengthenlng;, of -the
period or ffwpTßfluot-Km cannot ibut have
antelevatlng/effectiuponitheVorganism.-;
akin ."tOithe'prolongatloniofJchlldhobd,
j pointed out I by;? John Fiske; as i: playing
so Important k as part? In -the 'evolution
f the j highest* anlmals-V s
Another point,; too, is worth iconsldf^
eratlon;f -In*;an|aglng^Hwqrldy;where;
llving;"condltlons\have Kgrowrt: more;
difficult," 'mentality: in ust characterize
Its beings more and more m order for
them to survive,, and would 'in conse
quence..tend to :\u25a0 be evolved,: To find,
therefore, upon Mars highly intelligent
life •is what its state would lead one
to expect." 1 \u25a0
To some people lt^may seem that the
very strangeness; of Martian life pre
cludes for it an appeal to human'inter-
is surely a near-sighted view.
The \u25a0 the life there proves \u25a0 a coun
terpart \of ,;Qur own, the "more it flrea
fancy/ and. piques inquiry as to "what It
Is.'/; Byj studying.' others we learn about
oiirseh-es,«and, though from theiremoto
we learn less easily, we eventually
learn; the more, -Even on- the side,
then, :.thatr touches most men— the per
sonal—the strangeness ?'of the subject
should «,to's the? far-seeing, prove all the
more 5 powerf \il\ magnet. v *$§SB&93BStf>
One of the i things that roako ilars of
such trariscertdent to- man "is
the i foresight ifaffqrdsuH: of the course
earthly^ evolution Is topursiue. On our
.own ..world we f are only;" ahje to study
our j past and .-present ;_ i n Mars we are.
;able;to" grllmpselour^ nature. ,\u25a0:
:^Havihsr2 established this: premise,- let
us; review; the T planet under.;gondltion3
such \u25a0 as have i favored us in r Arizona.'
What^of the changes in colorlnjgr around
the i polar] cap—the -,vast: areas from .the
blue-greeriftojocher and ithen%" to choc
olate? H^Thls -'change 'no^longrer presup
poses; the physical transference of thou^t
saHds tof tons ;of substance.' s but the
'quiet ".:\u25a0 turning: of j the- leaf -under.- au
tumnal frosts. Even. the fact that they
occupy-, those ;res;ions fits -In, with the
samQfConception^forlltJls 'there that
the^squreesTor the water supply lie.*
On /December CO, Mar.tian date, the
Tfe Sail Frauctacp, Sunday L
\u25a0
area was clearly blue-green «ound
the polar cap. On January 1* a star
tilng transformation stood revealed
Instead of showing blue-sreen. as
usual. It was now a distinct chocolate
brown, the metamorphosis havin* taKen
place shortly after the winter solstice
at that part of the planet Two months
passed and then the chocolate hue van
ished—>one as it had come. The oul
minatlon of the change seems to Have
taken place about sixty days after the
southern winter solstice, or in tne
depths of the Martian winter to that
hemisphere. This is certainly Just the
time when vegetation should be dead
est. The lowest point of the blue-green
tint was reached about January 33 for
the northern and February 8 for the
southern part, which Indicates that the
wave of returning growth came worn
the north, not the sooth— an Important
fact as developed by the aotlon or the
canals. And on February 21 the brown
sreen was completely \u25a0nperseded by
the blue-green, just M would beCxs
case by th© resumption of floßflSßinf
vegetation. ..__
Now we will, consider the reoGXsa
ocher; tracts over the planet.^ I«asfyy,
unchangeable, tnese show essentially
the same day after day throughout
the year. In hue they range from sand
color to brick red, and it is to the lat
ter that the fiery tint' of Mars is They are unquestionably desert areas.
The pale salmon hue, which reproduces
best in drawings, is that which our
own deserts wear. The Sahara ii^}
this. look; still more, it finds its conn-?
terpart in the far aspect of the Painted
Desert of Northern Arizona. To onu
standing on the summits of the Fan
Francisco peaks and gazinsr off from
that isolated height upon thi3
other desolation of aridity the resem
blance to the telescopic, tints of this
Martian globe Is striking.
In other \u25a0words, the gradual en
croachment of desert areas on earth
finds a parallel in Mars, excepting that,
pitiless as our deserts ar?, they arc but
faint forecasts of the state of things
on Mars today.
From the detection of the main
markings on the planet surface we now
pass to a discovery so unprecedented
that the scientific world was at first
loth to accept it— that of the canals.
Not everybody can- see these delicate
lines at first sight, even when pointed
ont to them. When viewed under* the
best conditions, however, the disk of
th"c planet takes on a most singular
appearance. It looks as if it had been
cobwebbed all over a. mesh of nno
lines which., with attention, proves to
compass tho globe from one pole to the
other.
It Is due wholly to the lack of suit
able conditions-that the true form; of
the Martian lines is usually missed.
Given the proper prerequisites of loca
tion or of,eye, and their pencil mark
peculiarly stands forth unmistakably
confessed. The sole method of esti
mating their width is by comparison
of effect with a wire of known size at a
Known distance. For this purpose a
telegraph wire was stretched against
the sky at Flagstaff, and the observers,
going back upon the mesa, observed
and recorded its appearance as their,
stations': grew remote, it proved sur- v
prising at what great distances a alewwf
"der'wire could be made out wheff thua
projected against the sky. The wire in
the experiment was but .0728 of an
inch in diameter and yet could be seen
with certainty at a distance of igoo
feet, at which point Its diameter sub
tended only .69 of a second of are. How
small this is may be appreciated from
its taking more than ninety such lines
laid side by side to'make a width divis
ible iby the eye. Theoretically, then a
line three-fourths of. a mile wide on
Mars-would be visible to us through
our powerful:telescopes.-
But we will take a mile or two safety
as the smallest width for one of the
lines.. The greatest waa got by com
paring what is by far the largest of the
canals, the- NUosyrtls. with the mi
crometer thread. From such determin
ation'lt appeared that this' canal was
from twenty-flye to thirty miles wide,
while,the smallest may be fixed as be
ing from i two to three miles in width
On:the other hand, their length is rela
tively-enormous. Two thousand* miles
.is common, while many exceed 2500
'andUheEumenides.ls 3340 miles from
the(point swhere;it;ieavcs-the TPhoen'x
Laketo the point where It enters the
TMviumCharontls. But what is utiil
more remarkable it swerves neither t,t
the -right nor; left,of; the -great circli
joining.; the two;points.
._ Bach canar proceeds pot only with
absolute directnW but at its terminals
it?meetsrcanals! which have come with
similar directness fsom- oth£ far
places on the planet, j Three; four, a>e f
(Continued on Next Page.)
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1919-11-23/ed-1/?sp=30</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		Do the People on Mars Look UkeThis
Prof. Gernstack Explains Wky Science TLinks tke Peculiar
Conditions of Life on Tkat Planet Would,
Theoretically, -Produce a Higkly Intelligent tut
Grotesque Looking Giant 12 Feet Tall
An Anrtfe American, If He Li red on the Planet
Eros, Wwld Be Able to Lift e Big Mogul
Locomotive Weighing 262,200 Pounds.
By H. Qernsback,
Editor of Electrical Experimenter and
Radio Amateur News.
IN oar ptenaUry system there are prob
ably only three planets now capable
at beating organised life. They are
(fee aarth. Venus and Mars. It haa been
Ann conclusively that the major plan
eta, each a* Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and
Meptuna, are all still in a plastic or molten
rtata. And Ufa aa we know It cannot exist
am a pis?t ahuaa surface has not as yet
pooled to a firm crust, and whose tempera
tare la Car above the boiling point ot
Tfcoae large planets are still in their
early chtMbood, vhile the earth may bo
termed in its "teens." it being a tew steps.
afcaad of the evolution of the major plan
ets. Venus 1s probably abreast of tbo
earth's progress, or perhaps Just a stop bo>
hta?f*us.
We know verj little about Venus because
ao human being has ever seen its surface.
It Is constantly enshrouded In vast masses
<4 -loads making it impossible to see the
lasd or^oceans. Being twenty-Are million
miles nearer to the sun than our earth, It
receives twice as much heat. This gives
rise to a much greater amount of evapo
ration?hence the constant clouding.
We may be sure, however, that organ
ised life exists on Venus. Where there
are water and clonds. which must givp
Van as a similar atmosphere to our owl
organized life must exist without a shade
of a dohbt.
-But now what of Mars, that interesting
planet with which scientists dream of
some day communicating?
Being much smaller. Mars cooled down
hundreds of thousands of years before
the earth did. If the earth is in its'
teens Mars is well along In the eighties.
organized Ufa there must have begun
eons before it did here.
To form say fdequate conception of what
Ufa on Mars is like we must first under
stand the conditions under which It exists?
esadltions radically different from those
aider which wo on this earth live.
Our teiescopee reveal a very great scar
city of atmosphere on Mars. We know this
Dsn the exceedingly rare cloud forma
tfsna. The air is so thin theft that a man
saddeeiy transoort^d from the earth to
Mars would suffocate in a few minutes.
Aad Mars la losing its atmosphere Into
space much quicker than the earth be
cause of Its lower gravitation.
One terrestrial pound walffhs only about a
third of a pound ou Mars. Therefore Mais
does not hold down its air aa strongly as
la the case oa earth, and the air eacar>es
more quickly Into the outer space. While
this process is slow, requiring millions >f
years. It la steady and inexorable.
The accompanying diagrams, reproduced
from a recent issue of the Electrical Ex
perimenter. show the wide differences in
the amount of gravitational pull found be
neath the earth's surface and on Mars and
Eros
If you were to descend a shaft drilled
right throngh the centre of the earth you
would steadily lose weight until you
reached the earth's centre, where you.
would weigh nothing at alL
An average American living oa Mars
would be able to lift and carry about with
ease a safe weighing 554 pounds, and on
Bros be would actually be able to lift a big
mogul locomotive weighing K2.M0 pounds.
But to return to the condltlous life haa
to face on Mars. Scant air, as every avia
tor knows, lowers the temperature. How
raach colder is It then oa Mars with an
atmoephere thinner than an aviator ever
breathed oa earth? Also It most be rw
membered that
Mars Is forty-eight
million miles fur
ther away from
the tun than the
earth, and that on
this account alone
it receives bnt half
the heat we do.
Bearing these
facts in mind,
what sort of life
does Mars sup
port? How ha3
nature accustomed
the Martian to his
changing en Tirol*
ment down through
the tens of thott>
of centuries
of Ma htotory? I?
he a biped or a
quadruped? Is be
a mammal or ft
highly cultured fish
or a sort of think
ing bird? We dont
know. We can only
speculate.
Nature always
does the surprising
and biaarre thing
If yon dont
think to look at a
devil fish or a
giraffe or a chame
leon or a bat. Any
one of them could
hare been equipped
with a human
brain nad nature
thought it expedi
ent. But for some
reason they were
not. On the other
hand, ants and bees
probably "think'"?
Due to the very rare Martian. atmosphere the
Martian's chest moat be enormous to accommodate
his ponderout lungs, necessary to supply his
oxygen. Rare atmosphere conducts sound very
poorly, hence the large ears, necessary'to catch the
very weak sounds. Due to the poor atmosphere it
ia exceedingly cold on Mara, except at (he equator.
Hence Martians are covered with a white polar fur
from head to foot A rare atmospheris conducts
odors but poorly, hence die elephantine nose, which
goes to die odor, as the odor can't come to the
Martian.
Gravity on Mars being much less than on earth
?i lb. on earth weighs 0.3s lbs. on Mars?the pu}l
on his body ia very small. Therefore his height is
from 10 to is feet. To support such a tall body
where gravity ia small, better footing ia necessary.
hence the big feet. The tremendously civilized
Martian always rides or flies from place to place;
his lags are tiros almost .melees, hence devoid of
muscles, consequently thin.
The Martian stopped all physical work millions
of years ago; machines do his work. His arms thaa
are weak and thin. But the hands and eyes?the
Martian's moat important organs, are used and
worked constantly?hence are developed wonder
folly. As his food is all taken in highly concen
trated form and as he does not talk, the Martian's
mouth has shrank very smalt
Talking in a rare atmosphere being almost ia>
possible, die Martian communicates by his telep*?
thic organ, a sort of sensitive skin stretched be
tween antler-like prominences on top of his head.
The same organ sends out the telepathic waves.
perhaps better than we do. Contrawise. If
the? do, they probably think that all of
out acta are due to "Instinct." In their way
they are probably right It depends only
upon the point of view.
But given like conditions evolution will
progress alike In widely separated spheres.
The Indians on the American Continent
developed about the same as the Euro
peans, although they had not intermingled
for thousands of years. It is not even ab
solutely certain that they have not sprung
into being on their own accord.
Following this line of reasoning?and the
writer admits it may be all wrong?there
Is a strong chance that the Martian has de
veloped In s manner similar to that of man
on earth. As a matter of fact, the chances
are greaJy In Its favor. If w? grant this
truth. It should be easy to form a mental
picture of the Martian under his present
unfavorable conditions upon his planet.
To begin with, the Martian race, millions
of years older tuan the terrwitrlal, must
have advanced tremendously. The Mar
tian's head, due to his greatly developed
brain, must be enormous. On account of
the low gravitational force on Mars, where
his body is pulled downward with only one
third of the weight as that on earth, the
Martian must be of great height. He is at
least ten or twelve feet tall. Geotropism
on earth proves this amply.
To support such a tall body where grav
ity is so small, better footing Is necessary,
hence the big (eet are required. The tre
mendously civilized Martian always rides
or flies from [la to place; his legs are
thus Mnjpst unless. Just l'u* a sto'V's, for
instance?d oid of musdies. thin and
sinewy.
Due to the very rare Martian atmos
phere, the Martian's cheat must be enor
Pious to accommodate the ponderous
lungs which are necessary to supply air
and oxygen to his large body. On the
other hand, rare atmosphere conducts
sound very poorly, hence large ears are
required to catch the exceedingly weak
sounds.
As already mentioned, due to the poor
atmospl^ere, it is exceedingly cold on Mars,
except at the equator. Even here it is
freezing. Hence Martians are probably
oovered from head to foot with a white
polar fur. A rare atmosphere conducts
odors but rocly. We thus nay expect the
man on Mars to have an elephantine nose,
which goes to the odor, as the odor can't
com* to the Martian.
The Martian must certainly have
stopped all bodily work millions of years
ago; machines have done his work for
ages. His arms thus are weak and thin.
But the hands and eyes?the Martian's
most Important organs?are used and
worked constantly and therefore are de
veloped to an undreamed of degree.
He probably has six or more fingers on
his hands Even on earth we have already
?ix-flngered human beings.
His eyes probably can be extended from
their sockets at the end of a sort of ten
tacle, the same as a snail's. This gives the
Martian a larger range of vision, without
the trouble of moving his head about As
his food is all taken In highly concentrated
form and as he cannot talk, the Martian's
mouth has shrunk to very small dimen
sions. Talking in a rarificd atmosphere
being almost impossible?for there are no
sound waves in a vacuum?tbe Martian
communicates by means of his telepathic
(O) MIS, International Feature Barrier. Inc.
organ, a sort of sensitive skin stretched
between antler-like prominences on top of
bis huge head. This organ sends out the
telepathic waves/ The antlers protect the
sensitive skin asrainst blows, etc.
This statement need not be ridiculed.
Certain animals, each as our ants, havo a
highly developed telepathic orean. Stu
dents of ants know that the killing of one
ant will be Immediately sensed by others,
although ten or more feet distant. And
within a few seconds they will hare ar
rived at the spot where the death occurred.
The possibility that Mars is inhabited
by strange creatures like that pictured on
this page it itrengthened by the fact that
in other parts of the universe life persists
under the moat extreme conditions imag
inable. Certain species of fish may be
frozen stone hard for days, and will revive
after thawing out.
Thirty years ago it was strenuously de
nied that there could be living creatures
at the bottom of the ocean, where such
tremendoul pressure exists, as well as in
tense cold. It was argued that no living
thing oould withstand suoh enormous pres
sure as 12.000 pounds tf? the square inch,
or exist in the inky darkness of the ocaan
depths. But our deep sea expedltiona
brought up flah from these tremendous
depths as signal proof that nature some
how manages to implant life in the most
impossible placea, under the most unfavor
able conditions.
Life-bearing apores have been frozen in
a vacuum almost down to the absolute
zero They have been subjected to tre
mendous hydraulic pressures. Still life
continued to be evident after the experi
ments. This led Svatte Arrheniua to be
Orett Britain Sights Iwml
Here that
such llfe
bearing
spores pro
pelled by
the i pres
sure exerted by
the sunllg ht,
may float
through tnter
stellar space
a vacuum where
the temperature
is 459 derreea
Fahrenheit?till
they are ot.po?
ited upon a ce
lestial body
where. In t. fer
tile soil, they
are capable of
rising to organ
ized life from
1
If You Lived on
the Planet Mar*
You Would Be
Able to Lift with
Ease a Safe Weigh
ing 564 Pound*.
the lowest and most humble beginning
The history of evolution throughout na
ture shows Invariably that antmai life Is
the direct product of Its environment. h>
order to survive, nature equips each animal
with the necessary organs best edited for
its particular environment. Thus the ca
terpillar is colored green to match the
color of the leaves on which he feasts
If be were red In color the birds would
prey upon him sooner. The camel can go
for weeks without water, there being nonn
or little tn the desert. Nature eqntpped tho
camel with certain organs so that be needs
less water than other animals of hie site.
The elephant, due to his big site, round it
difficult to drink water, which he likes and
needs. It m imprac
tical to lengthen hts
huge bead or neck,
lnsteat, b's nose grew
into a trunk which
reaches down to the
water, so that the ele
phant does not have
to bend down on his
knees.
This all goes to
prore thst nature, in
Its effort to accus
tom life to its envtr
onment, will develop
t^e mart a-ton'shin*
and grotesque forms
of animkl physique
and >t maVes the at
tempt to picture what
tlye people of Mars
are like a re-fectly
le?"it!nnte gub'ect for
scientific speculation.
Such a be*n(r as has
been described here is
the sort of one Natura
would find *t neceesary to dezelop in order
to meet the peculiar conditions existing
on Mars.
Some Interesting comparison* given in
a recent issue of the Eectrical Experi
menter he'p to make clear the wide differ
ence between the conditions prevail ng on
Mars and the e*rth and show how certain
it is that the Martian must be a very dif
ferent sort of creature from mm.
If a man who weighs 150 pounds here
could be suddenly transported to Mars be
v ould find on reaching there that he
tipped the scales at only S3 pounds. The
shrinkage would be .due ent rely to the
lesser gravitational pull on Mjrs.
But in return for this reduction In his
avoirdupois the visitor to Mars would bsve
certain compensations. He would be able
to leap a distance of eleven feet into the
air without the slightest difficulty, as com
pared with a mere four feet here He
would be able to pick up and carry off
weight of 564 pounds as easily as he could
200 pounds here on the earth.
A cannon flred from this earth would
have to attain a velocity of five miles a
second in order to shoot a project.le into
the air so that it would never return. But
a projectile fired from Mnrs at the rate of
only a small fraction more than a mile a
second would never return to the planet
but would become a new satellite.
What scientists term the low velocity
of escape is believed to have an impor
tant bearing upon the possibility of the
planet's possessing and holding stmoe
ph??re. Even if Mars were originally
clothed with ao extensive atmosphere it
is believed, according to the pinetlc theory
of gases, that It is losing It molecule by
molecule.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-02-08/ed-1/?sp=69</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		Scientists, Agreeing Mai
Believe That Plane
tians Are
t May Be
uper-Race,
ignaling to
Us
life on Our Distant Neighbor Is
"Grand, Intense, Formidable/9
Says M. Perrier
By Arnold D. Prince
IF IT should prove to be the case
after all that those mysterious
Marconi "messages" came from
Mars or even Venus, the next
problem of importance will be the
"dud of people who sent them. For,
of course, if the earth is to have new
neighbors with whom to exchange
gossip across the back yard of the
sidereal firmament, it will want to
know something about them. It will
want to know something of their
habits, appearance, how they dress,
act and possibly their views on in?
terplanetary relations. All sorts of
situations may arise wherein a
mutual understanding of personal
traits, characteristics and general
disposition will aid in establishing
and preserving amicable relations.
Signor Marconi, unfortunately,
was not able to throw much light on
the subject. Virtually all that came
within the scope of his observation
was that when prosecuting wireless
experiments certain "signals oc?
curred'' with persistent regularity
which could not be explained on the
theory of casual interference. As
these signals had been received
"simultanecuslv_ at New York and
London with identical intensity," he
admitted the possibility of their be?
ing attempts by the inhabitants of
fother planets to communicate"
with us.
enus or Mars?
Subsequent discussion, in which
ientists in Great Britain, France
i the United States participated,
i ..'vu an almost hopeless confu
i.*:' views on the reasonableness
tir conclusion, but resulted in
agreement on one point at least, i
that if any attempts had
made Lo communicate at all,
y must have originated from
...,rs or Venus, the only worlds
?de our own upon which there
a. possibility of human habita
What kind of people, then, in
i ?bit these two planots? In seek?
ing an answer to this question the
inquirer is thrown back almost ex?
clusively, of course, on the con?
clusions of the scientists who have
made a 6tudy of the subject. No
one, so far as known, is in a posi?
tion to give first hand information.
Nor is there anything specially help?
ful in such suggestions as emanated
recently from one authority, who,
when asked his opinion as to the
population on Venus, replied with
hopeful animation that they were
"chorus girls." Such jocularity is
merely beclouding the issue and add?
ing difficulties to a problem that is
difficult enough as it is.
Among scientists who have won
the righ*- to speak with authority
the foreu?v- was the late Professor
Percival Lowell, director of the
observatory at Flagstaff, Ariz.
Professor Lowell was the brother
of Abbott Lawrence Lowell, presi?
dent of Harvard University. Be?
fore taking charge at Flagstaff he
had been attached to the observa?
tory at Harvard and had conducted
astronomical investigations in many
parts of the world, including Japan,
Tripoli, the Andes and other coun?
tries. He had delivered lectures on
his findings before important scien?
tific societies in Great Britain and
the United States.
Not only was Professor Lowell
convinced that Mars was inhabited,
but he believed the people had a
"?finch higher degree of intelligence
than those on earth. He dwelt
Particularly on their inventive
genius.
*i*eat Inventors
"Quite possibly," wrote Professor
'-owell in his book, "the Martian
[oik are possessed of inventions of
which we have not dreamed, and
"With them electrophones and kineto
scopes are things of a bygone past,
preserved with veneration in mu?
teras as relic? of the clumsy con?
trivances of the simple childhood of
the race.
'Certainly, what we see hints at
the existence of beings who are in
advance of, not behind, us in the
Journey of life.
"Startling as the outcome of
observations' may appear at
-fr"*-"? in truth there ia npthing
?tartling about it whatever. Such
P?ttibility has been quite on the
?ver aince the existence of
-P*9HmM ?M -mocBisMd by the
Chaldean shepherds, or whoever the
still more primitive astronomers
may have been. Its strangeness is
a purely subjective phenomenon,
arising from the instinctive reluc?
tance of mind to admit the possi?
bility of peers. Such would be comic
were it not the inevitable conse?
quence of the constitution of the
universe. To be shy of anything
resembling himself is part and par?
cel of man's own individuality.
"Like the savage, who fears noth?
ing so much as a strange man; like
Crusoe, who grows pale at the sight
of footprints not his own, the civi?
lized thinker turns from the thought
of mind other than he himself
knows."
The peculiar relevancy of this
view to the discussion resulting from
Signor Marconi's announcement will
strike- any one who reads Professor
Lowell's statement. His brother
scientists were indeed "shy," as he
had predicted, of the deductions
reached by him, but they at least
contained the views of the Flagstaff
astronomer as to the kind of people,
who, if we accept the pleasing possi?
bility suggested by Signor Marconi,
are trying to "strike up a speaking
acquaintance" with us. Not only are
they masters in the knowledge of
electricity, but they have already
relegated to the museum of antiqui?
ties many of the discoveries in that
field which we, here on earth, look
upon as last minute achievements in
scientific effort.
Professor Lowell, while comment?
ing strongly on the intellectual at?
tainments of the Martians, made
little or no reference to the actual
appearance of the folk living on that
distant planet True, he did say in
another part of his book that they
probably were not interested in
party politics, and that, judging from
their canals, they were favored by a
"comprehensiveness" of mind much
more embracive than that "which
presided over the various depart?
ments of our own public works" in
the United States, but as politicians
look much like other persons very
little could be gained from that.
First Martian Pictures
It was M. Edmond Perrier, direct?
or of the museum of the Jardin des
Plantes, in Paris, who constructed
the first picture of the Martians, as
he conceived them.
At the time M. Perrier undertook
this task the division among the au?
thorities on Professor Lowell's the?
ory had assumed wide p reportions.
Some were decidedly "cold" to the
notion that Mars?the question as to
Venus was temporarily in eclipse?
was inhabited at all, and they con?
sidered it futile and profitless, there?
fore, to attempt to depict a non-ex?
istent people. Others, as has hap?
pened even recently, considered the
matter in a light vein, thinking to
get some humor out of it, and one
newspaper carried a cartoon, cap
tioned "Hello Central," showing Pro?
fessor Lowell "calling up" Mars.
Still another group seemed to take
it as a personal affront that the as?
tronomer had sought to enlarge their
list of acquaintances by introducing
a race about which they had abso?
lutely no knowledge.
M. Perrier approached the problem
from a highly speculative viewpoint,
but made clear the fact, nevertheless,
that he saw no reason for condemn?
ing the position of Professor Lowell.
"Dreams are not a crime," con?
tended the French scholar, "and in
this case contradiction i? difficult."
The director of the museum of
the Jardin des Plantes led up to his
description of the inhabitants of
Man by ?rtabiiahing the premia?,
that conditions on Mars are not
inimical to human life. Rain, snow,
thunder and hail are known there,
as on earth. There are seaweeds in
the ocean, grass and trees on the
land, fields available for cultivation
and a friendly soil to provide food
for the people.
"The life which animates the
earth also animates other planets,"
said the French savant. "From what
goes on around us we may divine
what is happening elsewhere by ex?
amining the exact conditions under
which each planet finds itself en
rapport with every other. On the
planets which are furthegt away,
it is impossible that human beings
should exist, for no organism could,
for example, be formed in the al?
kaline seas of Jupiter, while Mer?
cury, which is too near the sun,
could not engender life. Only Venus,
the Earth and Mars are habitable."
On Mars, M. Perrier went on, life
is "grand, intense, formidable." The
mean temperature is 40 degrees
Fahrenheit, as against 76 degrees
on earth, the winters are more se?
vere, the summers warmer, the year
longer and the seasons more marked
than ours.
The sea animals are, much like
ours, the fishes have a sense of hear?
ing, there are insects in the animal
kingdom and flowers and butterflies,
but the humans are very, very differ?
ent.
Before going on and giving M. Per?
ri?re picture of the kind of people
the Martians are, and in order to re
assure such sensitive souls as may I
fear to establish speaking relations I
with a people too alien in -appearance
to make acceptable neighbors, it
should be stated that M. Perrier does
not agree with the conception of the
Martians set forth by H. G. Wells in
his book "War of the Worlds." Mr.
Wells, in that work, caused the Mar?
tians to resemble cuttlefish, with
round, gray bodies, with "sort of
faces" and long, groping tentacles.
This conception, M. Perrier as?
serted, did the Martians a great in?
justice and created a prejudice
against them, which is not only un?
scientific and unsound, but entirely
undeserved.
The Martians, the French scholar
held, bear a certain resemblance to
man, although many of their fea?
tures are more prominent. For this,
the difference in the forces of grav?
ity and in environment are chiefly
responsible, he said. Their ears, for
example, are very large.
Continniug? tie? gsmtos of thai
museum of the Jardin des Plantes]
said:
"The low atmospheric pressure
has produced a considerable devel?
opment of the pulmonary apparatus,
and consequently the general char?
acter of the Martians has been in?
fluenced by this development, which
is unknown on earth.
Why Martians Are Tall
"The men on Mars are tall be?
cause the force of gravity is slight.
They are blond, because the daylight
is less intense. They have less pow?
erful limbs. They have some of the
characteristics of our Scandinavian
type, although they probably have
larger skulls.
"Their large blue eyes, theii
strong noses, their large ears, con?
stitute a type of beauty which we
doubtless would not appreciate ex?
cept as suggesting superhuman in?
telligence."
Going further into details, M. Per
rier concluded that the jaw of the
Martian is narrower than ours.be
cause time and evolution have re
moved him further from his anima
forebears than they have us. His
lung capacity is enormous because of
the thin atmosphere, although his
legs are extremely thin, due to the
little effort needed in walking. He
has little or no neck.
Touching on the question of intel?
ligence, the French savant deduced
j that the Martians have solved the
problem of existence, and know no
such thing as industrial strife. Be?
ing older, they are also wiser than
we. They have long since conquered
disease, and know the hour of their
demise, awaiting the event calmly.
They have overcome poverty, are
too sophisticated to engage in war,
and need no law or government to
keep them orderly. Philosophers
and brothers, they live in amity and
understanding, devoting all their
thought to the promotion of large
undertakings in which selfishness,
avarice and earthly trifles have no
part.
They are, in a word, as different
from tha ?*ncifui And unpieasing
picture painted by Wells as are we
from the Simian types referred to
by Darwin.
Returning to tho question of flora
and fauna, M. Perrier concluded
that because of the reduced force
of gravity, animals are much larger
on Mars than here, and hop, run
and fly about much more easily.
Grass is higher, fruit is bigger, and
the flowers possess undreamed of
beauty. The light is something lik?
our dusk, and the general landscape
much more attractive than on
earth.
"The year on Mars is twice as
long as our earthly one," he ex?
plained, "and hence plants and in?
sects have twice the time in whicr
to evolve. Mars is the land of hug?
plants and ideal flowers, of bird;
abnormally powerful in song an<
wondrous in appearance, and o:
four-footed animals with extraor?
dinarily developed fur and skin."
Neither M. Perrier ?or the other
scientists who believe in the habita
bility of other worlds paid so much
attention to Venus. They agreed,
however, with the head of the Jardin
des Plantes that as this planet is
much younger than the earth,
life there is much less advanced.
Because of the greater nearness to
the sun, the climate is something
like that in our tropics, and the air
is always misty. Animals and plants
are much like ours, especially at the.
poles, where the temperature is not
so high, but humans are not much
beyond the development that existed
on earth during the secondary geo?
logical period.
Not From Venus
In other words, there is much less
likelihood that those strange Marv
coni signals came from Venus than
that they came from Mars. j
Having thus disposed o? the kind j
of beings supposed to exist on the
only two eligible planets, two other
questions arise?Why are the Mar?
tians or the Venusians trying to
communicate with us, that is, if they
are? and, What atmospheric condi?
tions will we on earth have to over?
come in order to reply to them?
As to tho first question, a possible
explanation may be found in Jtha
so-called cataclysm on Mars that was
I reported by the British Astronomical
Association in 1909. In that year
the "planet of mystery" was nearer
to earth than at any time since 1892,
and so in a favorable position for
observation.
The phenomenon which was her?
alded as without parallel in the rec?
ords of the past was the appearance
of a gloomy, yellow veil which en?
shrouded immense tracts of the Mar?
tian surface, obliterating important
markings.
On account of the theory, then
recently advanced by Professor
Lowell, that Mars was inhabited, the
changes aroused extraordinary inter?
est. It previously had I*? ;i sug?
gested that the canals on the planet
had been constructed by a dying
race, a race menaced by starvation
on a desert planet, which had sought
by means of these enormous via?
ducts to carry water from t?e melt?
ing ice caps at the poles, and the
appearance of the yellow mist com?
bined with the simultaneous erasure
of some of the canal markings gave
riso to the fear that a gigantic
i
Professor Lowell Held That Mar?
tians Were Far Advanced in
Inventions and Science
catastrophe had occurred, the effects
of which were only too apparent.
Can it be, some of the observers
of conditions now are asking, that
CCIENTISTS agree that
the people of Mars differ
from us in many ways. The
Martians are believed to
have very large noses and
ears and immense lung de?
velopment, because of the
rarefied atmosphere. Their
legs are poorly developed, be?
cause matter on Mars weighs
less than here and sturdy
legs are not needed to bear
their weight. Birds and but?
terflies are very large and j
beautiful
?some such similar catastrophe has j
overtaken the Martians, who, in
their desperation, are attempting to
communicate the fact to us?
In August, 1909, astronomers
working at their telescopes had re?
ported what they surmised to be a
new fracture of the southern polar
cap and the appearance of a dark
streak along the line of the break.
About the same time a brilliant spot,
which may have been a segment of
the shattered terrain, had- separated
itself from the polar cap and had
moved over to one of the dusky
areas of the planet, partly hiding it
from view.
Great Convulsion Possible
All this seemed to strengthen the
theory of a huge convulsion ad?
vanced by the British scientists, al?
though, as seems to be the fate of all
questions concerning this much dis?
cussed and little understood celes?
tial body, eminent authorities at
once took opposing ground on the
subject.
Professor Harold Jacoby, Ruther?
ford Professor of Astronomy at
Columbia University, contended that
"the Martians are not likely to have
their world destroyed any more than
are we," adding that if any such
catastrophe as hinted had actually
occurred the news would have be?
come known through some quicker
channel than the British Astro?
nomical Association. By this, it
should be explained hastily, Profes?
sor Jacoby did not mean that the
scientists across the Atlantic were
slower in observation than others,
but only that the disaster would
have been revealed by telescopes
everywhere long before a formal
report could have been prepared.
Professor F. R. Moulton, of the
University of Chicago, also doubted
the accuracy of the report, and Pro?
fessor Lowell himself, author of the
notion that Mars is inhabited, was
not particularly impressed with it.
Professor Lowell, it will be re?
membered, held to the belief that
the Martians were anything but a
starving, needy people, and he con?
stantly sought to fortify his posi?
tion by offering new proofs of their
prosperity, advancement and skill.
In 1914 he found a new opportunity
for strengthening his pet belief by
announcing that instead of losing
any of their canals the Martians
had built two new ones, which could
be seen plainly through the tele?
scope.
"We have actually seen them
formed under our eyes," Professor
Lowell said at the time, "and the
importance of it car. hardly be over?
estimated. Tho phenomenon tran?
scends any natural law, and is only
explicable sc far as can be seen by
the presence out yonder of animate
will." By animate will he meant, of
course, human beings.
Professor Lowell was admittedly
tho leading spokesman for the
Martians, and anything he said
was worthy of the moat respectful
consideration, but in view of recent
developments many thinkers are
asking if, after all, he was not mis?
taken in at least one particular,
and if the "signals" picked up in
New York and London were not
efforts on their part to notify the
earth folk of their desperate plight.
Xo unusual manifestations to sup?
port this view have been witnessed
recently on the distant planet, but?
it is at least a new guess on the
subject, which is all that its origi?
nators claim for it.
Tesla Believes It
To Nikola Tesla there is nothing
remarkable or impossible in the sug?
gestion that the mysterious signals
are from the Martians. Discussing
the question, he said:
"To most people the mere idea of
flashing a signal over the immense
gulf of 50,000,000 or 100,000,000
miles will naturally appear prepos?
terous, but as I have stated in an
article I wrote for 'The Harvard
Illustrated Magazine' of March,
1907, it is simply a feat of electrical
engineering, apparently hazardous,
but made perfectly feasible through
inventions with which the experts
are familiar.
"That the planets are inhabited is
a foregone conclusion. It would be
stupid to deny the existence of con?
ditions suitable for the development
of organic life on other plftnet3."
The next question is how the
earth is to reply to these signals,
supposing they are signals at all
and what are the atmospheric ob
s-itacles that will have to be over
come.
Mars at times is only 50,000,00
miles away from the earth and a
other times 250,000,000. ft is frc
quently surrounded by vapors, a
is the case, too, with Venus, wfsicl
would be extremely difficult of pen
etration by light radiation, but thi
chief problem to be met would bi
the creation of a wireless apparatui
of sufficient strength to send a mes
sage over the required distance
Dr. Charles P. Steinmetz, chief con
suiting engineer of the Genera
Electric Company, believes such ai
instrument possible, provided tb
world devoted itself to the inventioi
with the same thoroughness it em
ployed in the great war, but esti
mates it would cost at least $1,000,
000,000 to do it
Wireless messages have bee
transmitted over a distance of fror.
3,000 to 4,000 miles when condition
were favorable, although an officii
of the Radio Corporation of Amei
ica, of which the Marconi system
a part, said that signals had bee
sent as far as 10,000 miles und?
unusual circumstances.
"But there is one thing thi
should be remembered," said Davi
Sarnoff, comme??ial manager of
Radio Corporation of America, "thi
there are a great many conditions i
the atmosphere of which we do n<
know, even when sending a m-sssag
say, across the Atlantic or even
shorter distance.
"We know something about wa*
lengths, and we know what happe:
when we send a message and whi
we receive it, but what happens
route is still pretty much of a mj
tery.
Niagara Falls Would Help
"In connection with the actr.
practicalities in sending a wirelt
message over such a distance as th
between the earth and Mars, that
may say, is something about whi
the newspaper men know almost
much as we do. But the ch
problem, it would seem to me, w??
be to find an instrument power
enough, rather than anything el
and this would be no small achie
ment. We would have to ham
Niagara Falls and every other po\
producing agency that I know of
do it."
Electricity travels at a speed o
little more than 186,000 miles
second, and a message going
that rat? would take a little m
than twenty-two minutes to re
Mars when it is at its furthest p<
from the earth, and abaut four n
utes and twenty-one seconds whe:
is nearest. According to the it
calculation it would take two n
utes and eighteen seconds to sen
radiogram to Venus, two mini
and fifty-nine seoonds to the i
two seconds to the moon, thirty
minutes to Jupiter, one hour and
minutes to Saturn, two hours
thirty-two seconds to Uranuf
four hours and two minutes to 1
ton*.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045774/1922-05-28/ed-1/?sp=88</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		Will Mai

Coming to America
to get closet* to Mara?
Guglielmo Marconi, the r, v
father of Radio. V
4MMH HI M|
IF the patience of the folk on Mars
endures a little longer they finally
may succeed in their attempts to
get into communication with us. Marconi
of the wireless is comine here next
month to "listen" in on the messages he
believes are being flung through the
ether from the mysterious planet of
canals and supermen.
What will be the first message from
Mars? Even the imaginations of the
stolid scientists are stirred by this fantastic
attempt of Marconi. For years
scientists have attempted to perfect
some means of interplanetary communication,
ranging from immense rockets
to giant heliographs?and now radio.
Prof. Goddard of Clark College,
Massachusetts, at one time put forward
the suggestion that a giant rocket be
launched to the moon. But for the fact
that the idea appeared to be fathered by
the Smithsonian Institution ii would have
met only ridicule in scientific circles.
But given the Smithsonian
tuci O
was considerable discussion of this plan
until some one ventured to inquire what
was going to shoot the rocket off.
Projection of bright rays of light into
the sky, either by powerful searchlights
of tremendous power or by a gigantic
heliograph system of mirror:, placed in
some such locality as the Sahara Desert,
at one time appealed to science as the
most feasible way to establish communications
with Mars. Early in 1920 Preston
B. Bassett, research engineer of the
Sperry Gyroscope Company of Brooklyn,
asserted that there was no reason such a
method should not be entirely feasible.
Mr. Bassett, one of many who backed
the light system of communication with
he other planets, proposed the concentration
of the rays of 120 high intensity
searchlights of 1,000,000,000 candle-power
each into a single beam of 120,000,000,000
candle-power intensity, which would result
in a signal which, he claimed, could
be easily read on Mars, provided that
planet was Inhabited and that the inhabitants
possessed telescopic instruments of
equal strength to those used on earth.
But all methods suggested have been
proved impracticable even before given a
test. Radio seems to hold out the most
hope. Radio, Marconi reminds, gave science
our first real hope of interplanetary
communication
One night in January, 19<^ Marconi
operators in several different wireless
stations, of which the most important
was the London station, were siaftled by
a series of "mysterious" messages of extraordinary
wave length which tney could
not trace.
The operators wondered, unable to explain
these strange signals. Finally it
was observed that they were receiving a
series of S's. The "toe?toe?toe" was in
reality three dots, which In Morse code
represents the letter S. Each message
consisted of a group of three S's.
Later a query was broadcasted to wireless
stations the world over in an attempt
to find the source of the phantom signals.
It was found the messages were of no
"Could It be Mars?" a startled world
aRked Itself. And In answer a controversy
arose with one side defending the
Mars theory and the other bitterly opposing
It with explanations of "atmos- 1
pherlc discharges," "magnetic storms,"
"thunder storms on the sun'" ?nd other I
natural phenomena.
Marconi at the time said: "I vould be
a bold speculator were I to dt.-lire posl- i
tively that one or more of the planets i
are attempting to send us some kind of
messages, but it is equally futile to deny i
that such a thing Is possible, iu view of t
7
xoni Si

fl in
K8
^BklL ^Hl S
r _ ^PiSa?
t^.

S '.'
#v.;:;
V j
ill

M
V iff!
^~fc=
l&i
our incomplete knowledge of such a pn
found subject.
"What actually has happened in th
throbbing mystery is that signals hai
been received which apparently are di
to electro-magnetic waves of grei-t lengi
which are not merely stray signals."
Interest was revived in intero.anetai
communication?even in the minds
thoso most skeptical of the source of tl
mysterloUR messages. Efforts were mat
to And the most feasible way to cast ele<
trie waves across the limitless inte
stellar spaces.
Dr. Charles P. Steinmetz, the enginee
lng wizard of the Ceneral Electric Cor
pany and recent inventor of "synthetk
lightning, at the time estimated that
wireless plant powerful enough to cast
wave length capable of reaching Mai
would cost $1,000,000,000 to construct ar
require from the whole country the sarr
degree of energy and thoroughness wit
which it entered the war. Lofty tower
1,000 feet high, would have to be coi
structed and all the electric power of tl
country would have to be concentrate
into one great power plant or sendir
station. He also said that metal balloor
filled with helium gas and sent up se>
eral thousand feet could be used instea
of the 1,000 feet high towers, whic
might prove cumbersome to construct.
If such a station should he built, th
resultant wave length would be beyond a
previous conjecture. Wave lengths c
r.,000 miles, while not common, are ofte
cast and signals have been sent as far a
10,000 miles under unusual circun
dances. However, there are a grea
many atmospheric conditions still to b
contended with, even when sending
message a short distance, and even if
>vave length sufficiently powerful enoug]
THE NEW YORK HERAL]
jcceed?
wBr
>j|jp
J^V
V 'y H4
mmm'j
..V"*-
?w..>,,s

I V- <'JvS> J, g?** I
I i
J
.?s"'~ H^aHH|
would reach its des
tination.
But the speculatio
that the thought of such
wireless plant induces is fascinating
Mars when nearest to the earth i
is only 35,000,000 miles away; at othe
rG times 250,000,000. If a message wer
le flashed to Mars?electricity travels 186.00
;h miles a second?It would reach Its desti
nation in a little over twenty-two minute
y if Mars were at its farthest point fron
af earth, and ahout four minuteH and twer
ie ty-two seconds when the planet is nearest
le During the April following the re
c- celpt of the mysterious messages Prof
r- David Todd, former head of thi
astronomical department of Amhersi
r- made several serious attempts at Omaha
n- Neb., where a powerful receiving sta
s" tion was built under the supervision o
a the Oovernment to get into communica
a tion with the planet. A specially con'
'8 structed balloon, piloted by one of th
id greatest balloon experts in the world
Capt. Leo Stevens; all the facilities o
h the War Department's chief ballooi
8. school, experts from the Rockefeller In
stitiite, apparatus from Johns Hopklni
i? University, the very latest Inventions ii
-wireless telegraphy and wireless im
if? pulses and specially built instruments o
various kinds assisted Prof. Todd Ir
f" putting to test the belief that the Mar
fl tians were trying to communicate wltt
h the people of the earth. The ventun
met with virtually no success as regard?
le communciatlon with the Inhabitants o!
II the reddish hued planet.
>f Prof. Todd is now supervising the
n scientific work connected with the builds
ing of a giant telescope to be erected ir
l- a mine shaft In Chile. The shaft Is to
it be sixty feet in diameter, and a niagnie
flcation of 25,000,000 times theoretically
a will he obtained. This will bring Mars
a within about a mile and a half of the
I) earth?that ia optically?so that any life
i
D, SUNDAY, MAY 28, 195
rA fanciful inl
All that 1. nei
of the earth;
equipped to ri
Mar* as it mi
or activity upon Its surface would be
readily observable. Only a small part ol
the planet would thus be observed, it Is
true, and the spot would be moving
rapidjy past the telescope, but enough
could probably be observed to insure
h some positive conclusions. In 1924
s Mars will be within 35,000,000 miles or
e the earth, so that observations made at
i- that time would be under the most
t favorable conditions,
i- Judging from past performances, it appears
that if communication is to be esn
tablished between the two planets Mars
a will have to take the initiative. We have
a long way to go before we develop a wave
s length that will jump the 35,000,000 to
r 250,000.000 miles gap.
e But now comes Signor Marconi to the
0 United States, where radio has developed
1- in leaps and bounds during the last year
s or so. If he is to succeed in catching the
iar nung messages irom mars 11 win De
here.
Probably the most serious difficulty,
aside from the engineering features of
the strange groping through space of two
planets, Is the lack of a common medium
for the exchange of thought. However,
if the Martians can generate a wave
length to reach from their planet to ours.
It Is possible that they will be of such
super-mentality that they will easily overcome
this drawback.
Again the question, "What will be the
first message from Ma$s?" Injects itself.
What will It reveal?
Will It plunge our earth back a thousand
years? Will it make our radio, telephonic
and telegraphic systems seem, by
comparison with those of Mars, to be as
crude as the smoke signals of the Indian
or the tomtom wireless of the African
bushman? Such questions as these are,
indeed, fearful to contemplate.
And how about the Martian himself?
the subject of so much earthly speculation?
Will he be, as II. G. Wells describes
him In his book "War of the Worlds," a
cross between a cuttlefish and a monkey,
with a round grayish body, with a "sort
of a face" and long, groping tentacles?a
gruesome, hideous thing to look upon? Or
will he be, as Edmond Perrler, director of
the Museum of the Jardlne des Plantes
and constructor of the first picture of the
Martian, describes him? The French
scholar held that the Martian bears a certain
resemblance to man, although many
12.
V fi W$ $?>1j
-v.-
v'1
$P$: 1
3
terpretation of the most promising plan foi
:essary is for Marconi or some one else to I
e sending station atop towers rising thousai
an airplane landing supported in space
slay the wireless waves to Mars." The arti
iy be through a magnifying glass.
of the physical features are more promi
nent. He ascribes this to the differences
hi ?iavny ana environment. He Has
Bald:
"The life which animates the earth also
animates the other planets. Prom what
goes on around us we may divine what
is happening elsewhere by examining conditions
under which each planet finds itself
en rapport with every other. On the
planets which are farthest away it is impossible
that human beings should exist,
for no organism could, for example, be
found in the alkaline wastes of Jupiter,
while Mercury, which is too near the Sun,
could not engender life. Only Venus, the
Earth and Mars are inhabitable.
"The low atmospheric pressure has pro- i
duced considerable development of the
pulmonary apparatus, and consequently
the general character of the Martians has
been influenced by this development,
which is unknown on earth.
"The men on Mars are tall because the
lone ui gravuy is sugnt. Tney are blond i
because the daylight is less intense. They
have less powerful limbs. They have
some of the characteristics of our Scandinavian
type, although very probably have 1
larger skulls.
"Their large blue eyes, their strong i
noses, their large ears constitute a type i
t
fo72 Mars
V
,V T
-vt
r communicating with Mara,
find the way to make it poaida
of feet from the aurface
by balloona; the airplanea
iat haa included a glimpae at
of beauty which we doubtless would not
appreciate except as suggesting superhuman
intelligence."
He has further stated that the Martians
live in an intellectual Utopia?a Utopia
that is all the name implies.
Prof. Lowell, director of the observatory
at Flagstaff, Ariz., and one of the
greatest authorities on Mars, places the
Martian people on a much higher intellectual
plane than those on earth.
"Quite possibly," Prof. Lowell has written,
"the Martian folk are possessed of inventions
of which we have not dreamed,
and with them electrophones and kinetoscopes
are things of a bygone past, preserved
with the veneration in the museums
as relics of the clumsy contrivances
of the simple childhood of the race.
"Certainly what we see hints at the existence
of beings who are in advance of
not behind us in the journey of life."
The canal system of Mars indicates that
the planet's inhabitants' are a race of
super-engineers. If they outshine us men-
tally as much as Prof. Lowell claims, we
can expect to find that our "modern" and
much boasted of buildings are as the
tepees of the Sioux, our engineering
works no further advanced than the
dams of the beaver, our inventions as
9lmple as children's toys.
ovel Bird Trap
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1922-08-27/ed-1/?sp=48</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		Dying Planet That Seem to
Show the Martians Must Soon
Find Means to Move to
Some Better World or Be Wiped
IBH Ok? of Existence
How the Telescopes
on Earth Showed the
Firing of the Projec
tile* in Which the
First Invaders from
Mars Were Shot Out Into Space.
By Dr. W. H. Ballou.
THE reports of the leading astrono
mers show that the condition! of
life on the planet Mart at the pres
ent moment are becoming increasingly
hard and that if the planet is inhabited,
as appears probable, its people must now
be seeking some way of escape from their
miseries.
We are therefore confronted by the
possibility that has often been discussed
'>y imaginative scientists and others?a
descent upon the earth by the inhabitants
of Mars. Professor I/Owell, Professor
Pickering, Camille Flammarion and other
scientists, as well as H. G. Wells, have
pointed out that if the means of life were
failing on any planet it was logical to
expect the inhabitants would try to move
to some other planet. The only
question is how they would
move, und Mr. Wells may have
solved that problem.
Mart at the present moment
r>T?-rs unusual opportunities for
observation to the astronomer, as
it is nearer to the earth than it
!i;ts V?een for many ypars. It is
mow only 42,350,000 miles away,
"hereas at this time last year It
Two years from now Mars will
l-e only 34.P00.000 miles away.
If they cannot attack us
this year, the Martians,
having suffered unbear
able miseries, will, per
haps, have perfected their
arrangements in the two
year period and may then
descend upon the earth in
devastating myriads.
Summer on Mars has now passed, and
even ordinary telescopes show that the
ice and snow cap around the poles of
Mars have spread further than ever, add
ing to the hardships of life on an ordi
narily cold and arid planet.
There is ample scientific evidence for
conjecturing that life on Mars has now
become a long agony which no earthly
creature could endure, and which even the
Martians, who have undergone ages of
adaptation, are finding unbearable.
Incessantly swept by terrible dust
storms, unable to find sufficient nourish
ment on an arid, froten globe, gasping
for breath in an exhausted atmosphere,
unable to find even water, the Martians
are living in an inferno that only the pen
of a Dante could describe.
All the evidence indicates that the Mar
tians must soon make a wholesale migra
tion to the earth or some other favorable
planet in the manner that imaginative
writers have suggested. Unless they do
so, they are faced with speedy annihila
tion.
This tragic situation lends great inter
est to the new illustrations Jnade by a
brilliant European artist, Alvim Correa,
for a French edition of H. G. Wells' "War
of the Worlds." It will be remembered
that in this famous work the Martians,
luing threatened with extinction, brcan
shooting themselves to the earth in vast
numbers.
They were all brain and no bones and
shaped much like giant octopuses. To
compensate for the lack of skeleton, their
bodies were enclosed in circular metal
cases and moved on enormous metal stilts
They nourished themselves on Mars by
transfusing blood from the bodies of man
like creatures. When they reached earth
they used men for food purposes and
were rapidly destroying the helpless popu
lation. They rapidly conquered London
and other important regions.
But on Mars the Martians had liv#d
entirely without disease germs and con
sequently possessed no acquired immunity
to them. With the blood of human beings
they drew in the germs of death and
rapidly succumbed without a struggle.
They had command of a burning ray,
which instantly shrivelled up any object
which it touchcd.
When the Martian invaders needed
food they picked up human beings in their
long tentacles, transferred their blood to
themselves and threw their empty car
casses away.
Martian
Beginning to
Eject Deadly
Black Poison
Gas Upon the
Earth.
Are we now
destined in reality
to face a devastat
ing army of hun
ger driven Mar
tians and to pass
through a struggle
more terrible than
the world wart
Perhaps we should
find the real Mar
tians not so easily
destroyed by germs
as Wells imagined.
On the other hand,
we could probably
use poison gas
against them as
deadly as any they
can bring.
What other les
sons ha? 'he world
war ta^gh* us that
would help to renrl
the Martian non
sters? A brilliant
artillerist, who
A Martian Inrtdar Wounded by a Hainan ProjectiU.
served with a Chicago battery in the
world war, said:
"Creatures in metal cases such as Wells
describes would stand no chance against
a sufficient supply of 7o-m?llimetre runs.
These guhs fire 36 shells to the minute
and can be aimed to hit a man Ave miles
away. Kach shell will destroy a stone
building. It can be fitted with an armor
piercing fuse. It is only fair to say thit
no such weapon was in existence when
Wells wrote his hook.
"As recently as the Boer war, which
happened after Wells wrote his book, ar
tillery was practically useless against
trenches or moving obiaets. I? other
words, it was only effective against built
up objects that offr ed a permanent tar
get.
"All that is cha'.jred now. The French
75 millimetre shell finds its way into
tranches and all kinds of recesses. It is
certain to hit tanks, armored ears and
other moving objects.
"Progressive military men art the flrat
to admit that Wells pointed the way' to
tremendously improved methods of war.
We are now working on the production
Of poison gases of enormously increaaed
power and a burning ray similar to that
with which he equipped the Martians."
The official observers of the tawell
Observatory at Flagstaff, Arizona. Drs.
K. C. ami V. M. Sllphor. report that latR
tn June a white feanopy extending far
beyond the polar region*1 had appeared,
covering an area somewhat larger than
Manitoba province in Canada?that is.
250,000 square miles?and In about the
same latitude. They hold that there muit
have been a stupendous snowstorm, one
of tho flnt of the Martian autumn, and
that it must have brought untold hard
ship* to tha Martians.
Tho oboarvra at the Lowell Observa
tory hart boon able to see what was in
visible elaewhara, on account of the ex
tremely dry atmosphere in Arisona. They
(01 ton. to ASMrtcaa Wtakty. la
Martian Conqueror Picking Up
Humaa Being? With Its Octo
pus-Lik* Tentacles to De
vour Their Blood.
are convinced that the Martian atmos
phere is very rarefied, as compared with
that of the earth. The amount of water
vapor there ia so small that for many
years its existence was rather guessed
at than proved. It is so scanty that no
clouds can form thick enough to be visible
to our telescopes in most earthly coun
tries, but in the clear air of Arizona the
Doctors Rlipher have repeatedly observed
a kind of mist differing quite noticeably
from the fierce dust storms that prevail
upon Mars from time to time.
Thus the latest observations tend to
support the scientific hypothesis of Pro
fessor Lowell that there is an atmosphere
of sufficient density to support the life of
beings resembling human creature*.
M. 0rta* Britain Eight* Rm?i ??d.
"X raat, grayiah, round
mam, about the iiae of a
iw, rot* alowly and labor
ioualy out oi the aaatal cyl~
Mir. When it cama into
tba full light it thone like
wet loatbar. Ita two groat
dark eyet ragardad
ma fixed!j."
Picturos from Cor
roa'a ftomarkabla Il
lustrations of Walla'*
-War of tho Worlds."
The Martian
Invaders in
w Their Walking
Machine*
With Artificial
Eye* Using the "Heat
?Rays" That Instantly
Destroyed Everything
They Touched.
Professor Lowell
stated that Mars Is level
and monotonous, with no
mountains and only a few
dried-up beds of shallow
Martian Warrior* Carrying Away a Wounded
Companion.
seas to diversify its topography. More
than one-half of Mars is a dreary desert,
and the rest is green only when the canals
are bringing water from the Polar ice
capa. He first described the great dust
rtorms which sweep over its equatorial
section, blotting out hundreds of square
miles of the planet's surface from our
view.
The physical conditions on Mars are
very different from those we have on
earth. The force of gravity exerted on
Mars is only three-eighths of that on. the
earth, while the atmospheric pressure that
is about fifteen pounds to the square inch
at sea level on earth is less than fo*ur
pounds on Mars. This would make it
possible for enormous weights to be lifted
on Mars with. little muscular effort, as
compared with the tasks on our planet.
Lowell figured that Martians could do
seven times more work than human beings
on earth with the same amount of effort.'
An elephant could leap like a gatelle
there, and a stone thrown into the air
would go very high and sink with a slow,
graceful motion, much like the apparent
action of a slowed-up movie camera.
The supposed signals from Mars, which
Marconi believed he had received on his
yacht Electra this Summer, may well have
something to do with distress on that
planet, although a different explanation
of them has been furnished.
It is commonly assumed that the Mar
tian, if he exists at all, has a much older
civilization than our own. The basis for
this assumption is the nebular hypothesis,
according to which the various planets
were thrown off in succession from the
mass of world-stuff which contracted as
it cooled, with the sun at its centre. On
this thesis thfe outer planets would ob
viously be older and Mars would presum
ably have been far ahead of us in de
veloping a living population.
We might fairly expect our elder plan
etary brother to take the initiative in
sending signals to the earth. Radio,
which is new with us, may bo an old, old
story with the Martians. Quite possibly
they have been patiently waiting thou
sands of years for us to become intellir.
gent enough to answer their signals.
If the Martian exists, and if he has a
radio system that can reach the earth, ho
should have no difficulty in revealing him
self to us. Nothing more itrould be neces
sary than to send a series of signals at
fixed intervals. If. for example, ne were
to make two ?ipnsls, then after an inter
val two more, and after a doable interval,
four signals, we should know that he was
proving that he could add two and two.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1947-08-24/ed-1/seq-100</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		A great many scientists on the earth worry continually about whether
we'll ever be able to make the trip to Mars. Meanwhile Cartoonist
Charles Pearson, who is our expert on interplanetary matters, says he has the
lowdown that scientists on Mars are actually outfitting an expedition to the
Earth. At right you see the Martian writer, H. G. Wellspop, hard at work on a
prediction of what kind of life the expedition will find. Wellspop insists that
there is life on Earth — though some Martian scientists scoff at the idea.
"THBEE'QUARTEBS of the Earth is under water; thus
Earthians are amphibious creatures. They do most of their
farming on ocean beds, which seems strange to us Martians.”
"THE FAJDTT radio reception we get from the Earth
indicates that the creatures are fond of fearful, groan
ing noises that approximate what Martians call music.”
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1956-01-22/ed-1/seq-141</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		First Ship From Mars
Ever wonder what those weird Martians look like?
Cartoonist Ralph Stein suggests maybe they’re exactly like us I
THIS WEEK MaaasliM / January a, 1*66
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn2008060212/1959-09-12/ed-1/seq-10</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
		MARTIANS WILL
BE MARTIANS
“A couple of men from Mars
descended in a flying saucer and
emerged. They looked up at the
top of an apartmeint house and
saw a flock of TV antennas.
‘Hey, you kids,’ one hollered,
‘get down off that roof; ’ ”
—Beecher City Journal
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1956-02-19/ed-1/seq-118</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1955-09-01/ed-1/seq-13</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
